<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hollywood Studios on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/hollywood-studios/</link><description>Recent content in Hollywood Studios on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/hollywood-studios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docking Bay 7 Food and Cargo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/docking-bay-7-food-and-cargo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 13:59:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/docking-bay-7-food-and-cargo/</guid><description>This place in Galaxy Edge is close to the area where the Rise of the Resistance ride is located. We actually waited the full 2+ hours for the ride at around 10 AM, so coming out of it we were hungry. We walked all the way over to the 50s Diner, but our walk in time had passed. Fortunately, this place accepted mobile orders for lunch, and the availability window was pretty fast.</description></item><item><title>Hollywood Brown Derby</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/hollywood-brown-derby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 22:14:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/hollywood-brown-derby/</guid><description>Summary This is located in the central area of the Hollywood Studios theme park. Having dine in similar restaurants in Los Angeles, this definitely does bring back vibes from there. The restaurant decor has a ton of celebrity facial caricatures hanging on walls with an old 1910s to 1950s like decor. They placed us in our own booth, so they took care of social distancing. This restaurant is definitely not as upscale as some of the other restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to, but it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be regarded as the one to go to in this park.</description></item><item><title>Oga's Cantina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/ogas-cantina/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 17:57:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/ogas-cantina/</guid><description>Summary Oga&amp;rsquo;s Cantina is a Star Wars themed bar in the Galaxy Edge section of the Hollywood Studios park. It was a little confusing in figuring out where it actually was because there&amp;rsquo;s no visible sign, so we had to double check the online map on how to get there. The availability for this is insane in that you need to make reservations for this months in advance, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s advised that when you are eligible to make reservations you should do this first.</description></item></channel></rss>