<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Persian on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/persian/</link><description>Recent content in Persian on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:37:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/persian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nasrin's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/persian/nasrins-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:37:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/persian/nasrins-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nasrins-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to checkout a Persian restaurant, that is somewhat close to Central Park and within walkable distance from my work. This is a new restaurant that has been opened for around 3+ months already. In Los Angeles, they have their share of Persian, so it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to see how does NYC fare for this cuisine. The restaurant entrance is a little discreet. The door leads to the second floor which is where the restaurant sits. We were able to walk-in for 2 at 5:30 PM without reservations, though the restaurant filled up somewhat afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ravagh</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 14:13:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the other cuisines in NYC, Persian food is not something that we actively seek out. However, we often are around this area shopping at the now-closed Bed Bath &amp;amp; Beyond and tend to look for restaurants that are very close. This restaurant was something we surprisingly haven&amp;rsquo;t tried, so we checked it out. I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t had Persian food since I moved from LA back in 2016, so I am curious to relive those moments again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>