<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jye on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/friends/jye/</link><description>Recent content in Jye on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:38:49 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/friends/jye/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kogane</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:38:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kogane%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were definitely in for a treat in our visit to Los Angeles. My cousin raved about this place, and we were finally able to join for a lunch meal. They made a reservation for 4 around lunch time on Christmas eve, and it was fairly busy. For $125, you get a curated selection of omakase sushi that had a lot of interesting fishes that you would not typically have in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/clinton-st-baking-co%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends. Right when they open, we were about the 6th small party in line, so we were able to be seated pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-river-cafe%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Makahiki (Dinner)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-dinner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 17:02:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-dinner/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/makahiki-dinner%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makahiki is a restaurant that is located on the first floor of the Disney Aulani resort. The restaurant actually serves &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-breakfast/"&gt;breakfast&lt;/a&gt; and dinner at 2 different times, so this review will be for the dinner portion. Unlike breakfast, there was less of a crowd for dinner, so we were able to walk in with our reservations very quickly. We were seated in the outdoor section under the covered patio around 5:00 PM, which was when the sun started setting. Absolutely stunning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ama Ama</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ama-ama/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 18:32:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ama-ama/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ama-ama%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get our gourmand fix in, we booked &amp;lsquo;Ama&amp;rsquo;Ama as our fine dining Disney Aulani reservation. The price for this four course tasting was $125 per person. The menu offers contemporary island cuisine, which has many local flavors. The restaurant iself was designed to resemble a beachside house, and it&amp;rsquo;s located next to the Waikolohe Valley pool area, just a few steps from the beach. The whole restaurant has a very nice open and chill vibe. We were seated literally right next to the grass that was on the other side of the beach, where we had a straight, unobstructed view into the ocean and the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Makahiki (Breakfast)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 10:02:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-breakfast/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/makahiki-breakfast%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makahiki is a restaurant that is located on the first floor of the Disney Aulani resort. The restaurant actually serves breakfast and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-dinner/"&gt;dinner&lt;/a&gt; at 2 different times, so this review will be broken up into 2 separate reviews. For breakfast, Makahiki serves as a character dining experience. That means cast members dressed up as some of the Disney characters will come mingle with you while you&amp;rsquo;re eating. The people at my table simply loved this, whereas for me I&amp;rsquo;m a little indifferent. What is cool though is that the characters were able to express their emotions and thoughts pretty well without saying a word.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ka Wa'a</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ka-waa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 14:30:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ka-waa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On our first night at Disney Aulani, we went to the &lt;strong&gt;Ka Wa&amp;rsquo;a Luau&lt;/strong&gt; on property. The &lt;strong&gt;Preferred Seating&lt;/strong&gt; was $204 per adult, and the &lt;strong&gt;General Seating&lt;/strong&gt; was $175 per adult. The difference between the seatings is that the preferred seating is assigned and right by the front of the stage. You also can enter 10 minutes earlier, which means you can check out the side festivities earlier too. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry though. On this night, we noticed the general seating area was no where near full, so I imagine you can checkout the side festivities pretty easily. The luau is hosted on the Hālāwai Lawn.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bar Māze</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 17:31:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bar-maze%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our last day in the Waikiki/Honolulu area before we head over to the western part of Oahu for Aulani, we decided to splurge on something a little &lt;em&gt;nicer&lt;/em&gt; to eat. Of all the choices we had, we decided on this Bar Māze place that the internet had raved about. The dining room is quite small, and when we entered, we were seated at the counter. We noticed that many of the cooks were quite young, but they were also very professional with a lot of attention on making sure the food is cooked right. I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Hawaii fine cuisine, but I was getting good vibes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Haleiwa Joe's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/haleiwa-joes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 16:48:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/haleiwa-joes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/haleiwa-joes%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haleiwa Joe&amp;rsquo;s at Haiku Gardens in Kaneohe is known for its lush, beautiful views overlooking its own tropical garden and koi pond with a backdrop of a breathtaking Ko&amp;rsquo;olau mountain range. The restaurant opens for dinner nightly at 4 PM, and when we arrived at 3:30, there was already a line forming because they do not take reservations. Fortunately once they open, there are plenty of tables, but it feels that people are trying to get the best view overlooking the gardens.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ray's Kiawe Broiled Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/rays-kiawe-broiled-chicken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 12:48:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/rays-kiawe-broiled-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rays-kiawe-broiled-chicken%2F0_truck.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
We had just visited the Dole Plantation, and our next planned stop was to checkout this &amp;ldquo;word of mouth&amp;rdquo; BBQ chicken mobile that is similar along the same veins of the shrimp trucks. Be aware that there are 3 locations that this van goes to. This one that we went to is located in a gas station and is open on Tuesdays and Fridays. As a reference point if you are a tourist like me, this is located south of the Dole Plantation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gashoken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/gashoken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 23:19:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/gashoken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gashoken%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gashoken is located in this below ground Asian food mall called &amp;ldquo;Stix Asia&amp;rdquo;. There are several decent sized restaurants with different Asian cuisines, such as Japanese ramen, Taiwanese beef noodle, Japanese hot pot, Korean street foods, etc. We did our lap around, and ultimately landed first on this ramen joint because the host was really marketing it like crazy to everyone walking in front. Upon first glance, the menu was small, but alas we&amp;rsquo;re here for ramen.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Herringbone</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 15:05:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/herringbone%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herringbone is run by the &amp;ldquo;Tao Group Hospitality&amp;rdquo;, which operates more than 80 branded locations in 20 different markets. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what to expect, but per recommendations, we were able to do a walk in around 7 PM on a Monday. The restaurant is located on the top floor of the &amp;ldquo;International Market Place&amp;rdquo; where many restaurants are located, and it has a pretty laid back exterior. As you can vaguely tell from the picture, the right side is an outdoor covered patio letting in the Hawaiian breeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Poke Fix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/poke-fix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 14:16:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/poke-fix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We just landed in Honolulu for our Hawaii trip, and we were pretty hungry. Honolulu is 6 hours behind New York City! Our other friends had arrived a few hours earlier than us and suggested we check out this slight hole in the wall shop for poke near their hotel. My poke impression has always been pretty indifferent, so I was curious what is it about Hawaii poke that people rave about.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carthay Circle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:04:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Carthay Circle is located fairly close to the front of California Adventure. You do need an admission to the park in order to access this restaurant which is basically in the square at the end of the main road from the entrance. This was actually our second time visiting. I remember the first time being fairly underwhelming, so I felt it was wasteful to even spend the time to document it. This time around, my partner wanted to check this out again. As usual, you have to make sure you get reservations way ahead of arrival, or else there&amp;rsquo;s a sketchy wait time. For this, I lowered my expectations greatly, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how it went.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xécora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/xecora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 23:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/xecora/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt Los Angeles has better Mexican food, and I was offered a choice of eating hot pot or going for Mexican food. The hot pot choice would&amp;rsquo;ve been a place that we have a chain of here in NYC, and since we don&amp;rsquo;t know when we&amp;rsquo;ll be back in LA, I thought the answer was pretty easy. We decided on the Mexican joint because this is a local favorite for my cousin. Xécora is a small chain of Los Angeles Mexican restaurants with Huichol cultural influences.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yang's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yangs-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 11:50:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yangs-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yangs-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve finally arrived in Los Angeles to kick it with family before heading up to Mammoth for a wedding.  This restaurant was suggested because it has modern Taiwanese American tastes to it that is seemingly becoming a trend in the Alhambra areas.  Unlike NYC, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt LA had better Asian food in the low/mid price ranges, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how it tastes.  We were able to wait list on Yelp for about 5 minutes around 10:15 AM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix. This one is about the bar. To read the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Napa Rose</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:43:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/napa-rose%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Napa Rose is located in Disney&amp;rsquo;s Grand California Adventure hotel and is known for its award-winning wine list and exemplary service. The food has a lot of inspirations from California&amp;rsquo;s fresh, farm-to-table qualities. This is arguably Disneyland&amp;rsquo;s premier restaurant that many, including some of my local family and friends, visit just for the food. I wanted to try this out to see how it compared to New York City.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bistro Na's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bistro-nas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 23:26:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bistro-nas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without getting too much into the history of the origins of this restaurant, the food here generally was just OK for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bistro-nas%2F1_crispy_shrimp.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;crispy shrimp&lt;/strong&gt; is what everyone wants to get. The shell is super crispy, crunchy, and delightfully edible. It&amp;rsquo;s comparable to the Cantonese style salted pepper shrimp with shell. However, this also has a tangy sauce on the outside of it. For me, it was a little TOO tangy, but some people at my table love it. I think I prefer more savory flavors than sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>N/Naka</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/n-naka/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 21:49:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/n-naka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a borderline 2 month anniversary of my abysmal attempts at eating a LA restaurant every week, I decided to try out this place called N/Naka in Palms. The owner of this kaiseki-style restaurant, Chef Niki Nakayama, is very meticulous with the menu and presentation in her dishes. Reviewers like to compare this place to Urusawa (a very high end Japanese restaurant which is on my list before the end of the year), and they also often say the food is by far the BEST Japanese restaurant in Los Angeles. Like some of my past experiences, Fox W, a well known Foodspotter, provided pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Melisse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/melisse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 20:56:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/melisse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/melisse%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melisse is one of those restaurants in Los Angeles that was on my must-eat list along with Urasawa and Providence. Los Angeles has relatively very few fine dining restaurants that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed, so I have very high expectations for this particular occasion. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed as I also wanted to show my mum what kind of foods I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating outside of the valley. Fox W, a well known Foodspotter, also joined me for this and provided pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Portsmouth</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/portsmouth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 20:18:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/portsmouth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/portsmouth%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this place technically is not in LA, it&amp;rsquo;s within reasonable driving distance. Portsmouth is an oyster bar (with beer eventually) located close to downtown Whittier. The actual site is in a quiet location in suburbia, so it was odd to see the building. But with word of mouth, the internet, and Yelp/Eater-LA, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portsmouth had just been opened for roughly a week. There was a soft opening a few weeks back. I accidentally stumbled onto this site when I was craving for seafood and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to travel to Santa Monica. As some may know, the westside is just a pain to get around. The parking is annoying, and the prices are less than friendly. Eater LA posted an article about this little place, and I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be a nice small road trip for myself. I met up with Fox W, who is a well-known Foodspotter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>