<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Astoria on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/astoria/</link><description>Recent content in Astoria on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/astoria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cafe Olé</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and SVL Souvlaki Bar. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>SVL Souvlaki Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:00:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</guid><description>We tend to go to Food Bazaar on the outskirts of Long Island City often, and the easiest way to get there by train whilst having dinner options would be to exit off Steinway St in Astoria via the M/R train. This area has a mix of random restaurants ranging from national chains like Applebee&amp;rsquo;s to Mediterranean and Latin options. This restaurant is literally right across street from the subway entrance, so it was very easy to access.</description></item><item><title>Kilo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:12:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</guid><description>We have been here before prior to the pandemic when it was a weigh by the pound buffet-style. My partner took me here once because they had been here before several times and said it was their favorite. However that one time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it because the meat was all overcooked, and the rest of the sides were very mediocre. They agreed with me and were surprised by how mediocre it was on that day.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Festival</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</guid><description>This Peruvian restaurant was also on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list of cheap eats to try. The menu was quite similar to the prior Peruvian restaurant, Caravan Chicken we went to a few weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s conveniently located off the Ditmars N/W train on Ditmars itself. We arrived here at 7 PM, and there was no line nor patrons inside. We were not sure what to make of this considering how much we enjoyed the last restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Caravan Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:17:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</guid><description>Lately, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for budget type of restaurants outside of the main areas of Manhattan. This restaurant came at a suggestion from my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend. It&amp;rsquo;s located pretty close to us on Broadway in Astoria and fairly close to the N subway. It really is a no frills restaurant with a lot of local take out and dine-in traffic. We arrived here around 5 PM on a Sunday evening, and finding a seat for 2 people was pretty straight forward.</description></item><item><title>Pig Beach BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/pig-beach-bbq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:31:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/pig-beach-bbq/</guid><description>This area of Astoria is not in the heart where Ditmars and Broadway are, but rather on the cusp. There are a lot of different restaurants around that are not overly busy, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get a seat on most nights. We decided to stop by this new-ish BBQ restaurant on our way to the market. Pig Beach actually has alternative locations in Miami and in Brooklyn, and it has its own unique BBQ zest to its mix.</description></item><item><title>Milkflower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 17:02:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</guid><description>Astoria has a lot of nice gems for affordable prices. My partner wanted to do a nice walk and try out this restaurant per recommendation from their friend. At first glance at the menu, I was thinking this seems kind of ok. I had already done the artisan pizza several times, so my expectations were pretty low. I read many reviews, but I was skeptical because they were all pretty positive.</description></item><item><title>Sake Kawa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:42:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</guid><description>One of the really cool things about the Astoria neighborhood that is different than Manhattan and maybe Brooklyn, is that Japanese food is reasonably priced compared to the other boroughs. I am thinking part of the cause is because of the density of the Asian demographics in the area and having to be competitive with other neighborhood restaurants. This particular restaurant was just a few blocks north of Suzuki Shokudo.</description></item><item><title>Tacuba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:28:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</guid><description>Summary Every few weeks, we make a market run, and we pass by this small area in Astoria that is relatively close to the market. Nearby, they have a few chain restaurants as well as some NYC specific restaurants. This Mexican restaurant seems to always be happening, so we decided to give it a try this time around. They have a ton of tables, so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much of a problem securing an indoor or outdoor table.</description></item><item><title>Suzuki Shokudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 22:05:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</guid><description>Summary Astoria has a lot of Mediterranean restaurants and is seldom appealing for its Asian food. However, in the last few months prior the pandemic, there have been several Korean and Chinese/Taiwanese restaurants that were opening, so it&amp;rsquo;s starting to make a presence. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by this neighborhood Japanese sushi joint several times and were surprised about how low key it is. After looking at the menu, we decided to give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Psari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:38:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</guid><description>Summary You know what&amp;rsquo;s one of the great things about Astoria? It&amp;rsquo;s the excellent Greek seafood restaurants that are within walking distances of each other. We had been to Taverna Kyclades before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we&amp;rsquo;ve dined at their competitors. This was a restaurant that was within walking distance from our Food Bazaar trek on the way back home, so we thought to stop by and give this a try.</description></item><item><title>Queens Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/queens-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:30:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/queens-room/</guid><description>Summary This is a place along Ditmars Blvd in Astoria, relatively close to Taverna Kyclades. There is a lot of interesting outdoor setup on this street. The menu itself appears fairly simple, but this place had been highly recommended to us for the easy going vibe. For this COVID environment, the tables are organized north to south along the side street instead of the main street of Ditmars. It definitely felt a little safer.</description></item><item><title>La Mian Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:26:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</guid><description>Summary Astoria in the last few months has seen an uptick on Asian restaurants that aren&amp;rsquo;t fusion and are more authentic. This one just happens to be on Broadway near my partner&amp;rsquo;s old neighborhood. We&amp;rsquo;ve been around this area before going to eat Shanghainese food. Today, it&amp;rsquo;s for noodles.
This was the braised beef tendon. It was marinated in chili oil, garlic, scallions, sesame oil, and other things that I probably missed.</description></item><item><title>Bund on Broadway</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:29:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</guid><description>Summary Astoria is not really a place known for having typical Shanghainese food. I always think of it as having more latin and mediterranean influences to those respective demographics in the area.
This restaurant though was surprisingly pretty decent for this area.
The drunken chicken I normally don&amp;rsquo;t find in many restsaurants. Here, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as my cousin&amp;rsquo;s or my mother&amp;rsquo;s version as it&amp;rsquo;s WAY too salty, chicken pieces don&amp;rsquo;t appear cut right, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it was marinated well.</description></item><item><title>Kondo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kondo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 17:37:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kondo/</guid><description>Summary This is a very clean sushi spot close to the Broadway subway station off the yellow N and W line. Instead of going all sushi, I decided to mix it up a little with standard Japanese snacks over straight up sushi cut rolls, sorta.
The sea snails were cooked in a dashi broth, and were pretty tasty. I think my piece wasn&amp;rsquo;t cleaned entirely properly because there was some grit, but it tasted ok.</description></item><item><title>Taverna Kyclades</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:08:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</guid><description>We came here around 8:30 PM on a rather cold Saturday evening. Typically there is a long line outside, but today people were crowded and bundled up inside. I put my name down for 2. The wait was approximately 40-50 minutes. We had contemplated leaving when we heard the wait time, but we decided to power through and wait. It was worth it.
On July 1, 2023, we visited this restaurant again, and it has moved from it&amp;rsquo;s previous location.</description></item><item><title>Favela Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 14:55:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</guid><description>Had the churrasco here, and it was pretty good. The chicken and sausage was good. Make sure the steak is ordered medium rare. We ordered medium, and it came out borderline medium well. The caipirinha was really good too. Get the passion fruit and guava. Avoid the kiwi.</description></item><item><title>Tamashii Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 22:15:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</guid><description>Decent ramen noodles. Soup was a little salty. The egg was disappointing.</description></item></channel></rss>