<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lomo Saltado on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/lomo-saltado/</link><description>Recent content in Lomo Saltado on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/lomo-saltado/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kausa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kausa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had won another theater tickets for this Sunday, so we looked for a place nearby. My partner desired Peruvian food again, specifically lomo saltado. The best lomo saltado place we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had was actually &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/"&gt;Mario&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a comparable place, especially in New York City. We walked in on a late Sunday afternoon without issues, and we were seated promptly. Looking over the menu, they had your typical Peruvian options.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner was craving for lomo saltado, and they found this on Yelp. I mentioned to them that we had ordered this via Seamless before, but nonetheless we decided to check out this place in person. They actually have 2 locations near us: either in Astoria or in Sunnyside. The trains towards Astoria are just atrocious on weekends in that there&amp;rsquo;s like a 15 minute delay between trains. Going on the 7 train would have netted us better towards Sunnyside.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chicken Festival</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Peruvian restaurant was also on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list of cheap eats to try. The menu was quite similar to the prior Peruvian restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/"&gt;Caravan Chicken&lt;/a&gt; we went to a few weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s conveniently located off the Ditmars N/W train on Ditmars itself. We arrived here at 7 PM, and there was no line nor patrons inside. We were not sure what to make of this considering how much we enjoyed the last restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Andrea's Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/andreas-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 20:45:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/andreas-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner is fanatical about ceviche, and I am fanatical about lomo saltado. Our level of comparison is Mario&amp;rsquo;s in Los Angeles, and there has yet been a tolerable comparison to that so far. There are not too many Peruvian options in the Williamsburg area. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Chimu Bistro which was decent, and Llama Inn was a little too upscale. On this super sunny and muddy day after getting my hair chopped and despite all the plethora of options for anything but Peruvian, we decided to check out this restaurant based on recommendations. This is the second location of this restaurant, the first being in Maspeth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pio Pio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/pio-pio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:52:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/pio-pio/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pio Pio actually has several stores in the greater New York City. This one is number &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; and is located in Manhattan a few blocks north of Hudson Yards. Remember that the COVID protocols are still applicable. When we walked in, we were seated in an alcove to the left before the stairs that led down to a larger open space dining room. This alcove was pretty nice and it seemed to be catered for parties of 2. The lights were dimmer here for more intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chirp</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chirp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 19:24:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chirp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The lomo saltado was ok. The sauces cost 60 cents extra.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chimu Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chimu-bistro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chimu-bistro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ceviche was good, but the lomo saltado was surprisingly pretty good. Beef slices were tender.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/jora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:36:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/jora/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is located at the southern tip of Long Island City close to Vernon. I would probably classify this as a more upscale Peruvian restaurant with some romantic vibes to it. There is another Peruvian restaurant north of here that is probably more casual and less formal. Truth be told, we actually like this restaurant a lot more than the other one as this one is more consistent albeit a little more pricey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Llama Inn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/llama-inn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:32:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/llama-inn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place was pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s expensive sorta, but the lomo saltado was decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Riko Peruvian Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/riko-peruvian-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:31:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/riko-peruvian-cuisine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So bad. The lomo saltado is really dry. Can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find a decent lomo saltado in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Coppelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/coppelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:29:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/coppelia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gourmet&amp;rdquo; lomo saltado is like paying $20 tacos. This is a ripoff and not worth the $20+. Good, but not great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Senor Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/senor-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:55:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/senor-pollo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is pretty cheap. I remember both the lomo and pollo being a bit on the dry side, but it&amp;rsquo;s so cheap not much of a reason to complain I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>