<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Argentine on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/argentine/</link><description>Recent content in Argentine on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/argentine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baires Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 21:45:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</guid><description>We saw an early afternoon theater show, and right after, we decided to check out Argentine food. Baires Grill was appealing because it is a Miami chain, and this is their only non-Miami location. We are planning on visiting Miami in the near future, so I was curious to see how this food differs than other Argentine restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. We walked in around 4 PM on a Saturday without reservations, and they seated us immediately without issues.</description></item><item><title>R40</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/r40/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 23:17:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/r40/</guid><description>Summary Looking on Yelp, we found that this new Argentine restaurant opened up on Vernon Blvd pretty recently in Long Island City. The menu has a lot of interesting and affordable meat dishes. It&amp;rsquo;s great that this street is opening a lot of cool restaurants of various cuisines. It appears they have a patio in the back that would be pretty awesome once the weather warms up. I can imagine this place being a super popular hot spot in the foreseeable future.</description></item><item><title>Buena Vista</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 11:58:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</guid><description>Summary A friend was in town around the Hudson Yards area, and we wanted to look for something around the area. The menu here looked pretty decent, and it was on my bookmarks for quite a while.
The bread came with some type of tomato olive oil medley. It reminded me of bruschetta toppings but more akin to diced tomatoes out of a jar. The sauce itself was alright.
The octopus appetizer was pretty good.</description></item></channel></rss>