<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mexican on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/mexican/</link><description>Recent content in Mexican on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 13:09:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/mexican/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oyamel</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oyamel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 13:09:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oyamel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oyamel%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oyamel is one of Jose Andres&amp;rsquo; restaurants. Its first location is located in Washington DC, so they decided to open a second here in New York City in Hudson Yards. Jose Andres is one of those chefs and restaurateurs that has a good track record every time they open a restaurant. For his restaurants in NYC, we have been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zaytinya/"&gt;Zaytinya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/"&gt;Nubeluz&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/spanish-diner/"&gt;Spanish Diner&lt;/a&gt;. Coincidentally, Spanish Diner has closed and was replaced with Oyamel in the same location. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:00 PM easily for a Friday evening without issues the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lolita's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 13:44:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lolitas-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were out and about in Central Park taking pictures, and we were looking for a place to check out midday. This no-frills Mexican-like restaurant was near where we walked out of Central Park. We were a bit skeptical of this restaurant since the menu was on the smaller side, but we decided to give it a try. We were seated without reservations pretty easily around 1 PM on a Sunday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tacos Güey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacos-guey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 16:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacos-guey/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tacos-guey%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in the Flatiron area running errands, and unfortunately the nearby S&amp;amp;P sandwich shop was closed for dinner. As we scoured for food, we did ultimately end up at this Tacos Güey place. I vaguely had remembered that this was a relatively new restaurant, so we opted to try it out. We were able to walk in on a Friday evening at 6:30 PM and find a pair of seats in the bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empellón</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:54:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/empellon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we were again running some errands in this Midtown East area close to Central Park. We are running a bit dry on Italian options, so fortunately my partner finally said &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to a Mexican restaurant that I have wanted to go to for a long time. I vaguely recall Empellón having a Michelin Star a while back, but I cannot find any information on it at this time. I even asked ChatGPT, and they thought it had received a star in the Michelin 2019 NYC guide. Regardless, I have wanted to come here to try their infamous dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tán</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:45:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner saw this restaurant on their Instagram feed, and since it&amp;rsquo;s a new Mexican restaurant, we thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to check out. I know absolutely nothing about the Chef Richard Sandoval and Chef Jonatán Gomez Luna Torres, but the menu looked pretty interesting and looks like it can bring an upscale experience and taste of Mexican cuisine. We were able to get 5 PM reservation easily on a Thursday evening, and they still have not gotten their liquor license by our visit tonight. That&amp;rsquo;s fine because they do offer mocktails, which I am a huge fan of in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes. We walked in as a party of 2 around 4:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sobremesa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 11:49:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the word &amp;ldquo;sobremesa&amp;rdquo;, I instantly thought of dessert since that is what it means in Brazilian Portuguese. This restaurant is more of a taco place and is relatively new in the Long Island City neighborhood, and it&amp;rsquo;s located in a barren neighborhood with a bunch of empty warehouses. Surprisingly, there was a beer place opened next door, and there was an outside picnic area where people can enjoy their tacos in a social environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bar Tulix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/bar-tulix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 19:10:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/bar-tulix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following our Disney World trip and since I started going back to the office, we are starting to do our Friday date nights again. This restaurant appeared in the local news as a brand new restaurant, so we thought we&amp;rsquo;d give it a try before the crowds started discovering this and also because we missed NYC food after being in Disney World for a week. The restaurant is a partnership between restauranteur John McDonald of Mercer Street Hospitality with partnership with Chef Justin Bazdarich (&lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/"&gt;Oxomoco&lt;/a&gt;). We recalled we had a great time at Oxomoco for their brunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amor Loco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/amor-loco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 16:01:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/amor-loco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We got some new Mexican restaurant coupons for a margarita/beer. This location is quite convenient near Times Square, just a few steps from the heart of it. We made a reservation for a 4:15 PM on a Saturday late afternoon, and the crowd traffic was fairly light outside and inside. The reservation was probably not needed, but you never know. When we arrived at the restaurant, they did ask for proof of vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tacombi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:23:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Long Island City is starting to turn into another North Williamsburg but with less hipsters. There is a flurry of restaurants and stores that appear to be opening up soon. Along with Vernon Blvd, Jackson Ave is starting to show some liveliness especially around the Dutch Kills bar area. This Tacombi outpost just opened very recently within walking distance from our residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacombi is a NYC chain taqueria with several establishments across the city. We had been to the Flatiron location of Tacombi several times before, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a proper Tacombi post. Because we actually took pictures of the food in the new LIC location, we&amp;rsquo;ll share those here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tacuba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:28:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every few weeks, we make a market run, and we pass by this small area in Astoria that is relatively close to the market. Nearby, they have a few chain restaurants as well as some NYC specific restaurants. This Mexican restaurant seems to always be happening, so we decided to give it a try this time around. They have a ton of tables, so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much of a problem securing an indoor or outdoor table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Quality</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/top-quality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 16:28:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/top-quality/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a local neighborhood spot that has plenty of outdoor seating and social distancing. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting place in that it&amp;rsquo;s kind of in the middle of nowhere. The restaurant reminds me a lot of Williamsburg areas in that they take a warehouse and convert it into a nice comforting eatery. We sat in the outdoor patio area which is very airy and has plenty of comfortable space. We saw they had some electric heaters mounted in the roofs of the patio, so it seemed they are prepared for the colder months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gitano Jungle Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:22:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is located near the James Hotel. They have an outdoors garden that has a decent view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gitano-jungle-room%2F1_chilaquiles.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;chilaquiles&lt;/strong&gt; was basically 2 eggs, crema, salsa verde, and crispy tortillas. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much else here. I thought it was pretty primitive and uninteresting. The salsa was good, but you wish there was some more meats and maybe avocado or something else to give it a little more flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Los Mariscos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-mariscos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 16:34:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-mariscos/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is located in the backside of Chelsea Market along 14th Street. Basically walk towards Tippler, and it&amp;rsquo;d be on your right side. Can&amp;rsquo;t really miss it. It seems to be a semi-throwback to Baja style fish tacos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/los-mariscos%2F1_tacos.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got &lt;strong&gt;shrimp ceviche&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2 fish tacos&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;1 spicy shrimp taco&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted the fish ceviche, but they were out for whatever reason. The &lt;strong&gt;shrimp ceviche&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty good, although I&amp;rsquo;m not too much of a fan of it being put on a big tostada shell. I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be more peruvian style but who would have thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oxomoco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 23:50:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This apparently received a coveted 1 Michelin Star at this time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went here for brunch, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to go back to try the dinner. Just like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/"&gt;Casa Enrique&lt;/a&gt;, I find it pretty good but pricey for what you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oxomoco%2F1_horchata.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horchata was tasty, but does not beat those horchata machines back in LA. Also, it was loaded with ice, so the amount of liquid you get is pretty small for $6.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casa Enrique</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:49:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been to this Michelin 1 star restaurant with a friend for brunch. We were underwhelmed as we&amp;rsquo;ve been to several Mexican restaurants in Southern California. My partner hasn&amp;rsquo;t tried this before, so I thought to give it another shot for dinner. Note that the restaurant does not take reservations. We were able to walk in at 5 PM on a Saturday evening and be seated indoors right away. Take note that there is usually a line outside because people want to wait for outdoor tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waheyo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/waheyo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:48:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/waheyo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting Chipotle/Dos Toros style but feels a little more ghetto? Food was ok but cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lucky Luna</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lucky-luna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:45:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lucky-luna/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Got the pozole here which seems to be uncommon here in NYC. Spicy, but pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too bad it&amp;rsquo;s CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Los Tacos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-tacos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:44:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-tacos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good for NYC. Still cannot compare to LA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Barrio Chino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/barrio-chino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 17:33:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/barrio-chino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/barrio-chino%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very small restaurant in the lower east side, so be prepared to share tables if necessary. In my blog of NYC eats, I totally forgot to blog about this one. This place is supposedly known for their spicy margaritas. My party each ordered habanero margaritas, and they were delectable. They were spicy with a kick, but not overbearing. For many, habaneros are already daunting. But once you soak the habanero into the tequila, it&amp;rsquo;s really not that bad in terms of spicy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>