<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chinese on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/chinese/</link><description>Recent content in Chinese on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/chinese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Octo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 13:32:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</guid><description>Octo is a Korean-Chinese restaurant that brings Chinese dishes developed in Korea. I visited South Korea back in the 2014s, and they definitely had their own spin on Chinese food, which is what attracted me to this restaurant. South Korea has its fair share of Chinese foods that are pretty similar, considered they have shared cultures. Located near Koreatown, we made a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night very easily.</description></item><item><title>Golden Wuish</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/golden-wuish/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:56:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/golden-wuish/</guid><description>The Golden Wuish (Duck House) was featured in several social media outlets, and my partner was craving for duck after returning from Boston. I remembered that this looked pretty gimmicky, so it could be fun whilst having a decent dinner. The restaurant is located in a dark spot next to a hotel, so it was initially somewhat odd to locate. When we walked in for our reservation at 5:30 PM on a Friday night, we were seated towards the front.</description></item><item><title>Jing Li</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:04:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</guid><description>Jing Li has been opened for a few years now in this location. It actually used to be a different Chinese restaurant, so I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s the same owners. The menu looks very typical of non Sichuan Chinese restaurants. Before we walked in, I already decided to go more of a pescatarian selection and hoping the food quality and taste would be similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve had before in the San Gabriel Valley.</description></item><item><title>Han Dynasty</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 14:43:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</guid><description>Han Dynasty is yet another Chinese restaurant that recently joined the Long Island City area. They already have some existing locations spread around other parts of NYC. Their food is the same Sichuan style that many of the local restaurants here aim to serve. I think this style of Chinese is becoming too plentiful here, such that competition is bound to be very difficult. We decided to try this out.</description></item><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Fer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:03:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</guid><description>Fer is a nearby neighborhood restaurant that has similar spicy features comparable to other Chinese restaurants around the area. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of little shops because it usually means you can get your food pretty fast, and it feels casual. We stopped by late Saturday afternoon, and there was hardly anyone there. We were seated right away, and the food came out very fast. The menu has a lot of chili oil in all of their items, but luckily the spice was tolerable when ordered mild.</description></item><item><title>Red Sorghum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:50:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</guid><description>Red Sorghum has recently opened in Long Island City, and is yet another spicy Chinese restaurant. It seems that there are quite a few around Long Island City. This location replaced the closed Penny Bridge. Because this was really close to our place and we were meeting friends, we decided on this restaurant to try different dishes. They proud themselves in baijiu, which is China&amp;rsquo;s liquor to Korean soju. There are several cocktails made with them if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.</description></item><item><title>Din Soup Dumplings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:48:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</guid><description>We had some tickets to attend one of those Fever &amp;ldquo;Candlelight&amp;rdquo; concert events that was located at a church right next to the &amp;ldquo;Court St&amp;rdquo; R-stop in Brooklyn. There was not too many options in terms of food within close vicinity. I looked at the prices for this soup dumpling place, and to my surprise, Din Soup Dumplings seemed not bad. My partner was also in a dumpling mood, so it was convenient to go check this place out.</description></item><item><title>Knock Knock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</guid><description>Knock Knock is a nearby neighborhood cafe that has a mix of Cantonese-style dishes. The decor and the style of the food reminds me a bit of the San Gabriel Valley in Southern California, where there are a lot of small cafe shops opening serving quick eats. My cousin had visited this a few weeks ago for breakfast, and they said they were pleasantly surprised at the coffee. That was a catalyst for us to check this place out to see how its actual food was.</description></item><item><title>Four Four South Village</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</guid><description>Taiwanese food is one of the types of cuisines that is seldomly found in Manhattan and just simply cannot compare to the San Gabriel Valley in the greater Los Angeles area in California. I asked my partner before a show if they wanted to check this out, and to my surprise they said yes! Normally they are not fond of this type of food, especially when noodles are around. This is not too far from Broadway theaters.</description></item><item><title>Nai Brother</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 16:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</guid><description>In our area, there has been a plethora of Chinese restaurants opening. Literally around us, there are at least 3 hot pot places. I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider Nai Brothers a hot pot, but what grabbed my attention was that it specializes in sour fish soups. Nai Brothers is a very small chain with its primary location in Flushing, and this Long Island City location being it&amp;rsquo;s smaller sibling that&amp;rsquo;s closer to Manhattan.</description></item><item><title>Silky Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:41:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</guid><description>Occasionally, I can grab food for myself after work, and I tend to look for noodles. My partner is not a fan at all of noodles, so I took this liberty to look for something that they would not enjoy. Despite the hot and humid weather in NYC, I rarely mind eating hot soups with noodles. Silky Kitchen has a location near where I live in Astoria, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try out its location out in Midtown near Times Square.</description></item><item><title>Zhongzhong Noodles</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/zhongzhong-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 22:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/zhongzhong-noodles/</guid><description>We planned to meet my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend on the wonderful Roosevelt Island. For those that haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Roosevelt Island, there are literally 3 different ways to get there: the F train, the tram (cable car), or transportation via bridge from the Astoria side. With the hopefully slim possibility of living there, my partner wanted to meet their friend and also check out local food delights. Zhongzhong Noodles had been on my list for quite a while, so I figured now is a good time to try it out.</description></item><item><title>Gan Hoo BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:11:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</guid><description>Flushing is the NYC mecca for Chinese food. It&amp;rsquo;s at the end of the 7 train line heading east, and it takes about 40 minutes from Manhattan on weekends. Many restaurants and stalls only accept cash, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite different than being in Manhattan or Long Island City. My partner had a friend that wanted to meet in Flushing to try out Korean BBQ. I thought there would be several near Main Street, but it seems all the decent Korean BBQ places are least a mile east of the Main street subway station.</description></item><item><title>Noodlecraft</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:09:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</guid><description>We walked by this restaurant one evening as we were walking back, and I was reminded that this was something I wanted to try. At a quick glance, the interior seemed pretty spacious, and I always go back and forth on whether we can go here. My partner is never fanatical about noodles, but luckily this restaurant has other things such as dim sum and cold cut appetizers. This restaurant opened last year during the pandemic in October and seemed to have a pretty steady flow of repeat customers.</description></item><item><title>La Mian Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:26:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</guid><description>Summary Astoria in the last few months has seen an uptick on Asian restaurants that aren&amp;rsquo;t fusion and are more authentic. This one just happens to be on Broadway near my partner&amp;rsquo;s old neighborhood. We&amp;rsquo;ve been around this area before going to eat Shanghainese food. Today, it&amp;rsquo;s for noodles.
This was the braised beef tendon. It was marinated in chili oil, garlic, scallions, sesame oil, and other things that I probably missed.</description></item><item><title>Huo Yi Hot Pot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/huo-yi-hot-pot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:10:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/huo-yi-hot-pot/</guid><description>Summary It seems when it comes to hot pot, East Village is a thriving destination. Usually people try to go to 99 Favor Taste because it also has grillable BBQ meats in addition to hot pots. When people don&amp;rsquo;t have reservations and are quoted a 2 hour wait time, the next logical option is to look for another hot pot place which just happens to be this place since it&amp;rsquo;s a few streets down.</description></item><item><title>Tim Ho Wan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:46:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</guid><description>Summary A friend was in town, and I saw that Tim Ho was near their hotel. This place was always on my list to try given that it had received Michelin recognition at its Hong Kong location. Given I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten at numerous dim sum places already, they tout themselves as the dim sum specialists, so I already have high expectations.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the drink on the left, but the right was some type of mango cococnut slush.</description></item><item><title>Red Peony Chinese Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-peony-chinese-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:45:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-peony-chinese-cuisine/</guid><description>Summary We were around Central Park near the southern side, and this was on my list of restaurants to try. This new-ish Chinese (Shanghainese) restaurant is located where Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai used to be in Midtown. It&amp;rsquo;s not too far from the Apple flagship store.
The stir fry snow pea leaf was mighty tasty. You can taste the subtleness of that wine, and the vegetable itself was tender and delicious.
The yang chow fried rice was very uplifting and fresh too.</description></item><item><title>Dim Sum Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 15:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</guid><description>Summary It&amp;rsquo;s the evening and where could be a good place to get fairly traditional Cantonese style Chinese food? Dim Sum Palace!
The pork ribs (páigǔ; 排骨) is pretty decent. It came out piping hot with a lump of black bean that probably was suppose to be mixed in the sauce. It&amp;rsquo;s a little different than other dim sum places, but still pretty good.
The salted pepper prawns were really good.</description></item><item><title>Baodega</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/baodega/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 23:20:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/baodega/</guid><description>Summary This little spot closed to the edge of Flatiron is a decent place if you&amp;rsquo;re into Shanghainese food and are not close to Chinatown.
The passion fruit lemonade was good. You can taste the passion fruit, and it mixed well with the lemonade.
The chilled marinated cucumbers were also good too although I felt the cucumbers were not marinated long enough. They were crunchy with an OK kick to them.</description></item><item><title>Xu's Public House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xus-public-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:57:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xus-public-house/</guid><description>Summary This seems to be a new upscaled Chinese restaurant that we accidentally stumbled into. The decor is very modern and has a slight pretentious feel to it. I learned that the restaurant likes to advertise it hand makes basically all the dough.
They gave this waffle like starter. It is similar to those red bean cakes but without the red bean.
The dumpling sampler had 4 dumplings. This was a special, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to remember (top left clockwise): some soup dumpling, some squid ink dumpling with gold flakes, another soup dumpling variant, and shu mai with (crab?</description></item><item><title>Dun Huang</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dun-huang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 22:51:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dun-huang/</guid><description>This is an updated entry to Dun Huang. The original East Village location is closed, but they opened another location out in Long Island City. They have several locations spread throughout the city. Dun Huang advertises itself as authentic Northwestern Chinese food. The menu at this location pales in comparison to what we got in the East Village location, so I&amp;rsquo;ll still share the differences for reference.
Ambiance The decor at the Long Island City location is pretty no frills.</description></item><item><title>Bund on Broadway</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:29:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</guid><description>Summary Astoria is not really a place known for having typical Shanghainese food. I always think of it as having more latin and mediterranean influences to those respective demographics in the area.
This restaurant though was surprisingly pretty decent for this area.
The drunken chicken I normally don&amp;rsquo;t find in many restsaurants. Here, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as my cousin&amp;rsquo;s or my mother&amp;rsquo;s version as it&amp;rsquo;s WAY too salty, chicken pieces don&amp;rsquo;t appear cut right, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it was marinated well.</description></item><item><title>Xi'an Famous Food</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 22:27:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;ve been to this restaurant multiple times in various neighborhoods, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t documented it till now.
I usually get the spicy tingly beef. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but to be honest I do like Very Fresh Noodles in the Chelsea Market more. However this place was next to me, so the convenience is much appreciated.
The spicy and sour spinach dumplings are also really good too. I love the vinegary taste wih everything.</description></item></channel></rss>