<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tapas on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tapas/</link><description>Recent content in Tapas on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tapas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oppa Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 16:16:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</guid><description>We are likely going to frequent the West Village weekly because we&amp;rsquo;ve nearly tapped out the heart of the Midtown area. This area is densely populated with a high number of restaurants that goes through frequent turnovers and change. Oppa Bistro was an audible call when we learned that Olio e Piu was very packed at around 5:30 PM on a Friday. We were able to walk into Oppa Bistro with no reservations at around 5:45 PM, and there was just a handful of diners.</description></item><item><title>Zaytinya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zaytinya/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 14:29:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zaytinya/</guid><description>Zaytinya is located right next to the N (yellow) line off 28th St inside of the luxurious Ritz-Carlton hotel on the first floor. This is another restaurant of José Andrés, and the menu has a lot of classical Turkish, Greek, and Lebanese influences. What was appealing to us was the menu had hummus, and the prices did not seem too expensive despite being inside a luxury hotel. When you enter the restaurant, it has a very open and modern Greek ambiance to it, similar to many other Greek restaurants in the city.</description></item><item><title>Haizea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 23:21:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</guid><description>Summary We were stoked that New York City has reopened indoor dining albeit @ 25% capacity. Yeah, some people say it&amp;rsquo;s not safe, but they are usually the same people that go visit their friends and family. The restaurants, believe it or not, do an excellent job sanitizing and giving space to diners and each other. Today was Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, and they had a few prixe menu options. We ended up going with Cupid&amp;rsquo;s Arrow Menu which we shared and was just a tasting of many of their items on the menu.</description></item><item><title>Westlight</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 16:29:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</guid><description>Summary Westlight sits on the 22nd floor of the William Vale hotel in North Williamsburg. When you enter the lobby of the hotel, there is a line to the right that directs you to board the elevator. Upon arrival, the host will seat you on 1 of 2 floors. The 1st floor might be for reservations and has a waiter, whereas the 2nd floor might be for walk-ins. The 2nd floor has a fake grassy area with some patio tables/chairs, and you don&amp;rsquo;t get waiter service.</description></item></channel></rss>