<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/</link><description>Recent content on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chef Papa Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</guid><description>The Long Island City area around Queensboro Plaza is definitely missing some Vietnamese restaurants. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Cyclo, and it was very mediocre. Since Knock Knock closed down, this family-owned restaurant from Flushing took over the location. We were able to stop by around 5 PM on a Sunday early evening without reservations. There was no one eating, and we asked to sit at the same bar that was located at Knock Knock.</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.</description></item><item><title>Claud</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</guid><description>For this week, I offered my partner an option of European or Chinese. Of course they said European. Claud comes from 2 veterans of the Momofuku Ko restaurant, chef Joshua Pinsky and wine expert Chase Sinzer. I remember this restaurant a while back, but it slipped off my radar with all these new openings in the last few years. When I checked Resy, I noticed there were openings on Friday, so the stars aligned.</description></item><item><title>Rice Thief</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:02:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</guid><description>Rice Thief is one of the few Korean raw marinated crab restaurants in New York City. The focus of this restaurant is to provide deeply marinated raw crabs with lots of seasoning in it. To the surprise of many, the raw crab meat is actually a little gooey but quite flavorful. My partner saw this restaurant on Instagram and expressed interest in trying this out, despite me wanting to avoid bringing them here.</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Jing Li</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:04:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</guid><description>Jing Li has been opened for a few years now in this location. It actually used to be a different Chinese restaurant, so I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s the same owners. The menu looks very typical of non Sichuan Chinese restaurants. Before we walked in, I already decided to go more of a pescatarian selection and hoping the food quality and taste would be similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve had before in the San Gabriel Valley.</description></item><item><title>Konban</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:44:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</guid><description>Konban was a new katsu restaurant that was on my radar for a while. When it first opened, reservations were hard to come by. Now a few months later, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a reservation a week out. Because Manhattan has so few katsu-specialized options, this was going to be a very special experience. I was able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night for two people.</description></item><item><title>Han Dynasty</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 14:43:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</guid><description>Han Dynasty is yet another Chinese restaurant that recently joined the Long Island City area. They already have some existing locations spread around other parts of NYC. Their food is the same Sichuan style that many of the local restaurants here aim to serve. I think this style of Chinese is becoming too plentiful here, such that competition is bound to be very difficult. We decided to try this out.</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind Au Cheval and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.</description></item><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly Sal e Brasa, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Ole</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and SVL Souvlaki Bar. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant Cafe Olé even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Sal E Brasa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/sal-e-brasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:44:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/sal-e-brasa/</guid><description>Sal e Brasa is a Brazilian churrascaria (steakhouse) chain that has all-you-can-eat meats, salads, and foods. In the outside, you can see these gigantic ribs on spits rotating. I have no idea if those were real, but they were pretty cool. We were able to walk in with seating for a party of 6 very easily in the middle of the afternoon. This was going to be our last meal before we head back to the U.</description></item><item><title>Nau</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nau/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:10:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nau/</guid><description>Nau is a nicer seafood restaurant that also has several locations in Brazil. Many families come here to celebrate weddings or other moments. This restaurant is located in an area near the technology university, and it has a parking lot. We were able to walk in with a party of 4 without reservations easily around 7 PM local time. The moment you step in, the decor felt quite interesting.</description></item><item><title>Lotus</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/lotus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:09:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/lotus/</guid><description>We wanted to try some less authentic Brazilian food, and we received a recommendation from a friend to try out this place. They mentioned they were very impressed by the quality of the fish and felt it would meet our expectations, especially for sushi. This was one of the few Asian-centric restaurants in Natal. We were able to walk in around 7:00 PM here without any reservations. To our surprise, there were plenty of seats.</description></item><item><title>Dobradinha Do Lucas</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dobradinha-do-lucas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:06:59 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dobradinha-do-lucas/</guid><description>Dobradinha do Lucas literally translates to &amp;ldquo;Tripe of Lucas&amp;rdquo;. Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re coming here to eat tripe. My partner had been a frequent visitor to this restaurant during their university days, and they decided to bring me here to give this a shot. The area is a little sketchy, but we came here mid-day when there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of traffic or people. We sat outside along in their half covered patio on plastic tables and seats.</description></item><item><title>Curio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:04:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</guid><description>Curio is a local bar restaurant around where we were staying. My partner wanted to meet their friends locally here since it was new to them, and in the evenings, it appeared to be a very happening place. We were able to walk in for 4 people at around 6 PM without any issues. We had the option of sitting right in the outdoor area in front of the restaurant with security guards around, but we opted to sit inside toward the back.</description></item><item><title>Zeh Cozinha</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:59:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</guid><description>Zeh Cozinha is located in the Midway shopping mall in Natal. It&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a local restaurant with many options of steak or seafood. The price is not too expensive for locals, and this restaurant is competing for business against Camarões and Outback in the same level of the shopping mall. Along with the foods, it also has a decent selection of drinks. We were really excited to try this restaurant out to get a feel for what&amp;rsquo;s a popular local restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Camaroes</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:53:44 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</guid><description>Camarões is a very popular seafood restaurant which got its start in Natal, Brazil. If you meet anyone from this northeast region, they will say they love this restaurant. My partner has been talking about this since day 1 that I met them. Now, I have the opportunity to try this out to see what the rave is all about. Camarões has since expanded to more locations in Natal, as well as a location in São Paulo city, which is a food mecca for Brazilians.</description></item><item><title>Nakka</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nakka/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 22:29:42 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nakka/</guid><description>In our last night in São Paulo, we met up with my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend at Nakka in Jardim. This was a sushi restaurant close to our hotel that offers Japanese fusion type food. At first glance at the menu, the items look exactly similar to anything and everything in the US. My partner was adamant that Brazilian Japanese food was much different than what I had. The friend made a reservation for 7 PM, so we were able to walk in and get seated.</description></item><item><title>A Casa Do Porco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/a-casa-do-porco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 20:36:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/a-casa-do-porco/</guid><description>A Casa do Porco (translates to House of the Pig) is a homage to pork as a whole. If you love pork as much as we do, this is a restaurant that you need to check out in Brazil. One accolade recently was that Janaína Torres was rated as &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s Best Female Chef 2024&amp;rdquo;. The restaurant also has a Michelin green star, which means they are sustainability conscious. They control the entire food chain from farm to consumer.</description></item><item><title>Mani</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/mani/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 23:40:51 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/mani/</guid><description>Mani is a Michelin star Brazilian restaurant headed by chef Helena Rizzo and Willem Vandeven. My partner was adamant at getting reservations for this. Since the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s reservation system was a little odd at the time, my partner was talking to them through WhatsApp. Since Chef Helena Rizzo wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be there during our reservation, she sent a birthday congratulations message thru Whatsapp to me, which I thought was very humble and extremely awesome.</description></item><item><title>DOM</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 23:26:34 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dom/</guid><description>My partner made a reservation for D.O.M. months in advanced because of a Brazilian chef, Alex Atala, featured on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table. What was very attractive to me was how he is known for using indigenous Brazilian ingredients in the dishes. My partner had also contemplated bringing me to a Japanese or Asian type restaurant, but that could not really showcase what Brazil is about.
D.O.M. was rated at 53 on World&amp;rsquo;s 50 Best Restaurants 2022 and 33 on Latin America&amp;rsquo;s 50 Best Restaurants 2022, and it has also received a Michelin 2 Star rating.</description></item><item><title>Casa De Francisca</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/casa-de-francisca/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 01:27:15 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/casa-de-francisca/</guid><description>Casa de Francisca is located in a rather sketchy part of São Paulo. The area reminds me a bit of the early pages of the Art District in Los Angeles or the early gentrification in Bed Stuy in Brooklyn. They have 2 areas, one which is a regular restaurant, and the other being a second floor space. The second floor has a very interesting, artistic space where all the views are generously focused at the stage.</description></item></channel></rss>