<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LES on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/les/</link><description>Recent content in LES on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/les/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Tsukemen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</guid><description>What is tsukemen (つけ麺; pronounced &amp;ldquo;skee-men&amp;rdquo;)? It&amp;rsquo;s basically thick udon served cold with a side of a thick soup/broth for dipping. In Los Angeles, I frequented a place in Sawtelle near the Westside called &amp;ldquo;Tsujita&amp;rdquo; that also specialized in something similar. Okiboru recently opened in Manhattan, and it&amp;rsquo;s famed for being on Michelin&amp;rsquo;s Bib Gourmand list in Atlanta. They do not take reservations, so when we arrived at this location at 5:15 PM on a Friday, the line outside was about 10 parties ranging from 2 to 6 people per group.</description></item><item><title>Contra</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:24:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</guid><description>It was my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and they had asked for my partner to make a reservation to a Michelin Star restaurant that was not overwhelmingly expensive (&amp;lt; $120 per person before wine). My partner started looking for more contemporary cuisines, and stumbled onto this which was a bit below the radar of restaurants. I remembered looking at the menu a while back, and nothing really struck me as a must-have &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to trying to prove myself wrong.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Incident</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/spaghetti-incident/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:12:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/spaghetti-incident/</guid><description>Summary This is another restaurant on my list to go. I am not crazy about Italian, but I was hungry and wanted something pretty straight forward.
The lasagna bolognese came with ground beef, béchamel, and tomato sauce. The pasta consisted of several very thin sheets with a thin layer of ground beef between each. Careful though, the lasagna was piping hot. It was pretty good, but I think I would&amp;rsquo;ve preferred more sauce and more cheese as an ode to the normal lasagnas you&amp;rsquo;d normally get.</description></item><item><title>Wayla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/wayla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 20:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/wayla/</guid><description>Summary This restaurant is a current trendy Thai restaurant that we had to wait a month for our reservations. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a little hard to spot your first time. It&amp;rsquo;s basically where people are standing around aimlessly and down the stairs in a very hard to see nook. If there are no people, look for a sign that has an arrow pointing down to the basement.
We opted for the garden/patio seating, and luckily the weather was a perfect mid 70s temperature with very little to no breeze.</description></item><item><title>Black Tap Craft Burgers</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-tap-craft-burgers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 14:58:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-tap-craft-burgers/</guid><description>Summary Typically on the weekends, both this location and the midtown location have a huge line of people waiting outside. And for what reason?
We came on a Friday night around 5 PM, and there were probably at most 3 or 4 small groups of people in a big space.
The cookie shake was a massive vanila-ish shake that had a bunch of sweets on it. It was good, but it is all sugar.</description></item><item><title>Dirty French</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/dirty-french/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 14:16:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/dirty-french/</guid><description>Summary This place is right around the corner of Katz in the Ludlow Hotel. We sat in the patio area which is much nicer and quieter than indoors where everyone else is sitting.
Starting off, they serve bread that seems to be freshly made for your table. The bread comes with some butter with oil on it, and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
We ordered 2 cocktails: Laboulaye which is the green one and Petite Socco which is the red one.</description></item><item><title>Ivan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</guid><description>Summary I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this ramen spot other than it was on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, and how it really touched a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s hearts. So my review will be almost based solely on the food itself.
The pork musubi bites were surprisingly good. Each bite is packed full of flavor, although I am rather doubtful that it&amp;rsquo;s worth $5 a piece.
The Japanese fried chicken were an interesting spin on karaage.</description></item><item><title>Gentleman Farmer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gentleman-farmer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:03:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gentleman-farmer/</guid><description>Good date spot, small intimate venue.</description></item><item><title>Excuse My French</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/excuse-my-french/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:01:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/excuse-my-french/</guid><description>This was pretty good. Definitely would come back here again when craving for duck rillettes and other charcuteries.</description></item><item><title>Soft Swerve</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/soft-swerve/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:31:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/soft-swerve/</guid><description>Pretty good matcha soft serve ($5).</description></item><item><title>Creperie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/creperie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:24:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/creperie/</guid><description>Really good and BIG.</description></item><item><title>Russ &amp; Daughters Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/russ-and-daughters-cafe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:23:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/russ-and-daughters-cafe/</guid><description>This place was pretty good, but I feel it&amp;rsquo;s overrated. It has a lot of lox stuff. I didn&amp;rsquo;t care much for it, but then again I don&amp;rsquo;t care about lox either.</description></item><item><title>Public Hotel</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/public-hotel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:42:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/public-hotel/</guid><description>People come here to drink because they&amp;rsquo;re retarded. Terrible drinks. College-ish atmosphere. Pretentious for no reason.
Oh, it has the orange escalator hallway that everyone likes to take pictures of. There&amp;rsquo;s also that purple glass window back that people like too.</description></item><item><title>Attaboy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/attaboy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:35:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/attaboy/</guid><description>You tell them what ingredients you like in your drink, and they make something magical for you.</description></item><item><title>Copper and Oak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/copper-and-oak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:23:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/copper-and-oak/</guid><description>This place is cool. All scotches and nice ambiance.</description></item><item><title>WD~50</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 17:59:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</guid><description>I first found out about WD~50 from my friend who wanted to try it out for the longest time. On research, I found out one of the Bravo&amp;rsquo;s Top Chef previous contestant owns this restaurant. His name is Wylie Dufresne. He is well known for pushing a movement towards molecular gastronomy, which is basically a different way to cook things. This 1 Michelin Star restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu is pretty sparse in choices in that you basically choose from 2 different types of tasting menus, the cheaper or the more expensive.</description></item><item><title>Barrio Chino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/barrio-chino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 17:33:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/barrio-chino/</guid><description>This is a very small restaurant in the lower east side, so be prepared to share tables if necessary. In my blog of NYC eats, I totally forgot to blog about this one. This place is supposedly known for their spicy margaritas. My party each ordered habanero margaritas, and they were delectable. They were spicy with a kick, but not overbearing. For many, habaneros are already daunting. But once you soak the habanero into the tequila, it&amp;rsquo;s really not that bad in terms of spicy.</description></item><item><title>Katz's Delicatessen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/katzs-delicatessen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 16:13:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/katzs-delicatessen/</guid><description>Here in Los Angeles, we have a ton of pastrami places. My favorite meat is in fact pastrami. Not only do I enjoy the saltiness flavor in the cured meat, but I also enjoy how tender the meat is. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Johnny&amp;rsquo;s in Culver City, Canter&amp;rsquo;s Deli near West Hollywood, Jerry&amp;rsquo;s Famous Deli, Langer&amp;rsquo;s in Los Angeles, etc. Compared to all those places, I very much prefer Kat&amp;rsquo;z Deli. The meat is chunky, soft, and super flavorful.</description></item><item><title>Bacaro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/bacaro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 15:50:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/bacaro/</guid><description>I have a ton of food porn pics that I haven&amp;rsquo;t put online yet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll get through it. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know already, I went to New York City this past February and tried out some of the local hot spots. This is my first time to the east coast, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t care for any of the touristy places. My buddy and I, per recommendation, went to Bacaro which is Italian inspired cuisine.</description></item><item><title>Doughnut Plant</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/doughnut-plant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 21:25:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/doughnut-plant/</guid><description>Doughnut Plant is one of those institutionalized donut places in New York City. Between Dough and this place, it&amp;rsquo;s really difficult to go wrong, and each person will have their own preference. I remember what was unique about this donut place was mainly their flavors as it was unique and different. The size of the donuts are not as big as Dough, but they are almost as puffy and airy.</description></item></channel></rss>