<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Queens on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/queens/</link><description>Recent content in Queens on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 22:43:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/queens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Le Petit Pecheur</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/le-petit-pecheur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 22:43:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/le-petit-pecheur/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/le-petit-pecheur%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Petit Pêcheur is one of the highly rated Astoria seafood places where you can pick your seafood and they will cook it for you. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/"&gt;Hamido Seafood&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/"&gt;Taverna Kyclades&lt;/a&gt; several times, so we&amp;rsquo;re wondering how this place stacks up. This restaurant opened nearly 1 year ago, and it has been low key on the radar. We were able to walk in without reservations around 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Woodam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/woodam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 20:02:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/woodam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/woodam%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woodam is a Korean gukbap house that serves a very few options in the Flushing area. Gukbap is basically a Korean dish where you can put rice into a very flavorful soup, and it is iconic rustic, comfort food in Korean homes. We were in the area, and I thought this was basic enough to take some elders that were sensitive to sodium and strong spices. We were able to walk in for a party of 4 around lunch time without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Matsunori</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:18:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/matsunori%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matsunori Handroll Bar, not to be confused with Matsunori Sushi Club, originated as a Boston handroll sushi bar. They decided to open an additional location in Long Island City, where there is an influx of Asians moving in. They do not accept reservations, so we decided to try to walk in around 6:30 PM on a Friday evening. Fortunately, we got there just before the lines, and we were able to sit at a table for 2. The counter at the time was completely open.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hamido Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:38:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hamido-seafood%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen this restaurant Hamido Seafood on social media all over the place. Like many Astoria restaurants, they pride themselves in having the freshest seafood, and they are somewhat close to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/"&gt;Taverna Kyclades&lt;/a&gt; down the street. We went to the original Hamido Seafood restaurant at 4 PM on a Saturday late afternoon, and we were lucky to be seated right away before the crowds came. They are located very close to the N/W train off the Ditmars train stop.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef Papa Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chef-papa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Long Island City area around Queensboro Plaza is definitely missing some Vietnamese restaurants. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/"&gt;Cyclo&lt;/a&gt;, and it was very mediocre. Since &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/"&gt;Knock Knock&lt;/a&gt; closed down, this family-owned restaurant from Flushing took over the location. We were able to stop by around 5 PM on a Sunday early evening without reservations. There was no one eating, and we asked to sit at the same bar that was located at Knock Knock.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice Thief</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:02:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rice-thief%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rice Thief is one of the few Korean raw marinated crab restaurants in New York City. The focus of this restaurant is to provide deeply marinated raw crabs with lots of seasoning in it. To the surprise of many, the raw crab meat is actually a little gooey but quite flavorful. My partner saw this restaurant on Instagram and expressed interest in trying this out, despite me wanting to avoid bringing them here. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure how they would do with raw crabs and the mess that is to ensue. Nonetheless, this was the catalyst for us to try out this restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jing Li</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:04:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jing-li%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing Li has been opened for a few years now in this location. It actually used to be a different Chinese restaurant, so I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s the same owners. The menu looks very typical of non Sichuan Chinese restaurants. Before we walked in, I already decided to go more of a pescatarian selection and hoping the food quality and taste would be similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve had before in the San Gabriel Valley. We were able to walk in on a Sunday early evening without reservations. The whole dining area was quite roomy with tall ceilings and typical Chinese decor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Han Dynasty</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 14:43:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/han-dynasty%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Dynasty is yet another Chinese restaurant that recently joined the Long Island City area. They already have some existing locations spread around other parts of NYC. Their food is the same Sichuan style that many of the local restaurants here aim to serve. I think this style of Chinese is becoming too plentiful here, such that competition is bound to be very difficult. We decided to try this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Ole</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cafe-ole%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/"&gt;SVL Souvlaki Bar&lt;/a&gt;. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant Cafe Olé even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/meju%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jiang-nan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:03:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="front" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fer%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fer is a nearby neighborhood restaurant that has similar spicy features comparable to other Chinese restaurants around the area. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of little shops because it usually means you can get your food pretty fast, and it feels casual. We stopped by late Saturday afternoon, and there was hardly anyone there. We were seated right away, and the food came out very fast. The menu has a lot of chili oil in all of their items, but luckily the spice was tolerable when ordered mild.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Red Sorghum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:50:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/red-sorghum%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Sorghum has recently opened in Long Island City, and is yet another spicy Chinese restaurant. It seems that there are quite a few around Long Island City. This location replaced the closed &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/"&gt;Penny Bridge&lt;/a&gt;. Because this was really close to our place and we were meeting friends, we decided on this restaurant to try different dishes. They proud themselves in baijiu, which is China&amp;rsquo;s liquor to Korean soju. There are several cocktails made with them if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Knock Knock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/knock-knock%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knock Knock is a nearby neighborhood cafe that has a mix of Cantonese-style dishes. The decor and the style of the food reminds me a bit of the San Gabriel Valley in Southern California, where there are a lot of small cafe shops opening serving quick eats. My cousin had visited this a few weeks ago for breakfast, and they said they were pleasantly surprised at the coffee. That was a catalyst for us to check this place out to see how its actual food was. We were able to walk in with a group of 3 on a Sunday evening around 6:30 PM without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vert Frais</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 21:36:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/vert-frais%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a lazy Sunday, we decided to stay around our living area to eat. There have been several new restaurants that have opened in the past few months, and this one is the most recent one. The restaurant features ramen and European-Japanese dishes from Nobuyuki Shikanai, the owner of Kanoyama in the East Village. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Sunday at around 6 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nai Brother</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 16:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nai-brother%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our area, there has been a plethora of Chinese restaurants opening. Literally around us, there are at least 3 hot pot places. I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider Nai Brothers a hot pot, but what grabbed my attention was that it specializes in sour fish soups. Nai Brothers is a very small chain with its primary location in Flushing, and this Long Island City location being it&amp;rsquo;s smaller sibling that&amp;rsquo;s closer to Manhattan. This is something that&amp;rsquo;s not only comfort food, but something that I quite enjoy from Chinese cuisine. We were able to walk in on a Saturday without reservations very easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Murray's Cheese Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:54:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/murrays-cheese-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been frequent shoppers at Murray&amp;rsquo;s Cheese for our normal night in eating cheese and charcuterie. This location in Long Island City also has a restaurant part of it. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few glances at the menu, and there were some individual things that caught my eye. Fortunately, it was a lazy Saturday, and it was raining. This would be the ideal night to try this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations at 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SVL Souvlaki Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:00:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/svl-souvlaki-bar%2F0_logo.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to go to Food Bazaar on the outskirts of Long Island City often, and the easiest way to get there by train whilst having dinner options would be to exit off Steinway St in Astoria via the M/R train. This area has a mix of random restaurants ranging from national chains like Applebee&amp;rsquo;s to Mediterranean and Latin options. This restaurant is literally right across street from the subway entrance, so it was very easy to access.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner was craving for lomo saltado, and they found this on Yelp. I mentioned to them that we had ordered this via Seamless before, but nonetheless we decided to check out this place in person. They actually have 2 locations near us: either in Astoria or in Sunnyside. The trains towards Astoria are just atrocious on weekends in that there&amp;rsquo;s like a 15 minute delay between trains. Going on the 7 train would have netted us better towards Sunnyside.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes. We walked in as a party of 2 around 4:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zaab Zaab</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/zaab-zaab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 13:04:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/zaab-zaab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Zaab Zaab is a highly rated New York Times restaurant that serves North Eastern Thai food. We have been trying various Thai flavors that are very different than your typical Thai restaurant. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that these North/Eastern restaurants tend to have much more bolder and spicier flavors that are a bit more adventurous than what you&amp;rsquo;d normally expect. This is located fairly close to the 7 or E train by exiting off Jackson Heights / Roosevelt Ave. We walked in on an early Friday evening around 5:30 PM for 2 people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sobremesa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 11:49:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the word &amp;ldquo;sobremesa&amp;rdquo;, I instantly thought of dessert since that is what it means in Brazilian Portuguese. This restaurant is more of a taco place and is relatively new in the Long Island City neighborhood, and it&amp;rsquo;s located in a barren neighborhood with a bunch of empty warehouses. Surprisingly, there was a beer place opened next door, and there was an outside picnic area where people can enjoy their tacos in a social environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Khun Noo Thai Noodle House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/khun-noo-thai-noodle-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:10:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/khun-noo-thai-noodle-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The summer heat is starting to come to NYC, and it makes everyone including me feel especially groggy. This was also a lazy weekend since we&amp;rsquo;re mentally preparing for the humidity to rapidly increase. Fortunately on this day, it was not too bad. Instead of ordering for delivery, my partner wanted to travel to eat Thai somewhere. We centered on the Woodside area since we had visited before at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thailands-center-point/"&gt;Thailand&amp;rsquo;s Center Point&lt;/a&gt;. This Thai restaurant is not too far away, just 1 stop earlier on the 7 train heading towards Flushing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kyuramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:37:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Kyuramen restaurant chain has been slowly making its way throughout the greater NYC area. They just opened a location out in Long Island City which is not too far from where we live. This restaurant had construction signs early in the pandemic and just never opened until now. We thought we would be able to get seated right away on an early Sunday afternoon, but they checked us into Yelp and we had to wait around for about 15 minutes for a table of 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Piatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:10:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow gotten my partner to enjoy pasta a bit more. Some sacrifices have to be made such as looking for lasagna, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. I have to thank Tony Soprano and how he always made Italian sandwiches and pasta look so delicious. We had to stop by the pharmacy, and nearby was this incognito Italian wood fire pizza place. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Saturday evening around 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sweet Chick</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:07:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having been to Sweet Chick before in North Williamsburg, I vaguely remember this place having pretty good crust. I often get Pies N Thighs confused with this. In Williamsburg, there&amp;rsquo;s always a line outside, so when we walked by here with no line, we decided on a spur of the moment to try this out. When you sit at a table, there is a QR code that you can scan and even place your order.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ramen-spot%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kilo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:12:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We have been here before prior to the pandemic when it was a weigh by the pound buffet-style. My partner took me here once because they had been here before several times and said it was their favorite. However that one time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it because the meat was all overcooked, and the rest of the sides were very mediocre. They agreed with me and were surprised by how mediocre it was on that day. Years later, we decided to try it again to confirm if it was a one time mishap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chicken Festival</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Peruvian restaurant was also on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list of cheap eats to try. The menu was quite similar to the prior Peruvian restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/"&gt;Caravan Chicken&lt;/a&gt; we went to a few weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s conveniently located off the Ditmars N/W train on Ditmars itself. We arrived here at 7 PM, and there was no line nor patrons inside. We were not sure what to make of this considering how much we enjoyed the last restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Caravan Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:17:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/caravan-chicken%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for budget type of restaurants outside of the main areas of Manhattan. This restaurant came at a suggestion from my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend. It&amp;rsquo;s located pretty close to us on Broadway in Astoria and fairly close to the N subway. It really is a no frills restaurant with a lot of local take out and dine-in traffic. We arrived here around 5 PM on a Sunday evening, and finding a seat for 2 people was pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thailand's Center Point</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thailands-center-point/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:42:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thailands-center-point/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were on our way to get some delicious Popeyes chicken on the 7 train, and little and behold, the 7 trains were running express from Queensboro towards Flushing and were running local heading towards Manhattan. Normally the 7 runs local both ways, but they were doing track work, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite clear. The next stop after Queensboro was 61st Woodside, which basically skipped our desired stop by 3 stops. Instead of waiting, we decided to take the opportunity to check out this restaurant that we have ordered a few times on delivery apps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sami's Kabob House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:08:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the city, there are not too many Afghan restaurants to choose from. I&amp;rsquo;ve only had Afghani food once in my life in NorCal, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t ever make me yearn for it. However, I thought the menu looked enticing since we were looking for hummus and kabobs around Long Island City. This restaurant is located on the busy Vernon Blvd, which is becoming a happening street for this area. This location of Sami&amp;rsquo;s Kabob is their second location, whereas their first location is in Astoria.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Penny Bridge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Near where we live, they semi-opened this restaurant on Jackson Blvd at the start of the pandemic only to shut it down pretty quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here several dozen times, and it was never really opened until the last 6 months. Reading online, it seemed they had to change their menu several times for adjustments for some reason, and the menu itself initially seemed basic and not overly attractive. It felt they were trying really hard to attract a brunch crowd, so we have not been enthusiastic about trying. They sent coupons to neighboring apartment buildings to lure in. Finally, we decided today would be the day that we would give this a shot, and we were able to walk in without reservations at 6 PM on a Friday easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ziggle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:51:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is sandwiched at the cusp of Sunnyside between a AYCE Korean BBQ restaurant and a newly opened Sonic fast food joint. The menu looks pretty traditional Korean, and it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to try these types of restaurants in different neighborhoods. This one is rarely as busy as its next door neighbors, but I had some expectations of how this would turn out. When we arrived at 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, we were the only patrons in the restaurant. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gan Hoo BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:11:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gan-hoo-bbq%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flushing is the NYC mecca for Chinese food. It&amp;rsquo;s at the end of the 7 train line heading east, and it takes about 40 minutes from Manhattan on weekends. Many restaurants and stalls only accept cash, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite different than being in Manhattan or Long Island City. My partner had a friend that wanted to meet in Flushing to try out Korean BBQ. I thought there would be several near Main Street, but it seems all the decent Korean BBQ places are least a mile east of the Main street subway station. Instead, I selected this &amp;ldquo;Gan Hoo&amp;rdquo; because I thought it was Korean BBQ, but I learned much later it&amp;rsquo;s really a Chinese interpretation of Korean BBQ. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pig Beach BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/pig-beach-bbq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:31:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/pig-beach-bbq/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This area of Astoria is not in the heart where Ditmars and Broadway are, but rather on the cusp. There are a lot of different restaurants around that are not overly busy, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get a seat on most nights. We decided to stop by this new-ish BBQ restaurant on our way to the market. Pig Beach actually has alternative locations in Miami and in Brooklyn, and it has its own unique BBQ zest to its mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wonder Pig Kbbq</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 14:43:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All you can eat (AYCE) Korean BBQ places are pretty sparse the closer you get to Manhattan. If you did find one, the quality is kind of questionable compared to the a&amp;rsquo;la carte places. We discovered this restaurant a few months back when we went to the Popeyes next door. It hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened yet, but there seems to be a few restaurants next to it that are opening in the very near future. This restaurant used to be called &amp;ldquo;HoneyPig&amp;rdquo;, but apparently it changed its name right before opening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Noodlecraft</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:09:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We walked by this restaurant one evening as we were walking back, and I was reminded that this was something I wanted to try. At a quick glance, the interior seemed pretty spacious, and I always go back and forth on whether we can go here. My partner is never fanatical about noodles, but luckily this restaurant has other things such as dim sum and cold cut appetizers. This restaurant opened last year during the pandemic in October and seemed to have a pretty steady flow of repeat customers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blend on the Water</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/blend-on-the-water/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 21:03:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/blend-on-the-water/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is located right next to the water near restaurants like Maiella and American Brass. Whenever we try walk-in, they always tells us it&amp;rsquo;s an hour wait even when there&amp;rsquo;s no one outside. Since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything else close by that we wanted to try, we were able to book a reservation for an early Saturday dinner again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance"&gt;Ambiance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason this restaurant is very popular with a large latin clientele. People will have massive birthday parties or get togethers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Partners Coffee</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/partners-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 10:26:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/partners-coffee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Partners Coffee was formerly known as Toby&amp;rsquo;s Estate coffee. When I first moved to NYC many years ago to Williamsburg, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt they had my preferred coffee beans and coffee. The general atmosphere probably falls a little under &amp;ldquo;hipster&amp;rdquo; coffee, but it&amp;rsquo;s quite delicious. I have always tried to visit other coffee shops in NYC for their coffee and beans, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always fallen back to this. In some locations, they have brewing classes and a roaster, but because this one in Long Island City is much smaller, it&amp;rsquo;s just a straight up coffee cafe.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Manducatis Rustica</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 16:43:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve visited most of the Long Island City restaurants around the Vernon Blvd area. We had stopped by Blend on the Water hopefully for a walk-in, but there was already a wait. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by Manducatis Rustica several times, and we figured it was worth a shot to see if they can take us. When we arrived, there was hardly anyone there. They told us that they had garden seating, so we opted for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice X Beans</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-x-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:02:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-x-beans/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On a hot day, my partner wanted to eat at a Brazilian restaurant pretty far from where we live. I ended up walking 2 miles for this Brazilian restaurant. At first, I thought it was supposed to be an expansion of a Rice and Beans place in the city, but I learned this was entirely different. The first thought that came in my head when I sat down was that this restaurant definitely is more of a typical locals stop with no frills fair priced Brazilian dishes. I was not expecting any amazing Brazilian food, but who knows maybe they would surprise me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Milkflower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 17:02:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Astoria has a lot of nice gems for affordable prices. My partner wanted to do a nice walk and try out this restaurant per recommendation from their friend. At first glance at the menu, I was thinking this seems kind of ok. I had already done the artisan pizza several times, so my expectations were pretty low. I read many reviews, but I was skeptical because they were all pretty positive. But this is Astoria, and it&amp;rsquo;s known for having good food, so I was very pleasantly surprised how my experience turned out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sake Kawa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:42:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool things about the Astoria neighborhood that is different than Manhattan and maybe Brooklyn, is that Japanese food is reasonably priced compared to the other boroughs. I am thinking part of the cause is because of the density of the Asian demographics in the area and having to be competitive with other neighborhood restaurants. This particular restaurant was just a few blocks north of Suzuki Shokudo.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Levante</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new Trader Joes opened up in Long Island City, and I was hoping to make turkey tacos with guacamole. Unfortunately, the avocados were not ripe enough yet, so I mentioned to my partner we can eat out. The first thought that came to their mind was this place because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few nearby restaurants we have not tried yet but have seen a lot of people standing outside. Ever since I moved here, I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept glancing at the menu, but nothing really screamed at me that I have to try it. But now that I have tried it, how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Woodbines</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:58:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Woodbines is another craft beer and bar restaurant on Vernon Blvd in Long Island City that has fish and chips on the menu which my partner as craving for. At 5:00 PM, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people, and it was easy to get a seat inside the restaurant. Keep in mind, they do follow COVID protocols, so they asked us to check our temperature against the wall. They definitely have an outdoor setup, and that seemed to be more popular with the guests as the night went on. There are some other affliate locations in the city such as Kent&amp;rsquo;s Ale House in North Williamsburg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tacombi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:23:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Long Island City is starting to turn into another North Williamsburg but with less hipsters. There is a flurry of restaurants and stores that appear to be opening up soon. Along with Vernon Blvd, Jackson Ave is starting to show some liveliness especially around the Dutch Kills bar area. This Tacombi outpost just opened very recently within walking distance from our residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacombi is a NYC chain taqueria with several establishments across the city. We had been to the Flatiron location of Tacombi several times before, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a proper Tacombi post. Because we actually took pictures of the food in the new LIC location, we&amp;rsquo;ll share those here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adda Indian Canteen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indian/adda-indian-canteen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 15:24:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indian/adda-indian-canteen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Indian restaurant has been around for a few years and has actually garnered a lot of positive attention. I had seen this on Seamless a few times, and it was close to where we live such that walking to here would be very easy. When you walk in, the atmosphere is pretty loud and lively. The walls are decorated with prints of newspapers, so it presents itself as a rather trendy place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tacuba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:28:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacuba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every few weeks, we make a market run, and we pass by this small area in Astoria that is relatively close to the market. Nearby, they have a few chain restaurants as well as some NYC specific restaurants. This Mexican restaurant seems to always be happening, so we decided to give it a try this time around. They have a ton of tables, so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much of a problem securing an indoor or outdoor table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Takumen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to meet my partner the next block at Casa Enrique, but for some reason they mistook a Japanese restaurant for a Mexican restaurant and ended up here. They found it weird that there were no lines, whereas I went to Casa Enrique and encountered a line. Because Casa Enrique doesn&amp;rsquo;t take walk-ins and the line was getting rather long, we decided to just eat here, and to my surprise, it was a good substitute.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tournesol</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/tournesol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 15:44:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/tournesol/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This French restaurant is located at the southern part of Vernon Blvd right across the street from Cafe Henri. We were able to walk in without reservations. The interior is quite cozy in this COVID environment as it has this very French (Paris) cafe feel to it. Each table was separated by a plastic wall. Be warned though that this place only accepts cash or AMEX. More on that later, so onto the food&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cyclo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:33:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there had been a large number of Asian restaurants in the Long Island City and Astoria vicinity, vietnamese restaurants are still fairly limited. I was kind of craving for some pho since it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years, and this one was within walkable distance. The city recently allowed 25% dine in, and the reviews for this restaurant seemed fairly decent. The interior was decorated pretty homely, and the tables were spaced decently apart with screen separators. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the food.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Suzuki Shokudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 22:05:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astoria has a lot of Mediterranean restaurants and is seldom appealing for its Asian food. However, in the last few months prior the pandemic, there have been several Korean and Chinese/Taiwanese restaurants that were opening, so it&amp;rsquo;s starting to make a presence. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by this neighborhood Japanese sushi joint several times and were surprised about how low key it is. After looking at the menu, we decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Psari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:38:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what&amp;rsquo;s one of the great things about Astoria? It&amp;rsquo;s the excellent Greek seafood restaurants that are within walking distances of each other. We had been to Taverna Kyclades before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we&amp;rsquo;ve dined at their competitors. This was a restaurant that was within walking distance from our Food Bazaar trek on the way back home, so we thought to stop by and give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Quality</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/top-quality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 16:28:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/top-quality/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a local neighborhood spot that has plenty of outdoor seating and social distancing. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting place in that it&amp;rsquo;s kind of in the middle of nowhere. The restaurant reminds me a lot of Williamsburg areas in that they take a warehouse and convert it into a nice comforting eatery. We sat in the outdoor patio area which is very airy and has plenty of comfortable space. We saw they had some electric heaters mounted in the roofs of the patio, so it seemed they are prepared for the colder months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sapps</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sapps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 20:43:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sapps/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this pandemic, restaurants are trying all sorts of ways to do outdoor dining. What was interesting about Sapps was that they set up dining tables next door in the front of a mechanic shop but with plenty of distance between tables. They also put out propane powered heat warmers. When you arrive, you can basically choose your own seat, and the waiters will bring the water to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Queens Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/queens-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:30:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/queens-room/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a place along Ditmars Blvd in Astoria, relatively close to Taverna Kyclades. There is a lot of interesting outdoor setup on this street. The menu itself appears fairly simple, but this place had been highly recommended to us for the easy going vibe. For this COVID environment, the tables are organized north to south along the side street instead of the main street of Ditmars. It definitely felt a little safer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M.Wells</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is across the street from Food Cellar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in a garage and used to serve a lot of steak dishes. The menu has changed into a more casual patio like experience (I am guessing just for the summer). When we arrived, there was no table service. Instead you have to go to the counter and place your order there. The menus are shown via QRCode. After you place your order, you carry the utensils, dishes, and drinks back to your table. The waiter will serve the dishes, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go pick up that. When you order, you (can) leave with them your credit card to open a tab. When you check out, they will tell you that gratuity is already included.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>American Brass</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 18:50:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a restaurant from the same people that brought &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/"&gt;Maiella&lt;/a&gt;. Even though that restaurant was modern Italian, this one was more New American. It sits across the Gantry park near the Hunters Point library. Our first visit was on a Sunday, prior to the day that New York City had to shutdown dining in restaurants due to the coronavirus. Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t really out and about, the restaurant had many empty tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Mian Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:26:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astoria in the last few months has seen an uptick on Asian restaurants that aren&amp;rsquo;t fusion and are more authentic. This one just happens to be on Broadway near my partner&amp;rsquo;s old neighborhood. We&amp;rsquo;ve been around this area before going to eat Shanghainese food. Today, it&amp;rsquo;s for noodles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-mian-lounge%2F1_braised_beef_tendon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the &lt;strong&gt;braised beef tendon&lt;/strong&gt;. It was marinated in chili oil, garlic, scallions, sesame oil, and other things that I probably missed. It&amp;rsquo;s a very traditional cold appetizer dish. The beef tendon was actually quite crunchy but cooked properly and thoroughly. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Chinese restaurants in NYC where the tendons were hard as rock. But here, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that it was cooked thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Maiella</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 15:42:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/maiella%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight was another venture out to the area around Vernon Blvd. There are so many restaurants here to try. This one here is an Italian restaurant near Gantry park. There are a lot of cars for some reason compared to other parts of Long Island City. The restaurant was able to accommodate us as a pair of walk-ins at around 6:30 PM on a Saturday evening easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>R40</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/r40/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 23:17:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/r40/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking on Yelp, we found that this new Argentine restaurant opened up on Vernon Blvd pretty recently in Long Island City. The menu has a lot of interesting and affordable meat dishes. It&amp;rsquo;s great that this street is opening a lot of cool restaurants of various cuisines. It appears they have a patio in the back that would be pretty awesome once the weather warms up. I can imagine this place being a super popular hot spot in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Inkan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/the-inkan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 21:24:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/the-inkan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a forever hunt for the best lomo saltado in NYC, this is another place we tried. This restaurant is located near Vernon where all the restaurants are, and it was relatively easy to walk in without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-inkan%2F1_passion_fruit_juice.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the &lt;strong&gt;passion fruit juice with water&lt;/strong&gt; which was basically passion fruit syrup with water and crushed ice. It was pretty good, but it was pretty obvious that you could probably make this at home. It was neither sweet or sour, so they chose a good water/syrup ratio here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Madera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/madera/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 15:01:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/madera/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to explore the neighborhood in Long Island City. This street is littered with all sorts of restaurants, and the recent one that got our interest was this Cuban themed restaurant. We were able to walk in without any reservations on a Friday night around 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/madera%2F1_bread.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our meal, we were served &lt;strong&gt;bread&lt;/strong&gt; with a chimichurri variant. The bread was lukewarm and not toasted much at all, but the inside was soft.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Murasaki</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/murasaki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:39:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/murasaki/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another nice neighborhood spot off Vernon Blvd in Long Island City. Reviews seem to rave about how good this neighborhood sushi spot is, so we decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/murasaki%2F0_sparkling_sake.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;peach sparkling sake&lt;/strong&gt; was relatively inexpensive and mighty tasty. The peach flavor tasted artificial, but it was still pretty good. It felt like drinking champagne without the heavy alcohol taste and with that artificial peach sweetener.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tuk Tuk</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/tuk-tuk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 22:19:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/tuk-tuk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tuk-tuk%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;rsquo;re exploring the Long Island City neighborhood, this was a pretty good find. It&amp;rsquo;s on Vernon Blvd where there are a ton of neighborhood restaurants. About 2 blocks away is a park that is in vicinity of the Long Island City sign and lets you view Manhattan from the east. We&amp;rsquo;ve been here a few times, and we always notice a decent amount of locals that continue to stop by. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively easy to eat here without needing to make a reservation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Go Nonna</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/go-nonna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 22:44:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/go-nonna/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a local restaurant to Long Island City that classifies itself as an Italian Argentine restaurant. The place is super small, but it feels nice and cozy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/go-nonna%2F1_chicken_piccata.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;chicken piccata&lt;/strong&gt; is served with capers in a lemon and butter sauce, served with roasted potatoes. This dish was actually really good. The potatoes had a nice crunch to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/go-nonna%2F2_lasagna_marchigiane.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;lasagna marchigiane&lt;/strong&gt; has bechamel, bolognese, and parmigiano. The tomato sauce was pretty good. It was sweet with a little sour to it, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was homemade or not. I wish the texture was more chunky though, but still it was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dim Sum Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 15:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/dim-sum-palace%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the evening and where could be a good place to get fairly traditional Cantonese style Chinese food? Dim Sum Palace! We originally visited the Midtown location pre-pandemic, and it was pretty decent. Recently, they opened another location in Long Island City in a dense new-aged Chinese area. We&amp;rsquo;ve been missing Cantonese-style restaurants, especially dim sum, in this very close quartered area of over abundant boba places and spicy cuisines. We were able to walk in without reservations around 5:00 PM on a Saturday without issues. This restaurant is located in the former Brooks 1890 bar next to the Long Island City court house on Jackson Ave.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Penthouse 808</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/penthouse-808/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 16:13:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/penthouse-808/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bar / restaurant is located on the 6th floor in the Ravel Hotel in Long Island City. The view is fairly nice as you can see Midtown from the east, but it is not stellar since it sits slightly lower than the Queensborough bridge and there are 2 smoke stack obstructions as you look towards the Empire State building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered some bottles of Rose and an entree.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dun Huang</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dun-huang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 22:51:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dun-huang/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an updated entry to Dun Huang. The original &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/dun-huang-east-village-new-york-8"&gt;East Village location is closed&lt;/a&gt;, but they opened another location out in Long Island City. They have several locations spread throughout the city. Dun Huang advertises itself as authentic Northwestern Chinese food. The menu at this location pales in comparison to what we got in the East Village location, so I&amp;rsquo;ll still share the differences for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance"&gt;Ambiance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decor at the Long Island City location is pretty no frills. It feels they have two rooms: one &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; dining area and another dining area next to the window.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jaew Hon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/jaew-hon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 23:04:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/jaew-hon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of venturing out to deep Queens. The trains out here are probably not as bad as going into Manhattan, but it sure feels bad. The E trains today were barely running, and the R trains were making local stops going towards Flushing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, today was one of those days where we felt like grubbing some all you can eat hot pot. Instead of Chinese style, we heard of this place in Jackson Heights that was Thai style. It was pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bund on Broadway</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:29:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/bund-on-broadway/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astoria is not really a place known for having typical Shanghainese food. I always think of it as having more latin and mediterranean influences to those respective demographics in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant though was surprisingly pretty decent for this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bund-on-broadway%2F1_drunken_chicken.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;drunken chicken&lt;/strong&gt; I normally don&amp;rsquo;t find in many restsaurants. Here, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as my cousin&amp;rsquo;s or my mother&amp;rsquo;s version as it&amp;rsquo;s WAY too salty, chicken pieces don&amp;rsquo;t appear cut right, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it was marinated well. Some parts were very soaked, and other parts had next to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kondo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kondo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 17:37:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kondo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very clean sushi spot close to the Broadway subway station off the yellow N and W line. Instead of going all sushi, I decided to mix it up a little with standard Japanese snacks over straight up sushi cut rolls, sorta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kondo%2F1_sea_snails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sea snails&lt;/strong&gt; were cooked in a dashi broth, and were pretty tasty. I think my piece wasn&amp;rsquo;t cleaned entirely properly because there was some grit, but it tasted ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xi'an Famous Food</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 22:27:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to this restaurant multiple times in various neighborhoods, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t documented it till now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xian-famous-food%2F1_spicy_and_sour_spinach_dumplings.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually get the &lt;strong&gt;spicy tingly beef&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but to be honest I do like Very Fresh Noodles in the Chelsea Market more. However this place was next to me, so the convenience is much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xian-famous-food%2F2_spicy_tingly_beef_noodle.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spicy and sour spinach dumplings&lt;/strong&gt; are also really good too. I love the vinegary taste wih everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Huntress Whiskey N Wings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 21:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vibe in this place was pretty cool. It reminded me of being in one of those Lord of the Rings tavern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings%2F1_poutine.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;poutine&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty salty, but it was a good match with the beers. I wish the cheese curds were a little warmer and more abundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings%2F2_savage.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;savage&lt;/strong&gt; is actually regular hot wings. The hot wings tasted like they were fried first then doused in sauce after. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice texture combination, and it&amp;rsquo;s how I prefer my hot wings. The wings themselves didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a lot of flavor outside of the sauce though. There are some french fries that the wings sit on that soak up the sauce and oil.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Imperial Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/imperial-palace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 22:13:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/imperial-palace/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a trek, but it&amp;rsquo;s a much cheaper place for Peking Duck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/imperial-palace%2F1_peking_duck.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole &lt;strong&gt;peking duck&lt;/strong&gt; was actually pretty good and reasonably price. The skin was a nice crisp, and the duck was pleasantly fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/imperial-palace%2F2_fried_shrimp.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fried shrimp&lt;/strong&gt; was mistakenly ordered. We thought it was going to be the whole pepper salted shrimp with head. Even then, it was also decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Massa Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/massa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 17:00:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/massa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place was pretty dead when I went, but the pizza was excellent. In some ways I actually liked this more than Lombardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/massa%2F1_pepperoni.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a margarita pizza with pepperoni on it, and it was tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would love to go back and try their stromboli or calzones as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="overall-impression"&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a nice addition to the sparse Long Island City neighborhood. The pepperoni pizza quality and ingredients tasted really good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taverna Kyclades</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:08:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We came here around 8:30 PM on a rather cold Saturday evening. Typically there is a long line outside, but today people were crowded and bundled up inside. I put my name down for 2. The wait was approximately 40-50 minutes. We had contemplated leaving when we heard the wait time, but we decided to power through and wait. It was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;em&gt;July 1, 2023&lt;/em&gt;, we visited this restaurant again, and it has moved from it&amp;rsquo;s previous location. For a table of 4, we just had to wait approximately 30 minutes on a Saturday around 7:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Favela Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 14:55:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Had the churrasco here, and it was pretty good. The chicken and sausage was good. Make sure the steak is ordered medium rare. We ordered medium, and it came out borderline medium well. The caipirinha was really good too. Get the passion fruit and guava. Avoid the kiwi.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to start with this. I loathe cash only places considering the price of this is not exactly cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F1_u_&amp;amp;_i.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;U &amp;amp; I&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was really good but not for +$20. The bowl was rather small although the ingredients were pretty fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F2_the_flying_pig.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;flying pig&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was the biggest disappointment I&amp;rsquo;ve had. The broth was just OK. It&amp;rsquo;s subtly different than the normal tonkatsu style broth. I also opted for an ounce of the jamon iberico. I added an additional onsen tamago, which is basically a sous vide egg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shanghai You Garden</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shanghai-you-garden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 13:43:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shanghai-you-garden/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Known for their XLBs, it was pretty darn tasty. They also have stinky tofu too and it&amp;rsquo;s all pretty cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pastrami Plaza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/pastrami-plaza/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 22:16:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/pastrami-plaza/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pastrami was ok. It was moist yet tips were dry. Food was cheap though, so might be good for lazy dinners. They have other things.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tamashii Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 22:15:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent ramen noodles. Soup was a little salty. The egg was disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Shack</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:46:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent ramen. Got some super fancy ramen, and it was fat. Not the best though and it&amp;rsquo;s in a not so great neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lucky Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lucky-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:25:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lucky-pizza/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One word: cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casa Enrique</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:49:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been to this Michelin 1 star restaurant with a friend for brunch. We were underwhelmed as we&amp;rsquo;ve been to several Mexican restaurants in Southern California. My partner hasn&amp;rsquo;t tried this before, so I thought to give it another shot for dinner. Note that the restaurant does not take reservations. We were able to walk in at 5 PM on a Saturday evening and be seated indoors right away. Take note that there is usually a line outside because people want to wait for outdoor tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waheyo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/waheyo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:48:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/waheyo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting Chipotle/Dos Toros style but feels a little more ghetto? Food was ok but cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/jora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:36:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/jora/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is located at the southern tip of Long Island City close to Vernon. I would probably classify this as a more upscale Peruvian restaurant with some romantic vibes to it. There is another Peruvian restaurant north of here that is probably more casual and less formal. Truth be told, we actually like this restaurant a lot more than the other one as this one is more consistent albeit a little more pricey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pelicana Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/pelicana-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:45:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/pelicana-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Korean wings. They have ice cream beer which was a gimmick. It&amp;rsquo;s mediocre at best. They do give you these finger &amp;ldquo;condom&amp;rdquo; looking things to handle the chicken.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ChaTime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/chatime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:27:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/chatime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Passion fruit green tea was just OK.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kulu Desserts</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/kulu-desserts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:25:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/kulu-desserts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ok. Lots of durian stuff. Black sesame wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prince Tea House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/prince-tea-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:18:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/prince-tea-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good crepes and milk tea. The decor is interesting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/prince-tea-house%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;iced passionfruit green tea&lt;/strong&gt; was a nice drink for the hot summer weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/prince-tea-house%2F2_takoyaki.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;takoyaki&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clever Blend</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/coffee/clever-blend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:06:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/coffee/clever-blend/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bagel was pretty bad. The toasted coconut cold brew wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Birch Coffee</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/coffee/birch-coffee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:04:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/coffee/birch-coffee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The cold brew was pretty good, and the Ethiopian beans were good too.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Happy Stony Noodle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/happy-stony-noodle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:49:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/happy-stony-noodle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cheap. It&amp;rsquo;s ok beef noodle + stinky tofu. Beef noodle with mustard green was ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New May Wah 359</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/new-may-wah-359/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:32:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/new-may-wah-359/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese food. Rice cakes good. Everything else eh. Cash only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is PERMA closed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:29:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao is one of those XLB restaurants that is not often brought up in the XLB fights because it&amp;rsquo;s not that accessible. The original location is in Flushing, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit far from Manhattan. Many people do end up going to Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai to get their fix, but fortunately now a Manhattan location of this restaurant has opened in Koreatown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had originally gone to the Flushing location and said the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Baroness Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/baroness-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:16:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/baroness-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good albeit expensive. The beer selection here is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Burger Garage</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/burger-garage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:15:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/burger-garage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of Pops but more standard burgers. Still pretty good and not too pricey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>