<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Queens on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/queens/</link><description>Recent content in Queens on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/queens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Fer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:03:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</guid><description>Fer is a nearby neighborhood restaurant that has similar spicy features comparable to other Chinese restaurants around the area. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of little shops because it usually means you can get your food pretty fast, and it feels casual. We stopped by late Saturday afternoon, and there was hardly anyone there. We were seated right away, and the food came out very fast. The menu has a lot of chili oil in all of their items, but luckily the spice was tolerable when ordered mild.</description></item><item><title>Red Sorghum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:50:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</guid><description>Red Sorghum has recently opened in Long Island City, and is yet another spicy Chinese restaurant. It seems that there are quite a few around Long Island City. This location replaced the closed Penny Bridge. Because this was really close to our place and we were meeting friends, we decided on this restaurant to try different dishes. They proud themselves in baijiu, which is China&amp;rsquo;s liquor to Korean soju. There are several cocktails made with them if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.</description></item><item><title>Knock Knock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</guid><description>Knock Knock is a nearby neighborhood cafe that has a mix of Cantonese-style dishes. The decor and the style of the food reminds me a bit of the San Gabriel Valley in Southern California, where there are a lot of small cafe shops opening serving quick eats. My cousin had visited this a few weeks ago for breakfast, and they said they were pleasantly surprised at the coffee. That was a catalyst for us to check this place out to see how its actual food was.</description></item><item><title>Vert Frais</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 21:36:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</guid><description>On a lazy Sunday, we decided to stay around our living area to eat. There have been several new restaurants that have opened in the past few months, and this one is the most recent one. The restaurant features ramen and European-Japanese dishes from Nobuyuki Shikanai, the owner of Kanoyama in the East Village. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Sunday at around 6 PM.</description></item><item><title>Nai Brother</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 16:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</guid><description>In our area, there has been a plethora of Chinese restaurants opening. Literally around us, there are at least 3 hot pot places. I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider Nai Brothers a hot pot, but what grabbed my attention was that it specializes in sour fish soups. Nai Brothers is a very small chain with its primary location in Flushing, and this Long Island City location being it&amp;rsquo;s smaller sibling that&amp;rsquo;s closer to Manhattan.</description></item><item><title>Murray's Cheese Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:54:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been frequent shoppers at Murray&amp;rsquo;s Cheese for our normal night in eating cheese and charcuterie. This location in Long Island City also has a restaurant part of it. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few glances at the menu, and there were some individual things that caught my eye. Fortunately, it was a lazy Saturday, and it was raining. This would be the ideal night to try this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations at 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>SVL Souvlaki Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:00:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/svl-souvlaki-bar/</guid><description>We tend to go to Food Bazaar on the outskirts of Long Island City often, and the easiest way to get there by train whilst having dinner options would be to exit off Steinway St in Astoria via the M/R train. This area has a mix of random restaurants ranging from national chains like Applebee&amp;rsquo;s to Mediterranean and Latin options. This restaurant is literally right across street from the subway entrance, so it was very easy to access.</description></item><item><title>Don Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</guid><description>My partner was craving for lomo saltado, and they found this on Yelp. I mentioned to them that we had ordered this via Seamless before, but nonetheless we decided to check out this place in person. They actually have 2 locations near us: either in Astoria or in Sunnyside. The trains towards Astoria are just atrocious on weekends in that there&amp;rsquo;s like a 15 minute delay between trains. Going on the 7 train would have netted us better towards Sunnyside.</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes.</description></item><item><title>Zaab Zaab</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/zaab-zaab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 13:04:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/zaab-zaab/</guid><description>Zaab Zaab is a highly rated New York Times restaurant that serves North Eastern Thai food. We have been trying various Thai flavors that are very different than your typical Thai restaurant. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that these North/Eastern restaurants tend to have much more bolder and spicier flavors that are a bit more adventurous than what you&amp;rsquo;d normally expect. This is located fairly close to the 7 or E train by exiting off Jackson Heights / Roosevelt Ave.</description></item><item><title>Sobremesa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 11:49:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</guid><description>When I first saw the word &amp;ldquo;sobremesa&amp;rdquo;, I instantly thought of dessert since that is what it means in Brazilian Portuguese. This restaurant is more of a taco place and is relatively new in the Long Island City neighborhood, and it&amp;rsquo;s located in a barren neighborhood with a bunch of empty warehouses. Surprisingly, there was a beer place opened next door, and there was an outside picnic area where people can enjoy their tacos in a social environment.</description></item><item><title>Khun Noo Thai Noodle House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/khun-noo-thai-noodle-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:10:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/khun-noo-thai-noodle-house/</guid><description>The summer heat is starting to come to NYC, and it makes everyone including me feel especially groggy. This was also a lazy weekend since we&amp;rsquo;re mentally preparing for the humidity to rapidly increase. Fortunately on this day, it was not too bad. Instead of ordering for delivery, my partner wanted to travel to eat Thai somewhere. We centered on the Woodside area since we had visited before at Thailand&amp;rsquo;s Center Point.</description></item><item><title>Kyuramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:37:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</guid><description>The Kyuramen restaurant chain has been slowly making its way throughout the greater NYC area. They just opened a location out in Long Island City which is not too far from where we live. This restaurant had construction signs early in the pandemic and just never opened until now. We thought we would be able to get seated right away on an early Sunday afternoon, but they checked us into Yelp and we had to wait around for about 15 minutes for a table of 2.</description></item><item><title>Piatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:10:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow gotten my partner to enjoy pasta a bit more. Some sacrifices have to be made such as looking for lasagna, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. I have to thank Tony Soprano and how he always made Italian sandwiches and pasta look so delicious. We had to stop by the pharmacy, and nearby was this incognito Italian wood fire pizza place. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Saturday evening around 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Sweet Chick</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:07:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</guid><description>Having been to Sweet Chick before in North Williamsburg, I vaguely remember this place having pretty good crust. I often get Pies N Thighs confused with this. In Williamsburg, there&amp;rsquo;s always a line outside, so when we walked by here with no line, we decided on a spur of the moment to try this out. When you sit at a table, there is a QR code that you can scan and even place your order.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Kilo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:12:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</guid><description>We have been here before prior to the pandemic when it was a weigh by the pound buffet-style. My partner took me here once because they had been here before several times and said it was their favorite. However that one time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it because the meat was all overcooked, and the rest of the sides were very mediocre. They agreed with me and were surprised by how mediocre it was on that day.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Festival</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chicken-festival/</guid><description>This Peruvian restaurant was also on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list of cheap eats to try. The menu was quite similar to the prior Peruvian restaurant, Caravan Chicken we went to a few weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s conveniently located off the Ditmars N/W train on Ditmars itself. We arrived here at 7 PM, and there was no line nor patrons inside. We were not sure what to make of this considering how much we enjoyed the last restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Caravan Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:17:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/caravan-chicken/</guid><description>Lately, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for budget type of restaurants outside of the main areas of Manhattan. This restaurant came at a suggestion from my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend. It&amp;rsquo;s located pretty close to us on Broadway in Astoria and fairly close to the N subway. It really is a no frills restaurant with a lot of local take out and dine-in traffic. We arrived here around 5 PM on a Sunday evening, and finding a seat for 2 people was pretty straight forward.</description></item><item><title>Thailand's Center Point</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thailands-center-point/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:42:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thailands-center-point/</guid><description>We were on our way to get some delicious Popeyes chicken on the 7 train, and little and behold, the 7 trains were running express from Queensboro towards Flushing and were running local heading towards Manhattan. Normally the 7 runs local both ways, but they were doing track work, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite clear. The next stop after Queensboro was 61st Woodside, which basically skipped our desired stop by 3 stops.</description></item><item><title>Sami's Kabob House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:08:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</guid><description>In the city, there are not too many Afghan restaurants to choose from. I&amp;rsquo;ve only had Afghani food once in my life in NorCal, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t ever make me yearn for it. However, I thought the menu looked enticing since we were looking for hummus and kabobs around Long Island City. This restaurant is located on the busy Vernon Blvd, which is becoming a happening street for this area. This location of Sami&amp;rsquo;s Kabob is their second location, whereas their first location is in Astoria.</description></item><item><title>Penny Bridge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</guid><description>Near where we live, they semi-opened this restaurant on Jackson Blvd at the start of the pandemic only to shut it down pretty quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here several dozen times, and it was never really opened until the last 6 months. Reading online, it seemed they had to change their menu several times for adjustments for some reason, and the menu itself initially seemed basic and not overly attractive. It felt they were trying really hard to attract a brunch crowd, so we have not been enthusiastic about trying.</description></item><item><title>Ziggle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:51:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</guid><description>This restaurant is sandwiched at the cusp of Sunnyside between a AYCE Korean BBQ restaurant and a newly opened Sonic fast food joint. The menu looks pretty traditional Korean, and it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to try these types of restaurants in different neighborhoods. This one is rarely as busy as its next door neighbors, but I had some expectations of how this would turn out. When we arrived at 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, we were the only patrons in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Gan Hoo BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:11:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</guid><description>Flushing is the NYC mecca for Chinese food. It&amp;rsquo;s at the end of the 7 train line heading east, and it takes about 40 minutes from Manhattan on weekends. Many restaurants and stalls only accept cash, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite different than being in Manhattan or Long Island City. My partner had a friend that wanted to meet in Flushing to try out Korean BBQ. I thought there would be several near Main Street, but it seems all the decent Korean BBQ places are least a mile east of the Main street subway station.</description></item></channel></rss>