<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LIC on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/lic/</link><description>Recent content in LIC on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/lic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Fer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:03:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</guid><description>Fer is a nearby neighborhood restaurant that has similar spicy features comparable to other Chinese restaurants around the area. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of little shops because it usually means you can get your food pretty fast, and it feels casual. We stopped by late Saturday afternoon, and there was hardly anyone there. We were seated right away, and the food came out very fast. The menu has a lot of chili oil in all of their items, but luckily the spice was tolerable when ordered mild.</description></item><item><title>Red Sorghum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:50:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</guid><description>Red Sorghum has recently opened in Long Island City, and is yet another spicy Chinese restaurant. It seems that there are quite a few around Long Island City. This location replaced the closed Penny Bridge. Because this was really close to our place and we were meeting friends, we decided on this restaurant to try different dishes. They proud themselves in baijiu, which is China&amp;rsquo;s liquor to Korean soju. There are several cocktails made with them if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.</description></item><item><title>Knock Knock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</guid><description>Knock Knock is a nearby neighborhood cafe that has a mix of Cantonese-style dishes. The decor and the style of the food reminds me a bit of the San Gabriel Valley in Southern California, where there are a lot of small cafe shops opening serving quick eats. My cousin had visited this a few weeks ago for breakfast, and they said they were pleasantly surprised at the coffee. That was a catalyst for us to check this place out to see how its actual food was.</description></item><item><title>Vert Frais</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 21:36:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/vert-frais/</guid><description>On a lazy Sunday, we decided to stay around our living area to eat. There have been several new restaurants that have opened in the past few months, and this one is the most recent one. The restaurant features ramen and European-Japanese dishes from Nobuyuki Shikanai, the owner of Kanoyama in the East Village. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Sunday at around 6 PM.</description></item><item><title>Nai Brother</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 16:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nai-brother/</guid><description>In our area, there has been a plethora of Chinese restaurants opening. Literally around us, there are at least 3 hot pot places. I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider Nai Brothers a hot pot, but what grabbed my attention was that it specializes in sour fish soups. Nai Brothers is a very small chain with its primary location in Flushing, and this Long Island City location being it&amp;rsquo;s smaller sibling that&amp;rsquo;s closer to Manhattan.</description></item><item><title>Murray's Cheese Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:54:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been frequent shoppers at Murray&amp;rsquo;s Cheese for our normal night in eating cheese and charcuterie. This location in Long Island City also has a restaurant part of it. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few glances at the menu, and there were some individual things that caught my eye. Fortunately, it was a lazy Saturday, and it was raining. This would be the ideal night to try this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations at 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes.</description></item><item><title>Sobremesa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 11:49:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/sobremesa/</guid><description>When I first saw the word &amp;ldquo;sobremesa&amp;rdquo;, I instantly thought of dessert since that is what it means in Brazilian Portuguese. This restaurant is more of a taco place and is relatively new in the Long Island City neighborhood, and it&amp;rsquo;s located in a barren neighborhood with a bunch of empty warehouses. Surprisingly, there was a beer place opened next door, and there was an outside picnic area where people can enjoy their tacos in a social environment.</description></item><item><title>Kyuramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:37:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</guid><description>The Kyuramen restaurant chain has been slowly making its way throughout the greater NYC area. They just opened a location out in Long Island City which is not too far from where we live. This restaurant had construction signs early in the pandemic and just never opened until now. We thought we would be able to get seated right away on an early Sunday afternoon, but they checked us into Yelp and we had to wait around for about 15 minutes for a table of 2.</description></item><item><title>Piatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:10:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow gotten my partner to enjoy pasta a bit more. Some sacrifices have to be made such as looking for lasagna, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. I have to thank Tony Soprano and how he always made Italian sandwiches and pasta look so delicious. We had to stop by the pharmacy, and nearby was this incognito Italian wood fire pizza place. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Saturday evening around 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Sweet Chick</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:07:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</guid><description>Having been to Sweet Chick before in North Williamsburg, I vaguely remember this place having pretty good crust. I often get Pies N Thighs confused with this. In Williamsburg, there&amp;rsquo;s always a line outside, so when we walked by here with no line, we decided on a spur of the moment to try this out. When you sit at a table, there is a QR code that you can scan and even place your order.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Sami's Kabob House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:08:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/afghan/samis-kabob-house/</guid><description>In the city, there are not too many Afghan restaurants to choose from. I&amp;rsquo;ve only had Afghani food once in my life in NorCal, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t ever make me yearn for it. However, I thought the menu looked enticing since we were looking for hummus and kabobs around Long Island City. This restaurant is located on the busy Vernon Blvd, which is becoming a happening street for this area. This location of Sami&amp;rsquo;s Kabob is their second location, whereas their first location is in Astoria.</description></item><item><title>Penny Bridge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</guid><description>Near where we live, they semi-opened this restaurant on Jackson Blvd at the start of the pandemic only to shut it down pretty quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here several dozen times, and it was never really opened until the last 6 months. Reading online, it seemed they had to change their menu several times for adjustments for some reason, and the menu itself initially seemed basic and not overly attractive. It felt they were trying really hard to attract a brunch crowd, so we have not been enthusiastic about trying.</description></item><item><title>Noodlecraft</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:09:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</guid><description>We walked by this restaurant one evening as we were walking back, and I was reminded that this was something I wanted to try. At a quick glance, the interior seemed pretty spacious, and I always go back and forth on whether we can go here. My partner is never fanatical about noodles, but luckily this restaurant has other things such as dim sum and cold cut appetizers. This restaurant opened last year during the pandemic in October and seemed to have a pretty steady flow of repeat customers.</description></item><item><title>Blend on the Water</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/blend-on-the-water/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 21:03:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/blend-on-the-water/</guid><description>This is located right next to the water near restaurants like Maiella and American Brass. Whenever we try walk-in, they always tells us it&amp;rsquo;s an hour wait even when there&amp;rsquo;s no one outside. Since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything else close by that we wanted to try, we were able to book a reservation for an early Saturday dinner again.
Ambiance For some reason this restaurant is very popular with a large latin clientele.</description></item><item><title>Partners Coffee</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/partners-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 10:26:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/partners-coffee/</guid><description>Partners Coffee was formerly known as Toby&amp;rsquo;s Estate coffee. When I first moved to NYC many years ago to Williamsburg, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt they had my preferred coffee beans and coffee. The general atmosphere probably falls a little under &amp;ldquo;hipster&amp;rdquo; coffee, but it&amp;rsquo;s quite delicious. I have always tried to visit other coffee shops in NYC for their coffee and beans, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always fallen back to this. In some locations, they have brewing classes and a roaster, but because this one in Long Island City is much smaller, it&amp;rsquo;s just a straight up coffee cafe.</description></item><item><title>Manducatis Rustica</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 16:43:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve visited most of the Long Island City restaurants around the Vernon Blvd area. We had stopped by Blend on the Water hopefully for a walk-in, but there was already a wait. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by Manducatis Rustica several times, and we figured it was worth a shot to see if they can take us. When we arrived, there was hardly anyone there. They told us that they had garden seating, so we opted for that.</description></item><item><title>Levante</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</guid><description>A new Trader Joes opened up in Long Island City, and I was hoping to make turkey tacos with guacamole. Unfortunately, the avocados were not ripe enough yet, so I mentioned to my partner we can eat out. The first thought that came to their mind was this place because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few nearby restaurants we have not tried yet but have seen a lot of people standing outside.</description></item><item><title>Woodbines</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:58:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</guid><description>Woodbines is another craft beer and bar restaurant on Vernon Blvd in Long Island City that has fish and chips on the menu which my partner as craving for. At 5:00 PM, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people, and it was easy to get a seat inside the restaurant. Keep in mind, they do follow COVID protocols, so they asked us to check our temperature against the wall. They definitely have an outdoor setup, and that seemed to be more popular with the guests as the night went on.</description></item><item><title>Tacombi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:23:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacombi/</guid><description>Long Island City is starting to turn into another North Williamsburg but with less hipsters. There is a flurry of restaurants and stores that appear to be opening up soon. Along with Vernon Blvd, Jackson Ave is starting to show some liveliness especially around the Dutch Kills bar area. This Tacombi outpost just opened very recently within walking distance from our residence.
Tacombi is a NYC chain taqueria with several establishments across the city.</description></item><item><title>Adda Indian Canteen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indian/adda-indian-canteen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 15:24:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indian/adda-indian-canteen/</guid><description>Summary This Indian restaurant has been around for a few years and has actually garnered a lot of positive attention. I had seen this on Seamless a few times, and it was close to where we live such that walking to here would be very easy. When you walk in, the atmosphere is pretty loud and lively. The walls are decorated with prints of newspapers, so it presents itself as a rather trendy place.</description></item><item><title>Takumen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</guid><description>Summary I was supposed to meet my partner the next block at Casa Enrique, but for some reason they mistook a Japanese restaurant for a Mexican restaurant and ended up here. They found it weird that there were no lines, whereas I went to Casa Enrique and encountered a line. Because Casa Enrique doesn&amp;rsquo;t take walk-ins and the line was getting rather long, we decided to just eat here, and to my surprise, it was a good substitute.</description></item></channel></rss>