<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sunnyside on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/sunnyside/</link><description>Recent content in Sunnyside on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/sunnyside/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/don-pollo/</guid><description>My partner was craving for lomo saltado, and they found this on Yelp. I mentioned to them that we had ordered this via Seamless before, but nonetheless we decided to check out this place in person. They actually have 2 locations near us: either in Astoria or in Sunnyside. The trains towards Astoria are just atrocious on weekends in that there&amp;rsquo;s like a 15 minute delay between trains. Going on the 7 train would have netted us better towards Sunnyside.</description></item><item><title>Ziggle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:51:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</guid><description>This restaurant is sandwiched at the cusp of Sunnyside between a AYCE Korean BBQ restaurant and a newly opened Sonic fast food joint. The menu looks pretty traditional Korean, and it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to try these types of restaurants in different neighborhoods. This one is rarely as busy as its next door neighbors, but I had some expectations of how this would turn out. When we arrived at 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, we were the only patrons in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Wonder Pig Kbbq</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 14:43:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</guid><description>All you can eat (AYCE) Korean BBQ places are pretty sparse the closer you get to Manhattan. If you did find one, the quality is kind of questionable compared to the a&amp;rsquo;la carte places. We discovered this restaurant a few months back when we went to the Popeyes next door. It hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened yet, but there seems to be a few restaurants next to it that are opening in the very near future.</description></item><item><title>Pelicana Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/pelicana-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:45:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/pelicana-chicken/</guid><description>Korean wings. They have ice cream beer which was a gimmick. It&amp;rsquo;s mediocre at best. They do give you these finger &amp;ldquo;condom&amp;rdquo; looking things to handle the chicken.</description></item></channel></rss>