<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>South Village on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-village/</link><description>Recent content in South Village on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-village/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Haizea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 23:21:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</guid><description>Summary We were stoked that New York City has reopened indoor dining albeit @ 25% capacity. Yeah, some people say it&amp;rsquo;s not safe, but they are usually the same people that go visit their friends and family. The restaurants, believe it or not, do an excellent job sanitizing and giving space to diners and each other. Today was Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, and they had a few prixe menu options. We ended up going with Cupid&amp;rsquo;s Arrow Menu which we shared and was just a tasting of many of their items on the menu.</description></item><item><title>Gitano Jungle Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:22:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</guid><description>Summary This place is located near the James Hotel. They have an outdoors garden that has a decent view.
The chilaquiles was basically 2 eggs, crema, salsa verde, and crispy tortillas. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much else here. I thought it was pretty primitive and uninteresting. The salsa was good, but you wish there was some more meats and maybe avocado or something else to give it a little more flavor.
The chicken blt was pretty much what it says.</description></item><item><title>The Woo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 23:18:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</guid><description>Summary This is a surprising decent Korean restaurant in the South Village. Unlike Koreatown BBQ restaurants, this place actually has you cooking the meats just like in Los Angeles.
The banchan was on the blander side of things. The daikon was a little watery. The kimchi radish was decent but wasn&amp;rsquo;t as pickled as other Korean places. The broccoli was fine. Lastly, the kimchi was decent but again not as fermented as other places.</description></item><item><title>Hirohisa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 17:05:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</guid><description>Summary Hirohisa apparently has been around for a while, but they just received a Michelin star again this year.
With that in mind, I felt the price point $160 pp for the 9-course tasting + $70 sake pairing was a decent price for splurging for a special someone&amp;rsquo;s birthday dinner.
Just a note: they do respect some allergy restrictions. My guest had lobster specific allergies, and they were able to accomodate easy.</description></item><item><title>Felix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:11:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</guid><description>Summary This place is CASH ONLY as well. Food was pretty good, and it seems like a nice date spot.
I got the steak with bone marrow. The potato (au gratin style) was also pretty good. It also came with a side of brussel sprouts and bacon mish mash. The sauce was salty, but the steak was cooked nicely for a medium rare.
Final Verdict I&amp;rsquo;d come back here again if I was near the South Village, had cash, and wanted to eat something French.</description></item><item><title>Taureau</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 19:09:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</guid><description>This place is CASH ONLY. The chocolate fondu was good, but the cheese that we got was just ok. The meat quality was pretty good with the wine broth.</description></item></channel></rss>