<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>South Village on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-village/</link><description>Recent content in South Village on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:00:22 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-village/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hamburger America</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:40:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hamburger-america%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamburger America is a luncheonette-style restaurant with counters for eating a burger. It comes from an American chef George Motz, who is offering an homage to the history of the hamburger. It&amp;rsquo;s received a number of positive reviews from food critics for some reason, and Yelpers and food bloggers alike rave about this place. I came here as a quick stop around 4:30 PM on a Thursday evening, and I could walk in and sit on the stool without any trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Revelie Luncheonette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 18:00:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/revelie-luncheonette%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a quick and solo type of restaurant around the Hudson Square area. I decided to look into burgers, and I was debating Hamburger America and this Revelie Luncheonette. This restaurant is walk-in only and is across the street from Raoul&amp;rsquo;s. Since the burgers seem enticing and the restaurant received decent reviews, I decided to give this a try. I was able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Thursday and find an empty stool seat.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roscioli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:46:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/roscioli%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscioli has been on my list for a while since the original location of this restaurant is in Rome. This New York City alternative offers a pasta tasting menu, which looked quite interesting and affordable. I was able to book a reservation about a few weeks out for a 6 PM dinner. Keep in mind that the tasting is located downstairs, whereas the normal restaurant is located street level.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Haizea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 23:21:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/haizea/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were stoked that New York City has reopened indoor dining albeit @ 25% capacity. Yeah, some people say it&amp;rsquo;s not safe, but they are usually the same people that go visit their friends and family. The restaurants, believe it or not, do an excellent job sanitizing and giving space to diners and each other. Today was Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, and they had a few prixe menu options. We ended up going with &lt;strong&gt;Cupid&amp;rsquo;s Arrow Menu&lt;/strong&gt; which we shared and was just a tasting of many of their items on the menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gitano Jungle Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:22:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/gitano-jungle-room/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is located near the James Hotel. They have an outdoors garden that has a decent view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gitano-jungle-room%2F1_chilaquiles.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;chilaquiles&lt;/strong&gt; was basically 2 eggs, crema, salsa verde, and crispy tortillas. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much else here. I thought it was pretty primitive and uninteresting. The salsa was good, but you wish there was some more meats and maybe avocado or something else to give it a little more flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Woo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 23:18:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a surprising decent Korean restaurant in the South Village. Unlike Koreatown BBQ restaurants, this place actually has you cooking the meats just like in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-woo%2F1_banchan.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;banchan&lt;/strong&gt; was on the blander side of things. The daikon was a little watery. The kimchi radish was decent but wasn&amp;rsquo;t as pickled as other Korean places. The broccoli was fine. Lastly, the kimchi was decent but again not as fermented as other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hirohisa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 17:05:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hirohisa apparently has been around for a while, but they just received a Michelin star again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I felt the price point $160 pp for the 9-course tasting + $70 sake pairing was a decent price for splurging for a special someone&amp;rsquo;s birthday dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a note: they do respect some allergy restrictions. My guest had lobster specific allergies, and they were able to accomodate easy. She did not have any rashes or swelling at the end of the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Felix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:11:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is CASH ONLY as well. Food was pretty good, and it seems like a nice date spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/felix%2F1_steak.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the steak with bone marrow. The potato (au gratin style) was also pretty good. It also came with a side of brussel sprouts and bacon mish mash. The sauce was salty, but the steak was cooked nicely for a medium rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="overall-impression"&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d come back here again if I was near the South Village, had cash, and wanted to eat something French. I suppose since I don&amp;rsquo;t usually carry cash, then the chances are pretty dim.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taureau</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 19:09:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is CASH ONLY. The chocolate fondu was good, but the cheese that we got was just ok. The meat quality was pretty good with the wine broth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>