<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chelsea on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/chelsea/</link><description>Recent content in Chelsea on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 17:00:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/chelsea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crane Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/crane-club/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 17:00:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/crane-club/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/crane-club%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crane Club is located across the street from Chelsea Market. It&amp;rsquo;s being led by executive chef Melissa Rodriguez, who formerly oversaw Al Coro, which earned 2 Michelin stars at one point. This restaurant is under the Tao Hospitality Group, which oversees some upscale trendy hot spots like Hakkasan, Lava, and TAO Asian Bistro. We were able to make a reservation for the dining room very easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday night. This restaurant&amp;rsquo;s food was meant to be unapologetically fancy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Konban</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:44:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/konban%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Konban was a new katsu restaurant that was on my radar for a while. When it first opened, reservations were hard to come by. Now a few months later, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a reservation a week out. Because Manhattan has so few katsu-specialized options, this was going to be a very special experience. I was able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night for two people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zou Zou's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:02:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/zou-zous%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located near the Vessel and Hudson Yards, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for quite some time. They simply love Mediterranean small plates and dips. We actually had to make a reservation a few weeks out to nab our reservation at 5 PM on a Sunday night. The restaurant lies in this little courtyard where it leads into one of the Peloton offices. When we arrived, we were able to check in a few minutes early. The hosts asked us to wait at the bar, and when they were ready for dinner service, they will come get you and bring you to your table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Mermaid Inn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 22:33:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure of enjoying the company of one of our friends who is coming into town for work. This restaurant is conveniently close to the Highline and was also near their hotel. I vaguely recall that this is a very popular seafood restaurant down in West Village, and it had been on my list for a number of years. Surprisingly, they opened another location here, and we thought we&amp;rsquo;d go check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skirt Steak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/skirt-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/skirt-steak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed simple menus of steak frites. We visited &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/"&gt;L&amp;rsquo;entrecote&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a pretty good restaurant for a similar value as this one. When I arrived at 5:20 PM and because this restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t take reservations for small parties, there was already a line out of the door. Fortunately the total wait time for us was about 15 minutes in line because we volunteered for bar seats if they were available. We were hoping this restaurant would be another spot of equivalent, if not better, caliber steak frites. So how did it fare?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Genesis House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:14:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We saw this restaurant&amp;rsquo;s opening relatively recently on an NYC openings blog. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what exactly was the &amp;ldquo;Genesis House&amp;rdquo; or what &amp;ldquo;curated by Onjium&amp;rdquo; meant, but I figure post pandemic this was an excellent opportunity to make a reservation for something new to please my gourmand syndrome. The Genesis house is kind of interesting. The first floor is a showroom of Genesis vehicles where you can sit in the cars and talk to the different reps. The cars look nice, but this show room felt a little out of place for me. On the second floor is the library and restaurant, and on the lower level is an open meeting area. I learned that Onjium is a 1 Michelin Star out in Seoul. They curated the menu here with both modern and Korean techniques in iconic Korean recipes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Socarrat Paella Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/socarrat-paella-bar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 21:06:58 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/socarrat-paella-bar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this very special occasion, I had originally made a reservation for indoor dining at a Michelin restaurant. Unfortunately earlier this month, the governor and mayor disallowed indoor dining, so restaurants can only do outdoor dining for take out. This lovely night turned out to be around 31 degrees F (feels like 25F). They did set up heaters near each table, but it barely helps with the nasty wind chills. Despite this frigid day, let&amp;rsquo;s checkout the food we ordered.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hee Korean BBQ Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/hee-korean-bbq-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 16:06:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/hee-korean-bbq-grill/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Korean BBQ in NYC is often straight forward. If you want to eat it, you go to Koreatown for a safe bet. If you go away from Koreatown, you risk eating somewhere that may not satisfy that lust. Perhaps the meat would not be as good, or the side dishes would be awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately this place in Chelsea was actually pretty decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely want to preface that the ventilation in this restaurant is &lt;strong&gt;not good&lt;/strong&gt; despite the ducts over the grills, so your clothes will smell.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Death Ave</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:45:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a restaurant located close to the end of the Highline. It&amp;rsquo;s down on 10th ave at the corner. It&amp;rsquo;s actually next door to its bar. So if you want to visit this place, don&amp;rsquo;t open the first door on your left. Open the second door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/death-ave%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sour beer&lt;/strong&gt; on the top was quite good. It had some flavors of a Guinness but obviously with the sour in it. The &lt;strong&gt;sangria&lt;/strong&gt; cocktail at the bottom was alright. Not my choice, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kāwi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 17:15:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped by for lunch for David Chang&amp;rsquo;s newest Momofuku restaurant and is located in the mall across the street from The Vessel. It&amp;rsquo;s on the 5th floor near the Bouchon Bakery. Surprisingly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too filled, but then again it&amp;rsquo;s terribly hot and humid outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kawi%2F1_trading_card.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;trading card&lt;/strong&gt; cocktail consists of plantation pineapple, cruzan blackstrap, smith &amp;amp; cross rums, trader vic&amp;rsquo;s macadamia liqueur, curry, and yogurt. I did not like this at all as it was very sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The 18th Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-18th-room/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 01:32:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-18th-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cool speak easy spot right next to Bathtub Gin. Seems to be Cuban driven. It has a very jazzy speak easy feel to it. The theme of the menu is pretty cool. On Wednesdays, they have a live cuban band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bartenders can craft drinks based on what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. I think weekdays are probably the best to come here. The music on the speakers is good and isn&amp;rsquo;t loud, and you can actually hear people. You can also order snacks here as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Los Mariscos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-mariscos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 16:34:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-mariscos/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is located in the backside of Chelsea Market along 14th Street. Basically walk towards Tippler, and it&amp;rsquo;d be on your right side. Can&amp;rsquo;t really miss it. It seems to be a semi-throwback to Baja style fish tacos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/los-mariscos%2F1_tacos.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got &lt;strong&gt;shrimp ceviche&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2 fish tacos&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;1 spicy shrimp taco&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted the fish ceviche, but they were out for whatever reason. The &lt;strong&gt;shrimp ceviche&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty good, although I&amp;rsquo;m not too much of a fan of it being put on a big tostada shell. I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be more peruvian style but who would have thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kogane Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:15:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively new spot that has opened up in the last couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kogane-ramen%2F1_pork_buns.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pork buns&lt;/strong&gt; were surprisingly decent. I think they were a little expensive for each as is most Manhattan foods, but it was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kogane-ramen%2F2_lobster_ramen.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was interesting to me was &lt;strong&gt;lobster ramen&lt;/strong&gt;. It had miso flavored soup broth and of course lobster meat with shells. They gave a shell cracker on the side, and they definitely did not skimp on the meat. They gave chashu and lobster here. Even though I am pretty good at extracting lobster meat, I never realized how annoyed I&amp;rsquo;d be at doing it out of a soup. I think I prefer more of the Boiling Crab style if it came to that. The lobster meat definitely was a good value for the cost of this ramen soup (I think like ~18$?). However, next time, I&amp;rsquo;d probably not let my eyes dictate over my common sense. I think it was a good idea, but for me I felt the work to extract the meat was not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bonchon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bonchon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 17:33:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bonchon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty bad and expensive. 10 pieces of bites fro $14, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come with a drink.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CoBa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Their pho + banhmi combo $12.50 is OK for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chuck and Blade</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/chuck-and-blade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:00:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/chuck-and-blade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;New York strip was so so. Cream of spinach was not good. There were lots of tendons in the meat. The lava cake dessert was good though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Old Homestead</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:50:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first visit and not pictured, we got the aged rib eye for 2. It was surprisingly good and flavorful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/old-homestead%2F1_bacon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;applewood smoked slab of bacon&lt;/strong&gt; was thick and tasty. For 2 people, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to just get 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/old-homestead%2F2_prime_rib.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;prime rib&lt;/strong&gt; on the bone was super thick and good. Like Keen&amp;rsquo;s, this is a monster and can probably be shared by 2 people. I would say the thickness of this was probably close to 1.25 inches. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the whole thing comfortably. It came with cream of horseradish and chunky horseradish on the side. The cream of horseradish was delicious. The consistency was similar to sour cream but with that hint of horseradish in it. The steak itself was cooked a solid medium rare throughout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thai Sliders</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thai-sliders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:48:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/thai-sliders/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good tom yum noodle soup for lunch. Actually pretty good overall pad thai and pad see ew staples.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Riazor</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-riazor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:42:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-riazor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Spanish stuff. Cheap decent lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simply Hooked</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/simply-hooked/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:27:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/simply-hooked/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This used to be in the Lower East Side, but I guess they set up shop in this Gansevoort Market area. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good. I prefer the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery"&gt;A Salt &amp;amp; Battery&lt;/a&gt; place instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hot N Juicy Crawfish</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/hot-n-juicy-crawfish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:26:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/hot-n-juicy-crawfish/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Got the soft shell poboy. Was decent for lunch. $17 for fries, drink, and a poboy. The normal stuff is rather expensive. Probably a $2-3 per pound markup compared to LA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roccos Pizza Joint</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/roccos-pizza-joint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:09:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/roccos-pizza-joint/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Got the cheesesteak, and I regret it. This place is eh.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jun Men Ramen Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jun-men-ramen-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:23:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jun-men-ramen-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s similar to Shinsengumi. If in Chelsea and want ramen, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen"&gt;Oramen&lt;/a&gt; is way better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:22:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is pretty good for the area. I like the miso.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pizza Rollio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizza-rollio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:24:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizza-rollio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is just OK. Super gimmicky with the rolling pizza thing. Would rather have a slice than that. It&amp;rsquo;s like eating a super thin pizza that is malleable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Detroit Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/detroit-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:22:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/detroit-pizza/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The full name of this restaurant is &amp;ldquo;Lions and Tigers and Squares Detroit Pizza&amp;rdquo;. Obviously did not want that in the title of the post. Got the pepperoni and yellow peppers, and it was pretty good. Not too expensive&amp;hellip; ~$12-14&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Los Tacos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-tacos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:44:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/los-tacos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good for NYC. Still cannot compare to LA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Miznon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/miznon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:43:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/miznon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place sucks a lot, and it&amp;rsquo;s expensive. Food was just eh. I got the steak pita, and I was still very hungry. Overrated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dizengoff</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/dizengoff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:41:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/dizengoff/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place was surprisingly good. The shakshooka and bread was really good. Too bad it&amp;rsquo;s CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Coppelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/coppelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:29:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/coppelia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gourmet&amp;rdquo; lomo saltado is like paying $20 tacos. This is a ripoff and not worth the $20+. Good, but not great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mokbar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mokbar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:47:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mokbar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s right across from the Los Tacos place in Chelsea Market. Got the Korean ramen, and it was abysmal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momoya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/momoya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:33:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/momoya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just ok. Cheap sushi. Don&amp;rsquo;t trust people&amp;rsquo;s palettes when they say this place is good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Uma Temakeria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/uma-temakeria/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:06:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/uma-temakeria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Terrible &amp;ldquo;sushi burrito&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is CLOSED for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Go Go Curry</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/go-go-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:04:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/go-go-curry/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good lunch spot and fast. Cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lasagna Ristorante</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lasagna-ristorante/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:53:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lasagna-ristorante/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of food for lunch and just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dirty Bird to Go</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/dirty-bird-to-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:22:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/dirty-bird-to-go/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place sucks compared to KFC/Popeyes. Yeah I said it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Westville</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/westville/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:10:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/westville/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This fried chicken sandwich was a special served during lunch and was quite good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Westville&amp;rsquo;s normal menu seems bland and isn&amp;rsquo;t that great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Singe Vert</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-singe-vert/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:06:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-singe-vert/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good. Decent price. Don&amp;rsquo;t have much else to say I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shorty Tang</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shorty-tang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:34:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shorty-tang/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So so for lunch. Cash only. The sesame noodles was just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creamline</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/creamline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:05:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/creamline/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good. I like both the fried chicken and cheeseburger. Probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go here again if it&amp;rsquo;s out of my way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momofuku Nishi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/momofuku-nishi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:03:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/momofuku-nishi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is suppose to be Italian, but I ate here before they rebranded. They had the Impossible burger here, and it was surprisingly decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red sauce is really good with the fries.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Buns Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/buns-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:02:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/buns-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Greasy, but good and filling. I skip the sliders and went straight for the regular burger.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bareburger</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/bareburger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:00:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/bareburger/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent gourmet burger. I probably never crave this when I want a burger.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bathtub Gin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/bathtub-gin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 14:57:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/bathtub-gin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Went here with a friend for the first time. Saw a random bouncer looking guy standing outside of a coffee shop. There&amp;rsquo;s a door next to the coffee shop that leads into an apartment complex. My friend and I looked at each other. We were thinking we were suppose to open this door, and that this &amp;ldquo;speak easy&amp;rdquo; is somewhere in this apartment complex. We tried to open the door, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn at all. We stood there with a confused look in our faces as we check the address again. The random bouncer guy asked, &amp;ldquo;Are you guys looking for the bar?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Tippler</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-tippler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 14:57:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-tippler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cool place beneath Chelsea Market.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>