<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UWS on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/uws/</link><description>Recent content in UWS on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/uws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Leopard at Des Artistes</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 21:17:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</guid><description>We had a show to catch at the Lincoln Center, and the area had a lot of New American and Italian restaurants within half a mile. We&amp;rsquo;ve rarely explored anywhere north of 60th St. This area is just across the street on the lower west side of Central Park. The restaurant itself is located in a historic residential building called Hotel des Artistes. I was easily able to make a reservation the day before for a 5:15 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Miriam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/miriam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 21:34:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/miriam/</guid><description>After an early afternoon along the mid section of Central Park at the Natural History museum, I was looking for specifically Mediterranean restaurants within a half mile walk. As usual, we did not have reservations in mind, so we were hoping we could walk in. Sorting by the &amp;ldquo;hot and new&amp;rdquo; on Yelp, we decided on Miriam which seemed to be a second Israeli location for the owners. Fortunately, the restaurant was quite open around 4:45 PM, and we were able to walk in.</description></item><item><title>The Milling Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-milling-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 10:33:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-milling-room/</guid><description>We somehow won tickets to Shakespear in the Park, and we were debating whether we would scour for a restaurant in the west or east side. I was browsing on Yelp, and I saw this was very close to the Delacorte Theater. The interior pictures looked pretty amazing, and the food seemed pretty good although somewhat typical American. We ended up showing up promptly at opening and were seated right away without reservations.</description></item><item><title>Tap Nyc</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/tap-nyc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/tap-nyc/</guid><description>Summary This is a little quaint Brazilian breakfast-ish shop near 72nd Street close to Strawberry Fields. Their specialty is tapioca, açai, and pão (i.e. TAP). Many of their main products are gluten free, for those that really care about that. The Brazilian tapioca can be interpreted to be a crepe, but other than the shape, the texture isn&amp;rsquo;t really like a crepe at all.
The pão de queijo is basically cheese balls.</description></item><item><title>Jacobs Pickles</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jacobs-pickles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 21:08:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jacobs-pickles/</guid><description>Summary This is the main site to the sister site Maison Pickle.
The food here is really good, filling, and not too expensive.
Of course, you have to get the pickles. For appetizers, we got 4 pickles (spicy, green beans, green tomatoes, and regular). We also got a side of fried pickles. I liked them all to be honest, and would love to get the carrots next time.
Next, they had 3 different types of root beers on draft.</description></item><item><title>Jin Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:42:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</guid><description>This place was decent. Had to wait about 20 minutes. I think price wise it&amp;rsquo;s slightly cheaper than East Village stuff.</description></item><item><title>Maison Pickle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/maison-pickle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:59:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/maison-pickle/</guid><description>French Dip is really good here, espeically the au jus drippings.</description></item></channel></rss>