<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beverly Grove on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/beverly-grove/</link><description>Recent content in Beverly Grove on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/beverly-grove/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hart and the Hunter</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/the-hart-and-the-hunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 22:31:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/the-hart-and-the-hunter/</guid><description>At a whim, it was the end of the day, and I completely forgot to pick a place to go for this week. I saw this was on my list, and I figured why not? Mind as well try it. I sure didn&amp;rsquo;t regret this decision. The Hart and The Hunter is a pretty interesting place.
This is #14 of 52 on my 2014 LA food expedition.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.</description></item><item><title>Ink (#2)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-2/</guid><description>Earlier this week, I reviewed the Ink tasting menu that appeared approximately 2 months after open. Today I went to Ink again to sample his food again. I will be blunt and say tonight was by far the BEST LA expensive food that I&amp;rsquo;ve had. Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to what was on the menu.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. On this night, Michael Voltaggio was helming the meat station, so my friend and I were in awe that he touched our beef course.</description></item><item><title>Ink</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 22:55:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-1/</guid><description>In preparation for my second visit to Ink, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my ass to review and post my original Ink experience. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know already, this is Michael Voltaggio&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that he opened up here in West Hollywood. It&amp;rsquo;s his take on modern LA cuisine. I was looking forward to try some of his creations, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what it&amp;rsquo;s all about.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.</description></item><item><title>Son of a Gun</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:39:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</guid><description>This was a special night where Top Chef Marcus Samuelsson creates a culinary experience with the dynamic duo of Son Of A Gun. The menu was nothing like their normal menu. Marcus Samuelsson greeted most, if not all, of the guests during my visit. You can tell he was very appreciative for us patrons to experience this. Not only did he prepare food for us, but he also presented a signed copy of his memoir book &amp;ldquo;Yes Chef&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>SAAM at The Bazaar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bazaar-saam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 21:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bazaar-saam/</guid><description>The SAAM at Bazaar by Jose Andres is well known for its take on molecular gastronomy. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the SLS Hotel off of La Cienega near West Hollywood. It&amp;rsquo;s filled with your typical pretentious and superficial Hollywood crowds. If you can get past that, there are 2 restaurants here of note: the regular restaurant where you can order tapas and the SAAM restaurant where it&amp;rsquo;s a 22 course prix fix taster.</description></item></channel></rss>