<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beverly Grove on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/beverly-grove/</link><description>Recent content in Beverly Grove on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 22:31:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/beverly-grove/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hart and the Hunter</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/the-hart-and-the-hunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 22:31:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/the-hart-and-the-hunter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-hart-and-the-hunter%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a whim, it was the end of the day, and I completely forgot to pick a place to go for this week. I saw this was on my list, and I figured why not? Mind as well try it. I sure didn&amp;rsquo;t regret this decision. The Hart and The Hunter is a pretty interesting place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is #14 of 52 on my 2014 LA food expedition.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ink (#2)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ink-2%2F0_voltaggio.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I reviewed the Ink tasting menu that appeared approximately 2 months after open. Today I went to Ink again to sample his food again. I will be blunt and say tonight was by far the BEST LA expensive food that I&amp;rsquo;ve had. Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to what was on the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. On this night, Michael Voltaggio was helming the meat station, so my friend and I were in awe that he touched our beef course. I vividly remember that the course was sublime, and if this was the future of the LA food scene, I was super excited to see this restaurant&amp;rsquo;s future and contribution. Unfortunately and understandably, this restaurant closed in 2017 because he had outgrew it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ink</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 22:55:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ink-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ink-1%2F0_michael_voltaggio.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparation for my second visit to Ink, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my ass to review and post my original Ink experience. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know already, this is Michael Voltaggio&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that he opened up here in West Hollywood. It&amp;rsquo;s his take on modern LA cuisine. I was looking forward to try some of his creations, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what it&amp;rsquo;s all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. I recall molecular gastronomy being a very hot thing at this time, and after watching the Voltaggio brothers compete on Top Chef, I was super excited to try out this restaurant. On this night, I remember seeing him directing traffic in his kitchen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Son of a Gun</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:39:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/son-of-a-gun%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a special night where Top Chef Marcus Samuelsson creates a culinary experience with the dynamic duo of Son Of A Gun. The menu was nothing like their normal menu. Marcus Samuelsson greeted most, if not all, of the guests during my visit. You can tell he was very appreciative for us patrons to experience this. Not only did he prepare food for us, but he also presented a signed copy of his memoir book &amp;ldquo;Yes Chef&amp;rdquo;. I read the first chapter before I decided to write this. The book seems to document his journey through life and show how passionate he is with the culinary arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SAAM at The Bazaar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bazaar-saam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 21:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bazaar-saam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bazaar-saam%2F0_bazaar_sls_hotel.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SAAM at Bazaar by Jose Andres is well known for its take on molecular gastronomy. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the SLS Hotel off of La Cienega near West Hollywood. It&amp;rsquo;s filled with your typical pretentious and superficial Hollywood crowds. If you can get past that, there are 2 restaurants here of note: the regular restaurant where you can order tapas and the SAAM restaurant where it&amp;rsquo;s a 22 course prix fix taster. Since I&amp;rsquo;m more than likely to not go to the same high end restaurant again, I decided to go big.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>