<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kaiseki on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/kaiseki/</link><description>Recent content in Kaiseki on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:06:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/kaiseki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yamakase #2</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:06:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yamakase-2%2F0_chef.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning to go to this. I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t. However due to some ridiculous circumstances, I was asked to go, and I had to go. It&amp;rsquo;s been barely 2 months, and I went back to my favorite LA restaurant. One would expect and hope for the same experience considering how recent their first trip here was. So really, how was it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt;. For comparison, you can also read &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-1/"&gt;my 2 month old review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yamakase</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 15:11:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yamakase-1%2F0_chef.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hole-in-the-wall place that is a real hidden gem in the Palms neighborhood of LA. It&amp;rsquo;s Japanese cuisine served kaiseki style. There are only 10 seats per night as the meal lasts just about 5 hours. There is no sign on the front. There is simply the address. We got there at 6:50 PM, but the door was locked. It actually does not open till 7 PM on the dot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>N/Naka</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/n-naka/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 21:49:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/n-naka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a borderline 2 month anniversary of my abysmal attempts at eating a LA restaurant every week, I decided to try out this place called N/Naka in Palms. The owner of this kaiseki-style restaurant, Chef Niki Nakayama, is very meticulous with the menu and presentation in her dishes. Reviewers like to compare this place to Urusawa (a very high end Japanese restaurant which is on my list before the end of the year), and they also often say the food is by far the BEST Japanese restaurant in Los Angeles. Like some of my past experiences, Fox W, a well known Foodspotter, provided pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>