<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>anc on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/anc/</link><description>Recent content in anc on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 13:50:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/anc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Double Musky Inn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/double-musky-inn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 13:50:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/double-musky-inn/</guid><description>Summary On our last night before heading back, we stumbled onto this cajun place. For the price per quantity, this was unmatched.
The fried crawfish was delicious, albeit small. I was really digging the cocktail sauce with french fries though. That might be my new ketchup substitute now.
The fried crab cakes were delicious as well. You could definitely taste more of that crab taste, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly drowned by the sauce in it.</description></item><item><title>Turnagain Arm Pit BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/turnagain-arm-pit-bbq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 13:50:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/turnagain-arm-pit-bbq/</guid><description>Summary This is a semi-random shack off the highway about 10+ miles away from Girdwood.
The fried chicharron and fried okra was really good.
The fried ribs was had a slight crust to it with a strong glaze. I thought this was just OK.
The main dish was one of those platters that had St Louis ribs, chicken thighs, and sausage. You know something is up when the coleslaw was more memorable.</description></item><item><title>Jack Sprat</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/jack-sprat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:50:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/jack-sprat/</guid><description>Summary We&amp;rsquo;re boarding in Girdwood, and at night we&amp;rsquo;re looking for a good restaurant to try out.
Surprisingy, Girdwood has some pretty decent finds here.
The fried sweet potatoes was nice. I prefer this over thin cut sweet potato fries because you can get more fullness out of this. It was served with some jalapeno-ish creamy sauce that wasn&amp;rsquo;t spicy. I would&amp;rsquo;ve preferred it having more of a kick.
The pork tenderloin special was really good.</description></item><item><title>Simon and Seaford Saloon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/simon-and-seaford-saloon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 13:50:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/anc/simon-and-seaford-saloon/</guid><description>Summary In Anchorage, there is this spot that for some reason got a lot of good Yelp reviews. Usually when you venture outside of the major cities in the U.S., you have lower expectations on the taste of food. Of course in Alaska, we&amp;rsquo;d expect high quality seafood.
The cioppino was delicious. The bowl that it came in was huge, and the clams/fish/shrimp were all pretty tasty.
The clam chowder was also good too.</description></item></channel></rss>