<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>American on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/cuisine/american/</link><description>Recent content in American on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/cuisine/american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hollywood Brown Derby</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/hollywood-brown-derby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 22:14:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/hollywood-brown-derby/</guid><description>Summary This is located in the central area of the Hollywood Studios theme park. Having dine in similar restaurants in Los Angeles, this definitely does bring back vibes from there. The restaurant decor has a ton of celebrity facial caricatures hanging on walls with an old 1910s to 1950s like decor. They placed us in our own booth, so they took care of social distancing. This restaurant is definitely not as upscale as some of the other restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to, but it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be regarded as the one to go to in this park.</description></item><item><title>Regal Eagle Smokehouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/regal-eagle-smokehouse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 23:04:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/regal-eagle-smokehouse/</guid><description>Summary For dinner, we stopped by the American pavilion. This BBQ restaurant only took orders via mobile. After you placed your mobile order, they will text you when it&amp;rsquo;s time to pick up your food. Outside there are a bunch of tables, but you can also sit indoors too. Like other COVID menus, the choices were not as abundant. People have shared menus that you can order 3 meats, but the mobile menu only had single meat combos.</description></item><item><title>Beaches &amp; Cream</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/beaches-and-cream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 18:29:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/beaches-and-cream/</guid><description>Summary Nestled between the Yacht Club and Beach Club resort is this laid back restaurant that has American burger and dessert vibes to it. Note that you must make a reservation for this which was pretty annoying, but the food looked pretty good for an on-campus restaurant. We had just done a full day at Epcot and decided to finish the day with a nice dessert helping. The restaurant is very lively with a ton of kids.</description></item></channel></rss>