<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gastropub on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/gastropub/</link><description>Recent content in Gastropub on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 14:28:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/gastropub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Woodbines</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:58:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Woodbines is another craft beer and bar restaurant on Vernon Blvd in Long Island City that has fish and chips on the menu which my partner as craving for. At 5:00 PM, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people, and it was easy to get a seat inside the restaurant. Keep in mind, they do follow COVID protocols, so they asked us to check our temperature against the wall. They definitely have an outdoor setup, and that seemed to be more popular with the guests as the night went on. There are some other affliate locations in the city such as Kent&amp;rsquo;s Ale House in North Williamsburg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M.Wells</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is across the street from Food Cellar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in a garage and used to serve a lot of steak dishes. The menu has changed into a more casual patio like experience (I am guessing just for the summer). When we arrived, there was no table service. Instead you have to go to the counter and place your order there. The menus are shown via QRCode. After you place your order, you carry the utensils, dishes, and drinks back to your table. The waiter will serve the dishes, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go pick up that. When you order, you (can) leave with them your credit card to open a tab. When you check out, they will tell you that gratuity is already included.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Minetta Tavern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:07:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/minetta-tavern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the infamous Minetta Tavern. I had been here back in mid 2010s, and it was pretty good. Before I met my partner, I used to come here once every few months to just scarf their Black Label burger. The price for this was just barely over $20. Now in recent times post-pandemic, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit more difficult to walk in without reservations. We were able to sit at the bar on a Friday late-afternoon around 4:55 PM without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>