<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ontario on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/neighborhood/ontario/</link><description>Recent content in Ontario on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 19:44:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/neighborhood/ontario/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skylon Tower Revolving Dining Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 19:44:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room%2F0_tower.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Niagara Canadian side, there is a lot more tourist attractions, views, and restaurants. My partner really wanted to check this revolving dining room out, so I made a reservation for 2 for 4:30 PM a few days in advance fairly easy. When you arrive into the bottom floor, the bottom floor of the tower has a seemingly outdated game mall with super old games. It felt like a blast in the past. Then you take the escalators up to the elevators that bring you up to this revolving tower. The elevator went up to the dining room floor pretty quickly, and you get a nice view of Niagara Falls.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Restaurant Pearl Morissette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/restaurant-pearl-morissette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:32:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/restaurant-pearl-morissette/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/restaurant-pearl-morissette%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restaurant Pearl Morissette is located near the Niagara region of Canada in an area called &amp;ldquo;Jordan Station&amp;rdquo; neighborhood of Lincoln, Ontario. My partner and I visited Niagara Falls recently, and wanted to make a trip out to this restaurant from the U.S. side of Niagara. The drive into this area was very easy. Because we foolishly decided to eat at this restaurant rather late, we initially did not find any availability. However we checked again a few days before our trip, and we were able to book a table for 2 for 8:30 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Alfonso 1890</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/don-alfonso-1890/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:59:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/don-alfonso-1890/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/don-alfonso-1890%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the primary reason for us to come to Toronto. My partner saw this restaurant somewhere, and has been yearning for this for a few years. Don Alfonso 1890 is located near the top of the Westin hotel that lies next to the water. We have not been to a Michelin Star Italian based restaurant, so this was something for us to be excited about. In addition, Canada has a &amp;ldquo;100 best&amp;rdquo; restaurant list, and in 2023, they &lt;a href="https://canadas100best.com/don-alfonso-1890-2023"&gt;rated this restaurant 35 out of 100&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Harbour 60</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/harbour-60/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 15:35:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/harbour-60/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/harbour-60%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We planned to stay in Toronto for only 3 nights. On night 2, we decided to try this restaurant since it also had baked alaskas which are my favorite dessert. As mentioned previously, Toronto was a fairly dead city on December 25 and 26. We wanted to make reservations at Michelin Star restaurants, but they either were unavailable or they canceled my reservation because they wanted to give staff a break for the holidays. I made a reservation about a month in advance, and fortunately, they were open.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Louix Louis</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/louix-louis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 15:50:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/louix-louis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/louix-louis%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this 2023 Christmas to New Years holiday week, we spent time in downtown Toronto for the very first time. The unfortunate reality that we faced was that Toronto did not have a lot of restaurants opened on Christmas that weren&amp;rsquo;t original Chinese. So we were stuck with 3 options, and we chose this because of the dessert option. This was a special Christmas dinner at $175 CAD ($132 USD today) per guest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>