<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ramen on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/ramen/</link><description>Recent content in Ramen on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/ramen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Tsukemen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</guid><description>What is tsukemen (つけ麺; pronounced &amp;ldquo;skee-men&amp;rdquo;)? It&amp;rsquo;s basically thick udon served cold with a side of a thick soup/broth for dipping. In Los Angeles, I frequented a place in Sawtelle near the Westside called &amp;ldquo;Tsujita&amp;rdquo; that also specialized in something similar. Okiboru recently opened in Manhattan, and it&amp;rsquo;s famed for being on Michelin&amp;rsquo;s Bib Gourmand list in Atlanta. They do not take reservations, so when we arrived at this location at 5:15 PM on a Friday, the line outside was about 10 parties ranging from 2 to 6 people per group.</description></item><item><title>Kyuramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:37:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</guid><description>The Kyuramen restaurant chain has been slowly making its way throughout the greater NYC area. They just opened a location out in Long Island City which is not too far from where we live. This restaurant had construction signs early in the pandemic and just never opened until now. We thought we would be able to get seated right away on an early Sunday afternoon, but they checked us into Yelp and we had to wait around for about 15 minutes for a table of 2.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Yama Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yama-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:09:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yama-ramen/</guid><description>This ramen place is pretty close to where I work. It&amp;rsquo;s located on 48th and 6th ave and is very close to Rockafeller. There is no way you would know of this restaurant unless you were either intentionally looking for it, or if you saw the ground floor sign that indicated this was upstairs. I had some time during my lunch, and decided to take a quick spin to see how this was compared to other ramen spots.</description></item><item><title>Takumen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</guid><description>Summary I was supposed to meet my partner the next block at Casa Enrique, but for some reason they mistook a Japanese restaurant for a Mexican restaurant and ended up here. They found it weird that there were no lines, whereas I went to Casa Enrique and encountered a line. Because Casa Enrique doesn&amp;rsquo;t take walk-ins and the line was getting rather long, we decided to just eat here, and to my surprise, it was a good substitute.</description></item><item><title>Mazete</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:50:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</guid><description>Summary Typically when we walk north on 6th ave towards Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s for groceries, we stop by Cava across the street for a snack. We saw this seemingly new interesting restaurant opened with no one in it. The space is very bright, modern, and definitely has a Japanese cafe-chic vibe to it. This dry &amp;ldquo;ramen&amp;rdquo; place just opened along 6th Avenue between 20th and 21st Street.
This is another one of those &amp;ldquo;pick X of this and Y of that&amp;rdquo; type of restaurant except the theme here is Japanese.</description></item><item><title>Ichiba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 13:08:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</guid><description>Summary This ramen place is near NYU and Union Station, so it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible.
The spicy miso ramen comes with ox bones and marrow broth, spicy miso garlic base, bean sprouts, roasted corn, toasted nori, naruto fishcake, soy braised beef, scallions, and thick wavy noodle. THe broth is super rich, far beyond what I was expecting. It&amp;rsquo;s not spicy per se, but the soup doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down super smooth for me.</description></item><item><title>Tonchin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</guid><description>Summary This place has a pretty decent ambiance.
The yuzu margarita was surprisingly pretty good. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had yuzu before and like citrus, I recommend you get this if it&amp;rsquo;s available. I just checked their website&amp;rsquo;s drink menu, and it&amp;rsquo;s not on there. This drink wasn&amp;rsquo;t strong at all, and had a really really good before and after taste. I would drink this over any regular margarita any day.</description></item><item><title>Ivan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</guid><description>Summary I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this ramen spot other than it was on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, and how it really touched a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s hearts. So my review will be almost based solely on the food itself.
The pork musubi bites were surprisingly good. Each bite is packed full of flavor, although I am rather doubtful that it&amp;rsquo;s worth $5 a piece.
The Japanese fried chicken were an interesting spin on karaage.</description></item><item><title>Kogane Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:15:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</guid><description>Summary This is a relatively new spot that has opened up in the last couple months.
The pork buns were surprisingly decent. I think they were a little expensive for each as is most Manhattan foods, but it was good.
What was interesting to me was lobster ramen. It had miso flavored soup broth and of course lobster meat with shells. They gave a shell cracker on the side, and they definitely did not skimp on the meat.</description></item><item><title>Mu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</guid><description>Summary Where to start with this. I loathe cash only places considering the price of this is not exactly cheap.
The U &amp;amp; I bowl was really good but not for +$20. The bowl was rather small although the ingredients were pretty fresh.
The flying pig bowl was the biggest disappointment I&amp;rsquo;ve had. The broth was just OK. It&amp;rsquo;s subtly different than the normal tonkatsu style broth. I also opted for an ounce of the jamon iberico.</description></item><item><title>Tamashii Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 22:15:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</guid><description>Decent ramen noodles. Soup was a little salty. The egg was disappointing.</description></item><item><title>Menkoi Sato</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:49:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</guid><description>This is the old Mew Men place. Pretty good ramen. The spicy is actually spicy, and the broth is super flavorful. The only caveat is there is not a lot of stuff that comes with the soup. Just a few veggies, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. They should have some sort of combo or something.</description></item><item><title>Shinshi Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:47:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</guid><description>Pretty good tsukemen. Get the spicy miso. Tsukemen seems fairly rare in NYC. Still looking for something similar to LA Tsujita.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Shack</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:46:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</guid><description>Decent ramen. Got some super fancy ramen, and it was fat. Not the best though and it&amp;rsquo;s in a not so great neighborhood.</description></item><item><title>Wanpaku</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/wanpaku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/wanpaku/</guid><description>Decent ramen in the Greenpoint area.</description></item><item><title>EAK Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:44:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</guid><description>EAK Ramen is located on 6th Ave close to 14th. I used to venture here all the time pre-pandemic, and there was always a line or people. I was curious to see how the restaurant was like since. Back in September 2018, I thought it was one of the better ramen places, but now, EAK also has a ton more competition all over the city. We were able to walk in on a Sunday early afternoon around 4 PM.</description></item><item><title>Jin Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:42:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</guid><description>This place was decent. Had to wait about 20 minutes. I think price wise it&amp;rsquo;s slightly cheaper than East Village stuff.</description></item><item><title>Niu Noodle House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:41:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</guid><description>Beef noodle ramen was not as good as Taiwanese beef noodle. Passssss.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:40:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</guid><description>For whatever reason, there are 2 locations within neighboring vicinity of each other in the West Village. The ramen is similar to Shinsengumi. Slightly disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Totto Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/totto-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:38:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/totto-ramen/</guid><description>I think this is still one of my top favorite ramen places in NYC. It&amp;rsquo;s cash only.</description></item><item><title>Mentoku Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mentoku-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mentoku-ramen/</guid><description>It seems I only wrote &amp;ldquo;pretty good&amp;rdquo; on my spreadsheet, and right now I am drawing a blank about this place.</description></item><item><title>Momosan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:32:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s ok. Broth is not great, but tuna bowl is good. I think this restaurant is owned by Morimoto.</description></item><item><title>Kuu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kuu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:31:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kuu-ramen/</guid><description>Not good at all. Was near WTC.</description></item></channel></rss>