<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ramen on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/ramen/</link><description>Recent content in Ramen on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 22:57:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/ramen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yasubee</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yasubee/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 22:57:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yasubee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yasubee%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a free night on the way back from work, I stopped by this semi-new tsukemen place. For the uninitiated, Japanese tsukemen is basically ramen, except the soup is served on the side, and the noodles are thick by default. Yasubee is actually a restaurant chain with over 80 locations in Japan. They opened a NY location in Flushing, and this Chelsea location is the second one. I walked in on a Wednesday at 6 PM, and the restaurant barely had anyone in. Yasubee is part of the &amp;ldquo;Kung Fu Tea&amp;rdquo; family, which includes TKK Fried Chicken and Kung Fu Tea products.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TabeTomo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:18:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tabetomo%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a few years ago before the pandemic, TabeTomo was a very new tsukemen centric restaurant, and it was always on my try list. However, I never was able to make it to the restaurant due to how sparse tsukemen was in general in Manhattan, as well as, the restaurant was closed at random times when I tried to visit. Finally tonight, I got a chance to try this out and to compare against other tsukemen places.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kajiken%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything. I was able to walk in about 30 minutes before closing time and was seated without issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Tsukemen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen%2F0_store_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is tsukemen (つけ麺; pronounced &amp;ldquo;skee-men&amp;rdquo;)? It&amp;rsquo;s basically thick udon served cold with a side of a thick soup/broth for dipping. In Los Angeles, I frequented a place in Sawtelle near the Westside called &amp;ldquo;Tsujita&amp;rdquo; that also specialized in something similar. Okiboru recently opened in Manhattan, and it&amp;rsquo;s famed for being on Michelin&amp;rsquo;s Bib Gourmand list in Atlanta. They do not take reservations, so when we arrived at this location at 5:15 PM on a Friday, the line outside was about 10 parties ranging from 2 to 6 people per group. It took us about 30-45 minutes of wait before we were seated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kyuramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:37:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kyuramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Kyuramen restaurant chain has been slowly making its way throughout the greater NYC area. They just opened a location out in Long Island City which is not too far from where we live. This restaurant had construction signs early in the pandemic and just never opened until now. We thought we would be able to get seated right away on an early Sunday afternoon, but they checked us into Yelp and we had to wait around for about 15 minutes for a table of 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ramen-spot%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yama Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yama-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:09:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yama-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This ramen place is pretty close to where I work. It&amp;rsquo;s located on 48th and 6th ave and is very close to Rockafeller. There is no way you would know of this restaurant unless you were either intentionally looking for it, or if you saw the ground floor sign that indicated this was upstairs. I had some time during my lunch, and decided to take a quick spin to see how this was compared to other ramen spots.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Takumen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/takumen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to meet my partner the next block at Casa Enrique, but for some reason they mistook a Japanese restaurant for a Mexican restaurant and ended up here. They found it weird that there were no lines, whereas I went to Casa Enrique and encountered a line. Because Casa Enrique doesn&amp;rsquo;t take walk-ins and the line was getting rather long, we decided to just eat here, and to my surprise, it was a good substitute.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mazete</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:50:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically when we walk north on 6th ave towards Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s for groceries, we stop by Cava across the street for a snack. We saw this seemingly new interesting restaurant opened with no one in it. The space is very bright, modern, and definitely has a Japanese cafe-chic vibe to it. This dry &amp;ldquo;ramen&amp;rdquo; place just opened along 6th Avenue between 20th and 21st Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another one of those &amp;ldquo;pick X of this and Y of that&amp;rdquo; type of restaurant except the theme here is Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 13:08:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ramen place is near NYU and Union Station, so it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ichiba%2F1_spicy_miso_ramen.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spicy miso&lt;/strong&gt; ramen comes with ox bones and marrow broth, spicy miso garlic base, bean sprouts, roasted corn, toasted nori, naruto fishcake, soy braised beef, scallions, and thick wavy noodle. THe broth is super rich, far beyond what I was expecting. It&amp;rsquo;s not spicy per se, but the soup doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down super smooth for me. At the end, the spicy pepper would always surprise for some reason. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s attributed to the oil and thickness of the broth, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. Regardless, I thought the ramen was acceptable, but there are better ones in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tonchin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place has a pretty decent ambiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tonchin%2F1_yuzu_margarita.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yuzu margarita&lt;/strong&gt; was surprisingly pretty good. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had yuzu before and like citrus, I recommend you get this if it&amp;rsquo;s available. I just checked their website&amp;rsquo;s drink menu, and it&amp;rsquo;s not on there. This drink wasn&amp;rsquo;t strong at all, and had a really really good before and after taste. I would drink this over any regular margarita any day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ivan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this ramen spot other than it was on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, and how it really touched a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s hearts. So my review will be almost based solely on the food itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ivan-ramen%2F1_pork_musubi_bies.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pork musubi bites&lt;/strong&gt; were surprisingly good. Each bite is packed full of flavor, although I am rather doubtful that it&amp;rsquo;s worth $5 a piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ivan-ramen%2F2_japanese_fried_chicken.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Japanese fried chicken&lt;/strong&gt; were an interesting spin on karaage. The crust was nicely crisp, and the sauce was very tangy. There was a little kick to it too. They served this with a sauce on the side that I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember how it tasted like. I do remember that my first thought was that this was oversauced similar to how PF Chang&amp;rsquo;s would do orange chicken, but nonetheless it was decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kogane Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:15:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kogane-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively new spot that has opened up in the last couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kogane-ramen%2F1_pork_buns.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pork buns&lt;/strong&gt; were surprisingly decent. I think they were a little expensive for each as is most Manhattan foods, but it was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kogane-ramen%2F2_lobster_ramen.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was interesting to me was &lt;strong&gt;lobster ramen&lt;/strong&gt;. It had miso flavored soup broth and of course lobster meat with shells. They gave a shell cracker on the side, and they definitely did not skimp on the meat. They gave chashu and lobster here. Even though I am pretty good at extracting lobster meat, I never realized how annoyed I&amp;rsquo;d be at doing it out of a soup. I think I prefer more of the Boiling Crab style if it came to that. The lobster meat definitely was a good value for the cost of this ramen soup (I think like ~18$?). However, next time, I&amp;rsquo;d probably not let my eyes dictate over my common sense. I think it was a good idea, but for me I felt the work to extract the meat was not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to start with this. I loathe cash only places considering the price of this is not exactly cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F1_u_&amp;amp;_i.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;U &amp;amp; I&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was really good but not for +$20. The bowl was rather small although the ingredients were pretty fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F2_the_flying_pig.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;flying pig&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was the biggest disappointment I&amp;rsquo;ve had. The broth was just OK. It&amp;rsquo;s subtly different than the normal tonkatsu style broth. I also opted for an ounce of the jamon iberico. I added an additional onsen tamago, which is basically a sous vide egg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tamashii Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 22:15:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tamashii-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent ramen noodles. Soup was a little salty. The egg was disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Menkoi Sato</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:49:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the old &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/mew-men"&gt;Mew Men&lt;/a&gt; place. Pretty good ramen. The spicy is actually spicy, and the broth is super flavorful. The only caveat is there is not a lot of stuff that comes with the soup. Just a few veggies, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. They should have some sort of combo or something.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shinshi Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:47:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good tsukemen. Get the spicy miso. Tsukemen seems fairly rare in NYC. Still looking for something similar to LA Tsujita.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Shack</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:46:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-shack/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent ramen. Got some super fancy ramen, and it was fat. Not the best though and it&amp;rsquo;s in a not so great neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wanpaku</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/wanpaku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/wanpaku/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent ramen in the Greenpoint area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>EAK Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:44:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/eak-ramen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EAK Ramen is located on 6th Ave close to 14th. I used to venture here all the time pre-pandemic, and there was always a line or people. I was curious to see how the restaurant was like since. Back in September 2018, I thought it was one of the better ramen places, but now, EAK also has a ton more competition all over the city. We were able to walk in on a Sunday early afternoon around 4 PM. We were the only diners, so we thought it was cool that we can eat at non-prime times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jin Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:42:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jin-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place was decent. Had to wait about 20 minutes. I think price wise it&amp;rsquo;s slightly cheaper than East Village stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Niu Noodle House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:41:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Beef noodle ramen was not as good as Taiwanese beef noodle. Passssss.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:40:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, there are 2 locations within neighboring vicinity of each other in the West Village. The ramen is similar to Shinsengumi. Slightly disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Totto Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/totto-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:38:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/totto-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I think this is still one of my top favorite ramen places in NYC. It&amp;rsquo;s cash only.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mentoku Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mentoku-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mentoku-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It seems I only wrote &amp;ldquo;pretty good&amp;rdquo; on my spreadsheet, and right now I am drawing a blank about this place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momosan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:32:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ok. Broth is not great, but tuna bowl is good. I think this restaurant is owned by Morimoto.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kuu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kuu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:31:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kuu-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not good at all. Was near WTC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ippudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ippudo%2F0_napkin.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had visited Ippudo twice before this time throughout my whole life, once in London and once in the East Village. This original post just had a comment of &amp;ldquo;Overrated and pricey. I&amp;rsquo;d skip here any day of the week. Daikokuya in LA is way better&amp;rdquo;. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pics of my dinner nearly 4 years ago, I thought about revisiting this Midtown location to try to remember why I was underwhelmed. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I now remember why, and it makes perfect sense why I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for it before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zundo Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/zundo-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:27:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/zundo-ya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Misoya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-misoya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:26:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-misoya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recommended by Totto Ramen server for best thick noodle in NYC. Soup was bad and salty. But yeah the noodle was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jun Men Ramen Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jun-men-ramen-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:23:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/jun-men-ramen-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s similar to Shinsengumi. If in Chelsea and want ramen, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen"&gt;Oramen&lt;/a&gt; is way better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:22:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/oramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is pretty good for the area. I like the miso.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yuji Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yuji-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:20:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yuji-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ramen omakase. Really good. Everything is homemade. $130 per person.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ryujin Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ryujin-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:19:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ryujin-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just ok. I&amp;rsquo;d go to other ramen places over this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiran</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:18:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an updated review for the Midtown / Times Square (Theater District) location for Ichiran. I had been to the original Bushwick location years ago, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pictures nor remembered much about it. The only thing I wrote down was &lt;code&gt;it was a much better version of Shinsengumi&lt;/code&gt;. Shinsengumi was a popular Torrance (California) restaurant that served hakata style ramen. They also allowed you to select your flavor profiles, and it was far less busy than Ichiran.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tsurutontan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:29:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsurutontan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Tsurutontan a few times already in various locations including Union Square and Midtown next to Rockafeller Center. When this Japan udon chain first opened in Manhattan a few years ago, there was a massive line because it was the first international location in the USA. The food was outstanding back then, and now it&amp;rsquo;s gone down a little in quality but still pretty good. This restaurant is known for having mammoth sized udon bowls which will most definitely satiate your appetite. They also have a variety of other Japanese sushi-esque dishes as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momofuku Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momofuku-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 18:29:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momofuku-noodle-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/momofuku-noodle-bar%2F0_david_chang.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/"&gt;Ippudo&lt;/a&gt;, this was supposedly another must-try ramen place that was highly raved by the NYC food scene. I got to this spot right when they opened, and there was already a small line outside in this frigid cold weather. Inside, they have counter top seating for 1-2 people as well as a some picnic table setups for larger parties. There was no David Chang spotted here, but how was the food?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>