<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nomad on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/nomad/</link><description>Recent content in Nomad on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/nomad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Olle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 20:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</guid><description>If you visit sample sales frequently, there are 2 nearby the Nomad and Koreatown area. Because the sample sales close at 7 PM sharp, it compels you to look for food during core dinner hours. Fortunately if you go shop right after work and finish around 6 PM on weekdays, foot traffic to restaurants won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Olle is a Korean restaurant about a block away from the sample sale store on 5th Ave.</description></item><item><title>Okdongsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:37:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</guid><description>This restaurant is from a renowned Korean chef (Ok Dongsik) and is a 6 time Michelin Seoul Bib Gourmand restaurant. We were nearby at a popular sample sale, and this was on my list for a while to checkout. The menu is very small and is straight forward. We were able to walk in at around 6:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without reservation. They turn over seats fairly quickly even though there can easily be a line of people waiting.</description></item><item><title>Nubeluz</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 21:47:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</guid><description>Nubeluz is a bar from Chef José Andrés located on the 50th floor of The Ritz-Carlton in Nomad with the intent to show visitors the NYC skyline. He has another recently opened restaurant, Zaytinya, on the first floor of this hotel. We were able to make reservations for 4:00 PM on a Sunday a few weeks in advanced. When you walk into the hotel, check in with the concierge who will swipe you up to the floor.</description></item></channel></rss>