<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>South Street Seaport on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-street-seaport/</link><description>Recent content in South Street Seaport on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 14:58:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/south-street-seaport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fulton-fish-co%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/carne-mare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Fulton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is one of Jean Georges&amp;rsquo; new seafood-centric restaurant situated right at the corner of the Pier near South Street Seaport. This area has a tiny Boston like mall where people can shop and eat at some decent restaurants. The iPic theater is also here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is largely going through some sort of construction. The restaurant is located at the edge of the pier and overlooks the water facing towards the Brooklyn Bridge. In fact, just about everywhere in the restaurant you can see the Brooklyn Bridge without much obstruction. If you do try to make a reservation, I definitely think the second floor seating is more beautiful than the first.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>