<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dim Sum on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/dim-sum/</link><description>Recent content in Dim Sum on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/dim-sum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Din Soup Dumplings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:48:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</guid><description>We had some tickets to attend one of those Fever &amp;ldquo;Candlelight&amp;rdquo; concert events that was located at a church right next to the &amp;ldquo;Court St&amp;rdquo; R-stop in Brooklyn. There was not too many options in terms of food within close vicinity. I looked at the prices for this soup dumpling place, and to my surprise, Din Soup Dumplings seemed not bad. My partner was also in a dumpling mood, so it was convenient to go check this place out.</description></item><item><title>Knock Knock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/</guid><description>Knock Knock is a nearby neighborhood cafe that has a mix of Cantonese-style dishes. The decor and the style of the food reminds me a bit of the San Gabriel Valley in Southern California, where there are a lot of small cafe shops opening serving quick eats. My cousin had visited this a few weeks ago for breakfast, and they said they were pleasantly surprised at the coffee. That was a catalyst for us to check this place out to see how its actual food was.</description></item><item><title>Tim Ho Wan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:46:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</guid><description>Summary A friend was in town, and I saw that Tim Ho was near their hotel. This place was always on my list to try given that it had received Michelin recognition at its Hong Kong location. Given I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten at numerous dim sum places already, they tout themselves as the dim sum specialists, so I already have high expectations.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the drink on the left, but the right was some type of mango cococnut slush.</description></item><item><title>Dim Sum Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 15:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</guid><description>Summary It&amp;rsquo;s the evening and where could be a good place to get fairly traditional Cantonese style Chinese food? Dim Sum Palace!
The pork ribs (páigǔ; 排骨) is pretty decent. It came out piping hot with a lump of black bean that probably was suppose to be mixed in the sauce. It&amp;rsquo;s a little different than other dim sum places, but still pretty good.
The salted pepper prawns were really good.</description></item></channel></rss>