<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sea on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/</link><description>Recent content in Sea on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 21:13:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sushi Kashiba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/japanese/sushi-kashiba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 21:13:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/japanese/sushi-kashiba/</guid><description>Sushi Kashiba is located adjacent to the Pike Place Market. When I was doing research on restaurants to try out, I learned that Chef Shiro Kashiba trained under Jiro Ono (Jiro Dreams of Sushi). I also learned that Daisuke Nakazawa (chef of Sushi Nakazawa) also worked under Chef Kashiba. Online, everyone raved about how delicious the place was, so we decided to try this out. I made a reservation for 5:30 PM for a Friday evening, and they actually seated us earlier.</description></item><item><title>Altura</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/italian/altura/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:12:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/italian/altura/</guid><description>Altura is an Italian fine-dining restaurant in the Capitol Hill area of Seattle. It comes from Chef Nathan Lockwood who has worked in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Acquerello, which eventually earned a Michelin Star. He ended up coming to Seattle to lead and head this restaurant. Having done a lot of research on Seattle fine dining scene, I ended up on this restaurant to give it a try. Reviews mentioned that it was consistently good and nearly up there with some of the better U.</description></item><item><title>The George</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/new-american/the-george/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 13:30:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/new-american/the-george/</guid><description>The George is a restaurant located in the Fairmont Hotel right across the street from the downtown W Hotel in Seattle. The hotel has a somewhat pretentious exuberance to it because it has a lot of that old Ritz Carlton feel when you walk in. I was in a predicament where I had to stay in this hotel for just one night, but I was excited to see how this differed the modern feel of the W Hotel.</description></item><item><title>Trace Market</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/breakfast/trace-market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:28:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/breakfast/trace-market/</guid><description>Trace Market is the downtown Seattle Marriott&amp;rsquo;s available breakfast/brunch restaurant. Compared to NYC breakfast scene, I had very low expectations. I was a little irked by their hours opening at 7 AM (which seems late to me), but I understand that the west coast crowd don&amp;rsquo;t really wake up that early. In NYC, breakfast at these types of cafes can open as early as 6 AM. Regardless, this is a breakfast place that I frequent in the mornings when I travel to Seattle.</description></item><item><title>Elliot's Oyster House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/seafood/elliots-oyster-house/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea/seafood/elliots-oyster-house/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been coming out here for work, and it&amp;rsquo;s been challenging to find a time when I can document food that&amp;rsquo;s not in a big party atmosphere. This is one of the few times, where I can actually try and ponder over the food that I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten. We picked this place because it&amp;rsquo;s near the touristy areas of Pike Place Market and is next to a ton of seafood based restaurants on the waterfront.</description></item></channel></rss>