<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tsukemen on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tsukemen/</link><description>Recent content in Tsukemen on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tsukemen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TabeTomo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:18:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</guid><description>I remember a few years ago before the pandemic, TabeTomo was a very new tsukemen centric restaurant, and it was always on my try list. However, I never was able to make it to the restaurant due to how sparse tsukemen was in general in Manhattan, as well as, the restaurant was closed at random times when I tried to visit. Finally tonight, I got a chance to try this out and to compare against other tsukemen places.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Tsukemen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</guid><description>What is tsukemen (つけ麺; pronounced &amp;ldquo;skee-men&amp;rdquo;)? It&amp;rsquo;s basically thick udon served cold with a side of a thick soup/broth for dipping. In Los Angeles, I frequented a place in Sawtelle near the Westside called &amp;ldquo;Tsujita&amp;rdquo; that also specialized in something similar. Okiboru recently opened in Manhattan, and it&amp;rsquo;s famed for being on Michelin&amp;rsquo;s Bib Gourmand list in Atlanta. They do not take reservations, so when we arrived at this location at 5:15 PM on a Friday, the line outside was about 10 parties ranging from 2 to 6 people per group.</description></item><item><title>Ivan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</guid><description>Summary I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this ramen spot other than it was on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, and how it really touched a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s hearts. So my review will be almost based solely on the food itself.
The pork musubi bites were surprisingly good. Each bite is packed full of flavor, although I am rather doubtful that it&amp;rsquo;s worth $5 a piece.
The Japanese fried chicken were an interesting spin on karaage.</description></item><item><title>Shinshi Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:47:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shinshi-ramen/</guid><description>Pretty good tsukemen. Get the spicy miso. Tsukemen seems fairly rare in NYC. Still looking for something similar to LA Tsujita.</description></item></channel></rss>