<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>le on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/friends/le/</link><description>Recent content in le on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 22:33:20 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/friends/le/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mermaid Inn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 22:33:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</guid><description>We had the pleasure of enjoying the company of one of our friends who is coming into town for work. This restaurant is conveniently close to the Highline and was also near their hotel. I vaguely recall that this is a very popular seafood restaurant down in West Village, and it had been on my list for a number of years. Surprisingly, they opened another location here, and we thought we&amp;rsquo;d go check it out.</description></item><item><title>Death Ave</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:45:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</guid><description>Summary This is a restaurant located close to the end of the Highline. It&amp;rsquo;s down on 10th ave at the corner. It&amp;rsquo;s actually next door to its bar. So if you want to visit this place, don&amp;rsquo;t open the first door on your left. Open the second door.
The sour beer on the top was quite good. It had some flavors of a Guinness but obviously with the sour in it.</description></item><item><title>Tonchin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</guid><description>Summary This place has a pretty decent ambiance.
The yuzu margarita was surprisingly pretty good. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had yuzu before and like citrus, I recommend you get this if it&amp;rsquo;s available. I just checked their website&amp;rsquo;s drink menu, and it&amp;rsquo;s not on there. This drink wasn&amp;rsquo;t strong at all, and had a really really good before and after taste. I would drink this over any regular margarita any day.</description></item></channel></rss>