<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>East Village on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/east-village/</link><description>Recent content in East Village on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/east-village/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Claud</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</guid><description>For this week, I offered my partner an option of European or Chinese. Of course they said European. Claud comes from 2 veterans of the Momofuku Ko restaurant, chef Joshua Pinsky and wine expert Chase Sinzer. I remember this restaurant a while back, but it slipped off my radar with all these new openings in the last few years. When I checked Resy, I noticed there were openings on Friday, so the stars aligned.</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Udon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:48:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</guid><description>I just have this affinity for noodles. Their sibling location, Okiboru House of Tsukemen, was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the city when it comes to dipping ramen. This restaurant recently opened up marketing itself for udon. Like their tsukemen location, this one offers udon for dipping. Unlike traditional udon, these noodles are much wider and flatter. I was able to walk in by myself at 8 PM on a Tuesday evening, and I immediately was seated.</description></item><item><title>Secchu Yokota</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 21:47:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/</guid><description>Tempura is one of those things in Japanese cuisine that is pretty expensive for what it is, but when you find the right batter with the right ingredients, it&amp;rsquo;s so good. In Torrance in California, it&amp;rsquo;s been over a decade since I tried specialized tempura, so I was craving it recently. Unfortunately my partner loathes tempura for some odd reason, so I opted to dine alone when they decided to watch a Broadway show.</description></item><item><title>Madame Vo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 14:40:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</guid><description>Summary I haven&amp;rsquo;t frequent the heart of the East Village for quite some time. Walking through St. Marks, it&amp;rsquo;s pleasant to see that the city is slowly coming back alive. People still walk around with masks for the most part, and some restaurants have closed. Despite all this, the energy is slowly coming back alive. Since we were in this area and because now everyone is out and about, it&amp;rsquo;s getting difficult to do walk-in dinings.</description></item><item><title>Huo Yi Hot Pot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/huo-yi-hot-pot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:10:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/huo-yi-hot-pot/</guid><description>Summary It seems when it comes to hot pot, East Village is a thriving destination. Usually people try to go to 99 Favor Taste because it also has grillable BBQ meats in addition to hot pots. When people don&amp;rsquo;t have reservations and are quoted a 2 hour wait time, the next logical option is to look for another hot pot place which just happens to be this place since it&amp;rsquo;s a few streets down.</description></item><item><title>The Dip</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/the-dip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:05:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/the-dip/</guid><description>Summary French dips, let alone good ones, are pretty nonexistent in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a good one up in Upper West Side at Jacob&amp;rsquo;s Pickles, but other that I usually get my cravings by making my own. We just got out of watching the movie theater, and we were reasonably close to this new location. The chef used to work as an executive chef at 4 Charles Prime Rib in the East Village, and they picked a fantastic location on St.</description></item><item><title>Blue Ribbon Fried Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/blue-ribbon-fried-chicken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 13:05:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/blue-ribbon-fried-chicken/</guid><description>Summary The Blue Ribbon chain is known for their seafood and sushi. So it was interesting to see them coming out with the fried chicken venture. This has been around for a while, and for the last few years, friends have raved about it.
We got the 4 piece mixed with fries basket. The chicken itself is pretty tender and juicy. The skin is lightly crisped and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the batter thickness that something like KFC or Popeyes has.</description></item><item><title>Narcissa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/narcissa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 13:30:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/narcissa/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;m introducing a new category for restaurants that have gardens. This one has an interesting one. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly that great, but it seems to be an attraction for others. This is tucked near or in the Standard Hotel, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember. In the summer, the indoor seats are mostly vacant, so definitely ask for a seat near the window if you decide to sit inside.</description></item><item><title>Nu Noodle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nu-noodle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 19:02:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nu-noodle/</guid><description>This place&amp;rsquo;s beef noodles was just OK. I&amp;rsquo;ve had better. The portion size is just ok. I also got a side of bean curd, and it was a little on the salty side.</description></item><item><title>Mr White</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/mr-white/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 19:14:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/mr-white/</guid><description>Summary The clams were OK.
The Nola clams were better than the casino. The casino was so oversalted by the bacon such that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t taste the clams at all.
The shrimp beignets were forgotten.
The most memorable items were the crawfish dip and the cornbread. The crawfish dip was really good and had a lot of flavor to it. The cornbread was super buttery and was nice as well.</description></item><item><title>Dokodemo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/dokodemo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 22:10:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/dokodemo/</guid><description>Decent Japanese snack place with okonomiyaki and octopus balls. But that&amp;rsquo;s about it.</description></item><item><title>Ikinari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/ikinari/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:02:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/ikinari/</guid><description>Got the rare strip. It was pretty good for $30 for 14 oz. Not a lot of fat on it. I think the price keeps getting cheaper because not a lot of people go to this.</description></item><item><title>Zadie's Oyster Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/zadies-oyster-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:17:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/zadies-oyster-room/</guid><description>Different cooking styles for all types of oysters. Was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Ippudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</guid><description>I had visited Ippudo twice before this time throughout my whole life, once in London and once in the East Village. This original post just had a comment of &amp;ldquo;Overrated and pricey. I&amp;rsquo;d skip here any day of the week. Daikokuya in LA is way better&amp;rdquo;. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pics of my dinner nearly 4 years ago, I thought about revisiting this Midtown location to try to remember why I was underwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>Zundo Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/zundo-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:27:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/zundo-ya/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s just ok.</description></item><item><title>Ramen Misoya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-misoya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:26:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-misoya/</guid><description>Recommended by Totto Ramen server for best thick noodle in NYC. Soup was bad and salty. But yeah the noodle was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Martina Pizzeria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/martina-pizzeria/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:20:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/martina-pizzeria/</guid><description>Fast food version of Marta&amp;rsquo;s. It&amp;rsquo;s good. I like the salami and hot peppers, and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly inexpensive.</description></item><item><title>Hearth</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hearth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:01:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hearth/</guid><description>Was good but nothing particularly struck a note to me. Marc Forgione tasting menu is way better than here.</description></item><item><title>Senor Pollo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/senor-pollo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:55:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/senor-pollo/</guid><description>This place is pretty cheap. I remember both the lomo and pollo being a bit on the dry side, but it&amp;rsquo;s so cheap not much of a reason to complain I guess.</description></item><item><title>Shabu Tatsu</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/shabu-tatsu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:20:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/shabu-tatsu/</guid><description>Fairly inexpensive, but not very OG. Portions are small, and no where as good as LA shabu shabu.</description></item><item><title>Robataya Ny</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/robataya-ny/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:17:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/robataya-ny/</guid><description>This place was such a gimmick. Very showy like Benihanas but way worse. Food was just ok and super pricey. They have bday celebrations&amp;hellip; super weird.
But it&amp;rsquo;s CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>Curry Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/curry-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:08:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/curry-ya/</guid><description>The spicy pork tonkatsu was pretty good. One of the better Japanese curry places in the city.</description></item><item><title>Fuku</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/fuku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:19:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/fuku/</guid><description>A few doors down from the Ssam bar, this place is pretty good. $12 for a combo which was basically drink, fries, and the sandwich. The Momofuku red sauce is always good.
Unfortunately this is CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>Raclette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/raclette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 14:56:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/raclette/</guid><description>They are super stingy with the cheese, and it stinks the instant you walk in. But otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s delicious. You are allotted 2 cheese shavings. One of the guests at my table did not want their second shaving, so I used their second shaving for a total of three shaving. It&amp;rsquo;s good but not too expensive.</description></item></channel></rss>