<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vietnamese on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/vietnamese/</link><description>Recent content in Vietnamese on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/vietnamese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chef Papa Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</guid><description>The Long Island City area around Queensboro Plaza is definitely missing some Vietnamese restaurants. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Cyclo, and it was very mediocre. Since Knock Knock closed down, this family-owned restaurant from Flushing took over the location. We were able to stop by around 5 PM on a Sunday early evening without reservations. There was no one eating, and we asked to sit at the same bar that was located at Knock Knock.</description></item><item><title>Brasserie VietNam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 17:33:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to find decent Vietnamese restaurants in general in NYC. A lot of them just don&amp;rsquo;t get the broth in pho right. This one seemed like a more upscale version of general Vietnamese cuisine, and I saw it open less than a year ago on Yelp. It was tough at first to walk in a few times, so fortunately the hype subsided, and I was able to get an easy reservation on Friday at 5:30 PM for 2 people.</description></item><item><title>Cha Pa's Noodles and Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</guid><description>I work around the Rockafeller area, and I had to walk towards the Midtown West for an errand during lunch. Near the area that I was in, I noticed this Vietnamese pho restaurant that didn&amp;rsquo;t have many people. Since it was cold outside and before I head back, I decided to check this out for lunch, considering it had some basic pho options. When I walked in, there were some solo diners who were scarfing their noodles fast, so I felt at ease that this was would be a quick lunch spot.</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes.</description></item><item><title>Madame Vo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 14:40:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</guid><description>Summary I haven&amp;rsquo;t frequent the heart of the East Village for quite some time. Walking through St. Marks, it&amp;rsquo;s pleasant to see that the city is slowly coming back alive. People still walk around with masks for the most part, and some restaurants have closed. Despite all this, the energy is slowly coming back alive. Since we were in this area and because now everyone is out and about, it&amp;rsquo;s getting difficult to do walk-in dinings.</description></item><item><title>Cyclo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:33:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</guid><description>Summary Even though there had been a large number of Asian restaurants in the Long Island City and Astoria vicinity, vietnamese restaurants are still fairly limited. I was kind of craving for some pho since it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years, and this one was within walkable distance. The city recently allowed 25% dine in, and the reviews for this restaurant seemed fairly decent. The interior was decorated pretty homely, and the tables were spaced decently apart with screen separators.</description></item><item><title>High Lua Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 20:52:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</guid><description>Summary As usual, the North Williamsburg area is a pretty hot spot for restaurants to eat at. I had lived in this area for about 2 years, but I still come back time to time to get a haircut. Usually after the haircut, I&amp;rsquo;ll check out something. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a decent pho place that is close enough to me such that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to travel to Flushing.</description></item><item><title>Zen Yai Pho Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:38:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</guid><description>Summary Pho vietnamese restaurants are generally pretty scarce in the city compared to Los Angeles. If you do find one, they usually don&amp;rsquo;t give you all the fixins and are timid about their offerings. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a restaurant called Phorage pretty frequently where their broth was very rich, and their meats were rare but tender. So how would this compare?
We started off with thai tea and matcha thai.</description></item><item><title>Di an Di</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 19:28:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</guid><description>The pho was ok, and so was the dried vermicelli. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit expensive for what you get, but also not bad. I probably would still prefer to go to other Vietnamese places, though good Vietnamese places are hard to find in Manhattan. The decor is nice, but food wise - if anyone likes this place, I don&amp;rsquo;t trust their palette.</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn Banh Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:15:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</guid><description>Best banh mi I&amp;rsquo;ve had so far in New York. Cheap too.
But this place is CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>CoBa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</guid><description>Their pho + banhmi combo $12.50 is OK for lunch.</description></item></channel></rss>