<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vietnamese on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/vietnamese/</link><description>Recent content in Vietnamese on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:41:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/vietnamese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>La Dong</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/la-dong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:41:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/la-dong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-dong%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Dong was on my list for a while because I wanted to try some different Vietnamese flavors. The menu was quite appealing because there were things on there that I wanted to try since there is a sparseness of Vietnamese flavors in Manhattan. Even though there typically is a crowd outside, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to make reservations. I made a 5:30 PM for 2 reservation on a Friday without issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SEA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:58:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEA is a casual &lt;strong&gt;South East Asian&lt;/strong&gt; restaurant from Chef Jungsik Yim of two Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/"&gt;Jungsik&lt;/a&gt;. The restaurant offers a raw bar, small plates, and shareable plates with creativity. We were able to make a reservation pretty last minute for 5:15 PM on a Friday evening fairly easy. We arrived a little early, and they were able to seat us without issue. We had some high expectations that this restaurant will have great flavors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twin Tails</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/twin-tails%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new Southeast Asian restaurant is located on the third floor of the Columbus Circle mall. The restaurant is part of the &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurant group, which also included &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; to name a few. What was exciting about the menu here was that it was leaning into higher end Vietnamese and Thai flavors. We were able to make a reservation a few days in advance for two people at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef Papa Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chef-papa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Long Island City area around Queensboro Plaza is definitely missing some Vietnamese restaurants. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/"&gt;Cyclo&lt;/a&gt;, and it was very mediocre. Since &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/knock-knock/"&gt;Knock Knock&lt;/a&gt; closed down, this family-owned restaurant from Flushing took over the location. We were able to stop by around 5 PM on a Sunday early evening without reservations. There was no one eating, and we asked to sit at the same bar that was located at Knock Knock.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brasserie VietNam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 17:33:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/brasserie-vietnam%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to find decent Vietnamese restaurants in general in NYC. A lot of them just don&amp;rsquo;t get the broth in pho right. This one seemed like a more upscale version of general Vietnamese cuisine, and I saw it open less than a year ago on Yelp. It was tough at first to walk in a few times, so fortunately the hype subsided, and I was able to get an easy reservation on Friday at 5:30 PM for 2 people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cha Pa's Noodles and Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cha-pas-noodles%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work around the Rockafeller area, and I had to walk towards the Midtown West for an errand during lunch. Near the area that I was in, I noticed this Vietnamese pho restaurant that didn&amp;rsquo;t have many people. Since it was cold outside and before I head back, I decided to check this out for lunch, considering it had some basic pho options. When I walked in, there were some solo diners who were scarfing their noodles fast, so I felt at ease that this was would be a quick lunch spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes. We walked in as a party of 2 around 4:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Madame Vo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 14:40:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/madame-vo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t frequent the heart of the East Village for quite some time. Walking through St. Marks, it&amp;rsquo;s pleasant to see that the city is slowly coming back alive. People still walk around with masks for the most part, and some restaurants have closed. Despite all this, the energy is slowly coming back alive. Since we were in this area and because now everyone is out and about, it&amp;rsquo;s getting difficult to do walk-in dinings. Next door there was Curry Ya, but there were too many people. So we decided to try out this Vietnamese restaurant since there weren&amp;rsquo;t many people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cyclo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:33:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cyclo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there had been a large number of Asian restaurants in the Long Island City and Astoria vicinity, vietnamese restaurants are still fairly limited. I was kind of craving for some pho since it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years, and this one was within walkable distance. The city recently allowed 25% dine in, and the reviews for this restaurant seemed fairly decent. The interior was decorated pretty homely, and the tables were spaced decently apart with screen separators. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the food.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>High Lua Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 20:52:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the North Williamsburg area is a pretty hot spot for restaurants to eat at. I had lived in this area for about 2 years, but I still come back time to time to get a haircut. Usually after the haircut, I&amp;rsquo;ll check out something. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a decent pho place that is close enough to me such that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to travel to Flushing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zen Yai Pho Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:38:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pho vietnamese restaurants are generally pretty scarce in the city compared to Los Angeles. If you do find one, they usually don&amp;rsquo;t give you all the fixins and are timid about their offerings. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a restaurant called Phorage pretty frequently where their broth was very rich, and their meats were rare but tender. So how would this compare?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar%2F1_tea.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started off with &lt;strong&gt;thai tea&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;matcha thai&lt;/strong&gt;. The primary difference other than the higher cost is that the matcha thai tea has a bunch of matcha powder that kind of counters the sweetness of the thai tea by making it more dull but in a good way. It was actually pretty interesting comparing the 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Di an Di</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 19:28:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The pho was ok, and so was the dried vermicelli. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit expensive for what you get, but also not bad. I probably would still prefer to go to other Vietnamese places, though good Vietnamese places are hard to find in Manhattan. The decor is nice, but food wise - if anyone likes this place, I don&amp;rsquo;t trust their palette.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn Banh Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:15:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Best banh mi I&amp;rsquo;ve had so far in New York. Cheap too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this place is CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CoBa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/coba/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Their pho + banhmi combo $12.50 is OK for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>