<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sushi on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/sushi/</link><description>Recent content in Sushi on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/sushi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kogane</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:38:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</guid><description>We were definitely in for a treat in our visit to Los Angeles. My cousin raved about this place, and we were finally able to join for a lunch meal. They made a reservation for 4 around lunch time on Christmas eve, and it was fairly busy. For $125, you get a curated selection of omakase sushi that had a lot of interesting fishes that you would not typically have in New York City.</description></item><item><title>Tsujita Sushi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 20:37:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</guid><description>Tsujita is known for their ramen, particularly at the location where the dinner menu is different than their lunch menu. I was curious to try it for dinner to see how it compares to other Japanese restaurants. Note that this is not the Annex location. The Annex location at the time of this writing is the only Tsujita location that serves ramen for dinner.
This is #20 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.</description></item><item><title>Sushi Gen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/sushi-gen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 21:06:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/sushi-gen/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of sushi, let alone uni, so I was highly recommended to go to this place near Little Tokyo for lunch a few months ago. Sushi Gen, from what I was told, is the central supplier for sushi restaurants across Los Angeles. How much truth there is to this, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care. I was told that the lunch specials and fish quality here were great for the price.</description></item></channel></rss>