<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Montreal on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/neighborhood/montreal/</link><description>Recent content in Montreal on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/neighborhood/montreal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monarque</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/monarque/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:20:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/monarque/</guid><description>For our final dinner of our trip on this very frigid New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve in Montreal, I made a reservation at Monarque. Monarque is ranked 16 on Canada&amp;rsquo;s Best in 2023. They have 2 sides of the restaurant: one is a brasserie and the other is a more formal dining room. We sat in the dining room, which offered a 4 course menu for the night. Our area was a corner spot, where we had plenty of room to also place our jackets and bags without having it coat checked.</description></item><item><title>Montreal Plaza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/montreal-plaza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:20:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/montreal-plaza/</guid><description>Due to a last minute cancellation from Ile Flottante because they decided to shut down to give holiday break for their staff, I had to scramble to look for a reservation to book for our trip to Montreal. I had created a verbose document describing fallback plans on which day should there be problems. Montreal Plaza was one of the few for this day. It was ranked 21 on Canada&amp;rsquo;s 100 Best.</description></item><item><title>Jérôme Ferrer Europea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/jerome-ferrer-europea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 16:20:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/jerome-ferrer-europea/</guid><description>I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for a special Montreal restaurant for my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday. This came up as I was looking into gastronomy. The ingredients and menu looked interesting in that it had some whimsical tones to it, but also being a restaurant that had stood the test of time for at least a decade. In 2018 right before the pandemic, it was voted as the best Canadian restaurant.</description></item></channel></rss>