<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Honolulu on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/neighborhood/honolulu/</link><description>Recent content in Honolulu on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/neighborhood/honolulu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bar Māze</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 17:31:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</guid><description>For our last day in the Waikiki/Honolulu area before we head over to the western part of Oahu for Aulani, we decided to splurge on something a little nicer to eat. Of all the choices we had, we decided on this Bar Māze place that the internet had raved about. The dining room is quite small, and when we entered, we were seated at the counter. We noticed that many of the cooks were quite young, but they were also very professional with a lot of attention on making sure the food is cooked right.</description></item><item><title>Gashoken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/gashoken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 23:19:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/gashoken/</guid><description>Gashoken is located in this below ground Asian food mall called &amp;ldquo;Stix Asia&amp;rdquo;. There are several decent sized restaurants with different Asian cuisines, such as Japanese ramen, Taiwanese beef noodle, Japanese hot pot, Korean street foods, etc. We did our lap around, and ultimately landed first on this ramen joint because the host was really marketing it like crazy to everyone walking in front. Upon first glance, the menu was small, but alas we&amp;rsquo;re here for ramen.</description></item><item><title>Herringbone</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 15:05:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</guid><description>Herringbone is run by the &amp;ldquo;Tao Group Hospitality&amp;rdquo;, which operates more than 80 branded locations in 20 different markets. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what to expect, but per recommendations, we were able to do a walk in around 7 PM on a Monday. The restaurant is located on the top floor of the &amp;ldquo;International Market Place&amp;rdquo; where many restaurants are located, and it has a pretty laid back exterior. As you can vaguely tell from the picture, the right side is an outdoor covered patio letting in the Hawaiian breeze.</description></item><item><title>Poke Fix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/poke-fix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 14:16:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/poke-fix/</guid><description>We just landed in Honolulu for our Hawaii trip, and we were pretty hungry. Honolulu is 6 hours behind New York City! Our other friends had arrived a few hours earlier than us and suggested we check out this slight hole in the wall shop for poke near their hotel. My poke impression has always been pretty indifferent, so I was curious what is it about Hawaii poke that people rave about.</description></item></channel></rss>