<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scandinavian on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/scandinavian/</link><description>Recent content in Scandinavian on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/scandinavian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aquavit%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have &lt;strong&gt;2 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/"&gt;Aska&lt;/a&gt; recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aska</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I decided on this 2 Michelin Star restaurant located in the Williamsburg area. What appealed to me originally about this was that it was not just another French restaurant. French cuisine is great, but there are so many high end French restaurants around the city. Perhaps I am getting a little burnt out of having the same French tastes over and over, so I wanted something that was less normal. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had high end Scandinavian, so I thought today could be a good day. And to add, I had heard that they have non-alcoholic (juice) pairings, so I was excited to check this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>