<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Korean on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/korean/</link><description>Recent content in Korean on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/korean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Olle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 20:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</guid><description>If you visit sample sales frequently, there are 2 nearby the Nomad and Koreatown area. Because the sample sales close at 7 PM sharp, it compels you to look for food during core dinner hours. Fortunately if you go shop right after work and finish around 6 PM on weekdays, foot traffic to restaurants won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Olle is a Korean restaurant about a block away from the sample sale store on 5th Ave.</description></item><item><title>Okdongsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:37:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</guid><description>This restaurant is from a renowned Korean chef (Ok Dongsik) and is a 6 time Michelin Seoul Bib Gourmand restaurant. We were nearby at a popular sample sale, and this was on my list for a while to checkout. The menu is very small and is straight forward. We were able to walk in at around 6:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without reservation. They turn over seats fairly quickly even though there can easily be a line of people waiting.</description></item><item><title>Bōm</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:29:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</guid><description>Bom is a restaurant located in the back room of its sibling restaurant, Oiji Mi. We had been to that before, and I thought it was pretty decent. Bom was always on my list of things to try, but at $295 per person, I was pretty hesitant and skeptical. This restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a Michelin Star yet. Since reservations are fairly easy and Oiji Mi was pretty good, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this a try since we were celebrating two major milestones in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Jua</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 18:54:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</guid><description>Jua is one of those new-ish Korean restaurants that has received a number of praises from all sorts of diners. I was able to get a 2-seater a few days before Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day on a Saturday evening. It did require me to sit and snipe on Resy, which fortunately was not as difficult as trying to get reservations at Don Angie. Jua is a restaurant by chef Hoyoung Kim, who was the former executive chef of Jungsik.</description></item><item><title>Oppa Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 16:16:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</guid><description>We are likely going to frequent the West Village weekly because we&amp;rsquo;ve nearly tapped out the heart of the Midtown area. This area is densely populated with a high number of restaurants that goes through frequent turnovers and change. Oppa Bistro was an audible call when we learned that Olio e Piu was very packed at around 5:30 PM on a Friday. We were able to walk into Oppa Bistro with no reservations at around 5:45 PM, and there was just a handful of diners.</description></item><item><title>Naro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:28:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</guid><description>Naro is a new Korean restaurant that opened right next to the Rockafeller ice skating rink. According to the menu, the Naro name was inspired by South Korea&amp;rsquo;s first ever space vehicle to successfully achieve Earth&amp;rsquo;s orbit and also from the Korean phrase nah-ro (which means &amp;ldquo;through me&amp;rdquo;). Naro focuses on Korean cuisine, drawing inspiration from classic dishes from different moments in Korean history. Lastly, this is the third restaurant from the Atomix and Attaboy founders, so there is definitely some expectations.</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system Tock. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week.</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix.</description></item><item><title>Oiji Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:04:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</guid><description>I read about Oiji Mi somewhere, and my gourmand syndrome was kicking in since I felt like I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a prix fixe upper end restaurant in a while. Oiji Mi is relatively new, and it comes from the owners of the original East Village&amp;rsquo;s Oiji. It offers creative contemporary Korean dining composed uniquely for NYC. I saw that they offer a 5 course tasting menu for $125 per person, and the menu looked quite interesting.</description></item><item><title>Genesis House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:14:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</guid><description>We saw this restaurant&amp;rsquo;s opening relatively recently on an NYC openings blog. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what exactly was the &amp;ldquo;Genesis House&amp;rdquo; or what &amp;ldquo;curated by Onjium&amp;rdquo; meant, but I figure post pandemic this was an excellent opportunity to make a reservation for something new to please my gourmand syndrome. The Genesis house is kind of interesting. The first floor is a showroom of Genesis vehicles where you can sit in the cars and talk to the different reps.</description></item><item><title>Ziggle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:51:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/ziggle/</guid><description>This restaurant is sandwiched at the cusp of Sunnyside between a AYCE Korean BBQ restaurant and a newly opened Sonic fast food joint. The menu looks pretty traditional Korean, and it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to try these types of restaurants in different neighborhoods. This one is rarely as busy as its next door neighbors, but I had some expectations of how this would turn out. When we arrived at 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, we were the only patrons in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Gan Hoo BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:11:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</guid><description>Flushing is the NYC mecca for Chinese food. It&amp;rsquo;s at the end of the 7 train line heading east, and it takes about 40 minutes from Manhattan on weekends. Many restaurants and stalls only accept cash, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite different than being in Manhattan or Long Island City. My partner had a friend that wanted to meet in Flushing to try out Korean BBQ. I thought there would be several near Main Street, but it seems all the decent Korean BBQ places are least a mile east of the Main street subway station.</description></item><item><title>Wonder Pig Kbbq</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 14:43:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/wonder-pig-kbbq/</guid><description>All you can eat (AYCE) Korean BBQ places are pretty sparse the closer you get to Manhattan. If you did find one, the quality is kind of questionable compared to the a&amp;rsquo;la carte places. We discovered this restaurant a few months back when we went to the Popeyes next door. It hadn&amp;rsquo;t opened yet, but there seems to be a few restaurants next to it that are opening in the very near future.</description></item><item><title>Mr Mistah Oh</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mr-mistah-oh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 23:03:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mr-mistah-oh/</guid><description>On this very humid Friday afternoon, I had to make my way into the Flatiron area to run some errands. This Korean restaurant was something that seemed appealing since we haven&amp;rsquo;t had Korean food in a while. Normally for decent Korean, you&amp;rsquo;d have to venture into midtown, but the menu looked pretty decent online. We were fortunate that that they still had the NY restaurant week menu which was quite alluring.</description></item><item><title>Dokebi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/dokebi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:04:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/dokebi/</guid><description>Summary This Korean BBQ restaurant has been in North Williamsburg for a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to go to this, but prior to the pandemic, it was always easier to go to Koreatown since I was always in Manhattan. We arrived here at an early rainy Sunday afternoon. They follow COVID protocol very well, and there were very few people inside. The waitress took our temperature and address as usual, and then we were seated after.</description></item><item><title>Love Korean BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/love-korean-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 20:53:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/love-korean-bbq/</guid><description>Summary As we enter the end of the year and NYC indoor dining is forced to be shutdown due to a COVID uptick, we wanted to get some last fixin with Korean BBQ. Even though we have tried many of the major Korean BBQ restaurants near Koreatown already, this is one of the few remaining ones to try. When we visited, they check your temperature and had glass dividers between tables.</description></item><item><title>Cote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:00:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</guid><description>Summary Indoor dining finally opened again in NYC on September 30, 2020. There are those that feel it&amp;rsquo;s reckless in this COVID temperament, but we still decided to celebrate by booking an indoor reservation at Cote, a 1 Michelin Star Korean BBQ restaurant. Normally, this is difficult to get a reasonable time, so we were happy it was not too bad. Like all upscale restaurants, they take your temperature via the forehead, and each table is partitioned by a plastic partition.</description></item><item><title>Hee Korean BBQ Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/hee-korean-bbq-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 16:06:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/hee-korean-bbq-grill/</guid><description>Summary Korean BBQ in NYC is often straight forward. If you want to eat it, you go to Koreatown for a safe bet. If you go away from Koreatown, you risk eating somewhere that may not satisfy that lust. Perhaps the meat would not be as good, or the side dishes would be awful.
Fortunately this place in Chelsea was actually pretty decent.
I definitely want to preface that the ventilation in this restaurant is not good despite the ducts over the grills, so your clothes will smell.</description></item><item><title>The Woo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 23:18:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/the-woo/</guid><description>Summary This is a surprising decent Korean restaurant in the South Village. Unlike Koreatown BBQ restaurants, this place actually has you cooking the meats just like in Los Angeles.
The banchan was on the blander side of things. The daikon was a little watery. The kimchi radish was decent but wasn&amp;rsquo;t as pickled as other Korean places. The broccoli was fine. Lastly, the kimchi was decent but again not as fermented as other places.</description></item><item><title>Cho Dang Gol</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cho-dang-gol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 22:04:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cho-dang-gol/</guid><description>Summary We were visiting the Morgan Library on a late Sunday afternoon, and this restaurant was close by and on my list. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been into old school Korean places where the food was centered around non BBQ items such as bossam and kimchi jigae.
The egg soup was served as part of the meal. It&amp;rsquo;s simply tasted of steamed egg with some scallions on top. Pretty straight forward and pretty good.</description></item><item><title>K-Bap</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/k-bap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 20:20:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/k-bap/</guid><description>Summary This is easily walkable from the 5th Ave flagship Apple store for some decent casual Korean food.
The banchan comes with the bulgogi bento box below. It&amp;rsquo;s basically that white pickled daikon, kimchi radish, and kimchi. Just a note that their kimchi here is super sour compared to other places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to.
The bulgogi bento box was ok. It came with japchae (Korean sweet potato noodles), bulgogi, fish cake, kimchi daikon, and what tasted similar to tempura potato of some sort.</description></item><item><title>Kāwi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 17:15:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</guid><description>Summary We stopped by for lunch for David Chang&amp;rsquo;s newest Momofuku restaurant and is located in the mall across the street from The Vessel. It&amp;rsquo;s on the 5th floor near the Bouchon Bakery. Surprisingly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too filled, but then again it&amp;rsquo;s terribly hot and humid outside.
The trading card cocktail consists of plantation pineapple, cruzan blackstrap, smith &amp;amp; cross rums, trader vic&amp;rsquo;s macadamia liqueur, curry, and yogurt. I did not like this at all as it was very sweet.</description></item><item><title>Bap</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:47:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</guid><description>Summary The food here was surprisingly decent. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t expect many places in Midtown East to be good, let alone Asian ethnic foods.
We ordered a pineapple Mocktail and a glass of Hite, which is nothing to write home about.
The banchan here was pretty good, although portion size is on the smaller side. You can ask for additional banchan as needed. Here you got kimchi, mixed salad, jalapenos, pickled cauliflower, pickled daikon cubes, and pickled daikon slices.</description></item><item><title>Turntable Chicken Jazz</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/turntable-chicken-jazz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/turntable-chicken-jazz/</guid><description>Summary The vibe here is pretty cool if you&amp;rsquo;re into old school jazz environments. The walls have a load of records and lots of old music devices. It does get a little noisy, and sometimes people eat really slow to create a wait. It&amp;rsquo;s not too different than other typical Korean bar/chicken joints where they have lots of alcohol and Korean bar foods.
The drinks were ok. Started off with a passionfruit lemonade.</description></item><item><title>Anytime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/anytime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 14:45:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/anytime/</guid><description>Summary This place is interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s like a modern version of typical Korean tapas.
They have these idea cocktails that have flashing lights underneath it. You can click on the switch underneath to alter the different lighting patterns. It&amp;rsquo;s gimmicky, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure they are targeting that photo crowd. The drinks themselves were OK. I think I prefer Brazilian style fruit cocktails now.
The hamachi cevichee was decent. It&amp;rsquo;s just tartare with a different flavor profile, but otherwise, it tasted like what you&amp;rsquo;d expect.</description></item></channel></rss>