<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yakitori on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/yakitori/</link><description>Recent content in Yakitori on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/yakitori/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Torien</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 15:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</guid><description>As a Christmas celebration before we embark on a trip, I wanted to knock this final yakitori tasting off the list. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to a slew of yakitori tasting places, and this is the last one that is on the higher end. Torien still has 1 Michelin Star in 2023, and it also has a sister 1 Michelin Star restaurant, Torishiki, in Tokyo Japan. We were able to make a reservation for this for a Saturday a few weeks back without issues.</description></item><item><title>Heno Heno</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:42:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</guid><description>My partner had won some tickets to watch Appropriate on Broadway starring Sarah Paulson. The show starts at 8, but we had to pick up the will-call tickets by 7:30. I saw this Japanese small eatery was nearby the theater on 46th St, and I thought this would be a decent restaurant to try out since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of little things we can order. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening at around 5:30 PM before it got busy.</description></item><item><title>Kono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kono/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:58:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kono/</guid><description>Kono has been something on my radar for quite some time. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since we&amp;rsquo;ve splurged quality yakitori, so I was able to snipe a reservation for a Saturday night out at 5:30 PM fairly quickly on Resy. Chef Atsushi &amp;ldquo;ATS&amp;rdquo; Kono was originally at Torishin, and after looking at the menu, I was excited to see what this experience brought. This restaurant focused on kappo-style yakitori omakase featuring organic Amish chicken and seasonable vegetables.</description></item><item><title>Izakaya Toribar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:44:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</guid><description>Summary When people say Manhattan has practically endless restaurants, it&amp;rsquo;s quite true. There&amp;rsquo;s not enough time, money, and health to try all the different restaurants out there. For this visit into the city, we decided to go after yakitori since that was fairly close around the area we were at. We have had previously been to Torishin, a former Michelin 1-star, so I wanted to show my partner different yakitori places that were less upscaled.</description></item><item><title>Torishin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 14:29:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</guid><description>Summary For this special outing, Yakitori Torishin has been on my list ever since I moved to New York City. I finally had a chance to try this for the girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday.
We wanted the regular yakitori experience as opposed to the select counter experience. The reason is that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine the value from yakitori at literally double the cost of a regular omakase. They brought us into the back room, and we were still seated in front of the chefs.</description></item></channel></rss>