<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Canadian on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/cuisine/canadian/</link><description>Recent content in Canadian on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 19:44:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/cuisine/canadian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skylon Tower Revolving Dining Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 19:44:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/skylon-tower-revolving-dining-room%2F0_tower.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Niagara Canadian side, there is a lot more tourist attractions, views, and restaurants. My partner really wanted to check this revolving dining room out, so I made a reservation for 2 for 4:30 PM a few days in advance fairly easy. When you arrive into the bottom floor, the bottom floor of the tower has a seemingly outdated game mall with super old games. It felt like a blast in the past. Then you take the escalators up to the elevators that bring you up to this revolving tower. The elevator went up to the dining room floor pretty quickly, and you get a nice view of Niagara Falls.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monarque</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/monarque/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:20:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/monarque/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monarque%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our final dinner of our trip on this very frigid New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve in Montreal, I made a reservation at Monarque. Monarque is &lt;a href="https://canadas100best.com/monarque-2023"&gt;ranked 16 on Canada&amp;rsquo;s Best in 2023&lt;/a&gt;. They have 2 sides of the restaurant: one is a brasserie and the other is a more formal dining room. We sat in the dining room, which offered a 4 course menu for the night. Our area was a corner spot, where we had plenty of room to also place our jackets and bags without having it coat checked.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Montreal Plaza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/montreal-plaza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:20:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/montreal-plaza/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/montreal-plaza%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a last minute cancellation from Ile Flottante because they decided to shut down to give holiday break for their staff, I had to scramble to look for a reservation to book for our trip to Montreal. I had created a verbose document describing fallback plans on which day should there be problems. Montreal Plaza was one of the few for this day. It was &lt;a href="https://canadas100best.com/montreal-plaza-2023"&gt;ranked 21 on Canada&amp;rsquo;s 100 Best&lt;/a&gt;. We saw that Phil Rosenthal from &amp;ldquo;Somebody Feed Phil&amp;rdquo; had eaten here and highly recommended it. Granted, this was probably during a time of different situations. He had gone through a 27-course meal, whereas we just had roughly 5 courses. This restaurant is pretty close to the orange line, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to access. Within a few days, we were able to make a reservation for 8:30 PM on December 30.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ma Poule Mouillée</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/ma-poule-mouillee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 16:40:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/ca/ma-poule-mouillee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ma-poule-mouillee%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner has lusted for Portuguese chicken for some time for some reason. Essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s just wood fire-cooked chicken. You can expect lots of woodsy flavors, and supposedly a lot of juicy flavors as well since you&amp;rsquo;re sweating the chicken. We saw Phil Rosenthal from &amp;ldquo;Somebody Feed Phil&amp;rdquo; on Netflix come here and have a fantastic time. The real big question though for me is his palette similar to mine (or ours). When we arrived here around 2:30 PM in the afternoon, and there was a line already.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>