<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hell's Kitchen on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/hells-kitchen/</link><description>Recent content in Hell's Kitchen on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 22:08:26 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/hells-kitchen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Elephant Ear</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/elephant-ear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 22:08:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/elephant-ear/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/elephant-ear%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elephant Ear, an interesting name for a Thai restaurant, has been on my list for quite a while. In this area near the theaters, there is an ongoing rotation of Thai restaurants. We happened to catch a Broadway show, so I made a reservation for two people at 6 PM. When we went to the restaurant after our show, they mentioned that there&amp;rsquo;s a 1.5 hour limit for dining.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Limusina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/limusina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:41:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/limusina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/limusina%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/"&gt;Quality Branded restaurateurs&lt;/a&gt; comes another restaurant in a similar vein to popular hits like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/"&gt;Bad Roman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zous&lt;/a&gt;. The cuisine for this restaurant is Mexican-inspired and has all the snazzy colors to indicate this could be fun. This restaurant is near the Hudson Yards area, and it was very easy to make a reservation for 2 for 6 PM on a Friday night. This restaurant is about 1 block away from the E-train exit off 34th.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Baires Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 21:45:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/baires-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw an early afternoon theater show, and right after, we decided to check out Argentine food. Baires Grill was appealing because it is a Miami chain, and this is their only non-Miami location. We are planning on visiting Miami in the near future, so I was curious to see how this food differs than other Argentine restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. We walked in around 4 PM on a Saturday without reservations, and they seated us immediately without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kochi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:48:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kochi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kochi has been on my list for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to several of the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other restaurants, and they&amp;rsquo;re all delightful. This is his first solo project, after working in kitchens like Le Bernardin, Per Se, and Morimoto. What&amp;rsquo;s also great about this restaurant is that it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to get a reservation if you just book a few days out. We were able to get one at 5:30 PM on a Friday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Papa San</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/papa-san/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 23:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/papa-san/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/papa-san%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papa San was on my list for a while, especially from the folks that did &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/llama-inn/"&gt;Llama Inn&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an izakaya (think of Japanese tapas), made with a Peruano-Japanese influence. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting blend of cuisines, and it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon. In Peru, they do have a lot of Asian influences, such as lomo saltado, where they use soy sauce in the dish. We made a reservation for 2 for 5:00 PM on a Sunday evening very easily. This is located very close to Hudson Yards.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rosevale Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rosevale-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was another Broadway showing that we had to attend. Our theater district restaurant pool is thinning a bit, so this one was somewhat difficult to locate. It reminds me of a Midtown staple type of restaurant that is very friendly to the theater crowd, and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get in. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening around 5 PM without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Becco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:05:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/becco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becco was on our list for a while. This restaurant in the Theater District was always full around theater times, so of course, that&amp;rsquo;s naturally alluring. It was first opened in 1993 by Lidia Bastianich and her son, Joe, who you might recognize from the U.S. version of the MasterChef series. The Yelp ratings of the food seem surprisingly low compared to the Google counterpart, so that increase our curiosity. We were able to easily make a reservation the earlier in the day for 5:15 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/il-divino%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/"&gt;Mari&lt;/a&gt;. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/"&gt;Le Bernardin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/"&gt;Le Rock&lt;/a&gt;. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night. The restaurant is located on the second floor, but you check in on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kausa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kausa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had won another theater tickets for this Sunday, so we looked for a place nearby. My partner desired Peruvian food again, specifically lomo saltado. The best lomo saltado place we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had was actually &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/"&gt;Mario&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a comparable place, especially in New York City. We walked in on a late Sunday afternoon without issues, and we were seated promptly. Looking over the menu, they had your typical Peruvian options.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Danji</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:18:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/danji%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danji is Chef Hooni Kim&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that opened 15 years ago. It earned a Michelin Star back in 2012 and closed in April 2023 due to a fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, which was phenomenal for what it was. We decided to check out this to see how it was, so I made a reservation pretty easily a week prior for 5:30 PM for a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twin Tails</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/twin-tails%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new Southeast Asian restaurant is located on the third floor of the Columbus Circle mall. The restaurant is part of the &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurant group, which also included &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; to name a few. What was exciting about the menu here was that it was leaning into higher end Vietnamese and Thai flavors. We were able to make a reservation a few days in advance for two people at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pure Thai Cookhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pure-thai-cookhouse%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won yet another lottery for one of the theater shows, so we were hoping to walk into Wondee Thai. As expected, there was a line outside and a wait inside, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble missing the show if we had waited. We instead opted to walk a block south to this restaurant which had no patrons. We were able to walk in for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Saturday night without reservations. There seemed to be 2 sections to this restaurant, a left and a right. We were seated on the left on a small table with stools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mari%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/frena%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sicily%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/steak-frites-bistro%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/amarone-scarlatto%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bad-roman%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/about/the-team/"&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; that created this restaurant also helped create &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/"&gt;Quality Eats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant is very bustling, with lots of noise and all types of clientele. You will find many on their date nights, and you will find big parties celebrating something as if they were celebrities. The noise level is pretty loud, and you are seated pretty close to other tables. The music is also on the louder side too, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t uncomfortably loud. At times it was hard to hear our server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heno Heno</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:42:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/heno-heno%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had won some tickets to watch Appropriate on Broadway starring Sarah Paulson. The show starts at 8, but we had to pick up the will-call tickets by 7:30. I saw this Japanese small eatery was nearby the theater on 46th St, and I thought this would be a decent restaurant to try out since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of little things we can order. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening at around 5:30 PM before it got busy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Roosters</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 13:11:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/three-roosters%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been just demolishing a ton of restaurants around the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/theater-district/"&gt;Theater District&lt;/a&gt; since we&amp;rsquo;ve been going to a lot of Broadway shows. This restaurant was on our eyes to go to, but they always take a small break between 4 to 5 PM, so it can put a little time crunch if you have a show around 6:30 to 7 PM. However despite the restaurant being small with probably 5 or 6 tables, we were able to walk in on a Sunday evening around 5:30 PM without reservations. The food here is less about your normal Thai food, and more about chicken set meals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Four Four South Village</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/four-four-south-village%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese food is one of the types of cuisines that is seldomly found in Manhattan and just simply cannot compare to the San Gabriel Valley in the greater Los Angeles area in California. I asked my partner before a show if they wanted to check this out, and to my surprise they said yes! Normally they are not fond of this type of food, especially when noodles are around. This is not too far from Broadway theaters. We were able to walk in around 5:30 PM on a Monday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giardino 54</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/giardino-54%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near Broadway and 50th to watch the Back to the Future musical, which was actually surprisingly good. After, we had wanted Thai food, but the restaurant was closed briefly. My partner didn&amp;rsquo;t use the restrooms at the theater, so I scrambled for another option that had a restroom and found this restaurant off of 54th. We were able to walk in without reservations for 2 at around 5:30 PM on a Saturday night. The host said that the &amp;ldquo;garden&amp;rdquo; was saved for just reservations, which we were fine with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chalong</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 19:25:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chalong%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show to go to around 43rd and 9th Ave, so we decided to look around the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. In this area from my research, there seems to be some pretty good Thai restaurants that have been here for a bit or are opening up. We had recently gone to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/lumlum/"&gt;LumLum&lt;/a&gt;, which focused on more Northern Thai cuisine. Here in Chalong which is on 9th Ave between 51st and 52nd, they are focused on more Southern Thai. This restaurant is a few months old, and we were able to get a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM the night prior to our arrival.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef's Table at Brooklyn Fare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table at Brooklyn Fare is a renown &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant by Chef Cesar Ramirez. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by Japanese cuisine with French technique, and the 13 course tasting menu tonight is focused on fish &amp;amp; shellfish with 1 meat course and 4 dessert courses. I was quite excited to come here since moving to NYC. This restaurant was always very difficult to get reservations, so it was great that we were able to when we wanted. This restaurant is currently rated number 61 out of 100 on the &lt;a href="https://www.theworlds50best.com/stories/News/the-worlds-50-best-restaurants-2023-51-100-list.html"&gt;The World&amp;rsquo;s Best 50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prime Meat Rokko</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/prime-meat-rokko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 23:01:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/prime-meat-rokko/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/prime-meat-rokko%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area catching up on a Broadway musical called &amp;ldquo;MJ: The Musical&amp;rdquo; based on Michael Jackson. This area we have rarely explored much, considering early post-pandemic, this area was quite dangerous with the drug users and harassers. Nevertheless, this katsu restaurant has been on my list for years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to check this out. We were able to walk in on a Sunday at around 5:30 PM without any issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zou Zou's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:02:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/zou-zous%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located near the Vessel and Hudson Yards, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for quite some time. They simply love Mediterranean small plates and dips. We actually had to make a reservation a few weeks out to nab our reservation at 5 PM on a Sunday night. The restaurant lies in this little courtyard where it leads into one of the Peloton offices. When we arrived, we were able to check in a few minutes early. The hosts asked us to wait at the bar, and when they were ready for dinner service, they will come get you and bring you to your table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cha Pa's Noodles and Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cha-pas-noodles%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work around the Rockafeller area, and I had to walk towards the Midtown West for an errand during lunch. Near the area that I was in, I noticed this Vietnamese pho restaurant that didn&amp;rsquo;t have many people. Since it was cold outside and before I head back, I decided to check this out for lunch, considering it had some basic pho options. When I walked in, there were some solo diners who were scarfing their noodles fast, so I felt at ease that this was would be a quick lunch spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>LumLum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/lumlum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 22:40:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/lumlum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lumlum%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LumLum is a fairly new Thai restaurant to the city. What attracted me was that it has a lot of Northern Thai flavors and influences in the food. Think Thai but modernized somewhat. When you see some of the photos below, you will see what that means. The restaurant is run by 2 sisters who grew up in Thailand. When you arrive, both the interior and exterior are very social media friendly. We arrived at around 5:10 on a Friday evening after work, and were able to walk in with just a party of 2. When we finished around 6:00, there was a wait outside already.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Per Se</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:37:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/per-se%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per Se is Thomas Keller&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed interpretation of the French Laundry restaurant in New York City and has &lt;strong&gt;3 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a replacement for the French Laundry, but it might be indicative of what to expect if we did ever go to Napa Valley to try it out. This restaurant is located in Columbus Circle at the top floor inside the mall. When we walked in, we were astounded by the huge ceiling and the vast feeling of space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Harrow</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 21:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearby, we had gotten free tickets to the Intrepid museum which sat on the water along 46th. The museum closed at 5 PM sharp, and we picked this restaurant since it was not too far of a walk. This had been on my list for a few years already, but we&amp;rsquo;re rarely in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen restaurants is that the restaurant prices are not usually that expensive and the food is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pio Pio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/pio-pio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:52:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/pio-pio/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pio Pio actually has several stores in the greater New York City. This one is number &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; and is located in Manhattan a few blocks north of Hudson Yards. Remember that the COVID protocols are still applicable. When we walked in, we were seated in an alcove to the left before the stairs that led down to a larger open space dining room. This alcove was pretty nice and it seemed to be catered for parties of 2. The lights were dimmer here for more intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tim Ho Wan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:46:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/tim-ho-wan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend was in town, and I saw that Tim Ho was near their hotel. This place was always on my list to try given that it had received Michelin recognition at its Hong Kong location. Given I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten at numerous dim sum places already, they tout themselves as the dim sum specialists, so I already have high expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tim-ho-wan%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the drink on the left, but the right was some type of &lt;strong&gt;mango cococnut slush&lt;/strong&gt;. It was pretty good as it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Torishin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 14:29:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this special outing, Yakitori Torishin has been on my list ever since I moved to New York City. I finally had a chance to try this for the girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/torishin%2F1_restaurant.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted the regular yakitori experience as opposed to the select counter experience. The reason is that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine the value from yakitori at literally double the cost of a regular omakase. They brought us into the back room, and we were still seated in front of the chefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Buena Vista</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 11:58:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend was in town around the Hudson Yards area, and we wanted to look for something around the area. The menu here looked pretty decent, and it was on my bookmarks for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/buena-vista%2F1_bread.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;bread&lt;/strong&gt; came with some type of tomato olive oil medley. It reminded me of bruschetta toppings but more akin to diced tomatoes out of a jar. The sauce itself was alright.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carlo's Bakery</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/carlos-bakery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 23:58:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/carlos-bakery/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is known for the dessert chef featured on Cake Boss. To be quite honest, I&amp;rsquo;ve never watched it, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/carlos-bakery%2F1_desserts.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got &lt;strong&gt;chocolate cannoli&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;plain cannoli&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;some red velvet cake&lt;/strong&gt; thing, and &lt;strong&gt;lobster tail&lt;/strong&gt;. To be honest, the lobster tail was actually quite good and was my favorite of everything. The lobster tail&amp;rsquo;s pastry thin crust was flaky but not brittle. It tasted like a delicate thin but sturdy crust of a pastel I had at Aldea. The filling was good and not too sweet. The cannolis, to be honest, I could do without. They were actually quite sweet, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really recommend that as much as the lobster tail if you had to pick one. Lastly, the red velvet cake looking thing was not very good. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much cake in it. And if there was, it was blended with all the cream inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Polynesian</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-polynesian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 15:32:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-polynesian/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is located near 42nd Street and 9 ave in the POD hotel. The restaurant decor is kind of interesting as it does give out a tropical-ish vibe to it. There is an outdoor area that has a lot of those basket woven seats with a cushion on them. From where we sat outdoors, we can see views of the H&amp;amp;M building and the Empire State Building in plain sight.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kāwi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 17:15:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kawi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped by for lunch for David Chang&amp;rsquo;s newest Momofuku restaurant and is located in the mall across the street from The Vessel. It&amp;rsquo;s on the 5th floor near the Bouchon Bakery. Surprisingly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too filled, but then again it&amp;rsquo;s terribly hot and humid outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kawi%2F1_trading_card.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;trading card&lt;/strong&gt; cocktail consists of plantation pineapple, cruzan blackstrap, smith &amp;amp; cross rums, trader vic&amp;rsquo;s macadamia liqueur, curry, and yogurt. I did not like this at all as it was very sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Marshal</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-marshal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:04:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-marshal/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Was surprisingly good. Good date place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>