<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Baked Alaska on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/baked-alaska/</link><description>Recent content in Baked Alaska on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/baked-alaska/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item><item><title>Gage and Tollner</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:28:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</guid><description>Gage and Tollner has been on my list for quite a while now. I was casually browsing for restaurants with baked alaska, and this had shown up high on people&amp;rsquo;s list. Whenever I had tried to look at reservations, it was pretty booked. I was very lucky to have found an open reservation for 2 at 5 PM on a Sunday the night before. So how did it go?</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.</description></item><item><title>American Brass</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 18:50:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</guid><description>Summary This is a restaurant from the same people that brought Maiella. Even though that restaurant was modern Italian, this one was more of a modern French. It sits across the park near the Hunters Point library.
We came here on a Sunday, prior to the day that New York City had to shutdown dining in restaurants due to the corona virus. Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t really out and about, the restaurant had many empty tables.</description></item><item><title>Le Coucou</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-coucou/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:05:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-coucou/</guid><description>Amazing place. The baked alaska and veal tongue were really good. It&amp;rsquo;s also not too expensive.</description></item></channel></rss>