<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Baked Alaska on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/baked-alaska/</link><description>Recent content in Baked Alaska on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/baked-alaska/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Giorgio's of Gramercy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 21:51:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</guid><description>In our quest to find all the &amp;ldquo;Baked Alaska&amp;rdquo; restaurants in NYC, this was one that I was surprised to have it priced reasonably. Looking at the menu, everything was affordable compared to the rest of Manhattan. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest that I have never heard of this restaurant, and this came up randomly in my search. We easily made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday.</description></item><item><title>The Clocktower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 19:39:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</guid><description>The Clocktower has been on my list for a while and was a former 1 Michelin Star restaurant a few years ago. I ended up circling back to this restaurant because we&amp;rsquo;re desiring to eat as many baked Alaska places as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how many permutations of this dessert exists. We were able to book a reservation for 2 for a Friday evening without issue. The restaurant is located inside The Edison hotel on the second floor.</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item><item><title>Gage and Tollner</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:28:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</guid><description>Gage and Tollner has been on my list for quite a while now. I was casually browsing for restaurants with baked alaska, and this had shown up high on people&amp;rsquo;s list. Whenever I had tried to look at reservations, it was pretty booked. I was very lucky to have found an open reservation for 2 at 5 PM on a Sunday the night before. So how did it go?</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.</description></item><item><title>American Brass</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 18:50:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</guid><description>Summary This is a restaurant from the same people that brought Maiella. Even though that restaurant was modern Italian, this one was more of a modern French. It sits across the park near the Hunters Point library.
We came here on a Sunday, prior to the day that New York City had to shutdown dining in restaurants due to the corona virus. Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t really out and about, the restaurant had many empty tables.</description></item><item><title>Delmonico's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/delmonicos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:04:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/delmonicos/</guid><description>Delmonico&amp;rsquo;s was a steak restaurant I recall going a long time ago. I wrote that the steak kind of sucked because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t flavorful or fatty. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through an extensive journey in steak world, I&amp;rsquo;m curious how my palette has updated itself. We went to this restaurant mainly because it apparently is known for its Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Fortunately, they offered this dessert option in their restaurant week menu at $60 per person, which includes choice of 1 appetizer, 1 entree, and 1 dessert.</description></item><item><title>Le Coucou</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-coucou/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:05:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-coucou/</guid><description>Amazing place. The baked alaska and veal tongue were really good. It&amp;rsquo;s also not too expensive.</description></item></channel></rss>