<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Downtown on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/downtown/</link><description>Recent content in Downtown on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/downtown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chicken and Rice</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/chicken-and-rice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 23:18:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/chicken-and-rice/</guid><description>This was going to be one of those weeks where it&amp;rsquo;s time to go street food. If you have ever been to New York, they have halal carts that people love to eat at after a night at the bars. This is LA&amp;rsquo;s tribute to that.
This is #19 of 52 of my LA food expedition.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.</description></item><item><title>Nick and Stef's Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/nick-and-stefs-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 11:58:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/nick-and-stefs-steakhouse/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had steak in a while. I heard of this place from my buddy as a place he always wanted to try since he&amp;rsquo;s a steak guy. They do their own aging process here. When you walk into the restaurant, you can see through a window slabs of meat going through the aging process.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. Around this time was when aged steaks started to be a huge thing in Los Angeles.</description></item><item><title>Baco Mercat</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/baco-mercat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 22:20:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/baco-mercat/</guid><description>It was my cousin&amp;rsquo;s birthday, so she wanted to try this place because of all the rave Yelp reviews. Took the train to downtown LA and then hiked about a mile to this place. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen any of the reviews yet, but I personally take Yelp reviews like a grain of salt because from past experiences my palette seems to be very much different than the majority (or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m picky?</description></item><item><title>Sushi Gen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/sushi-gen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 21:06:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/sushi-gen/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of sushi, let alone uni, so I was highly recommended to go to this place near Little Tokyo for lunch a few months ago. Sushi Gen, from what I was told, is the central supplier for sushi restaurants across Los Angeles. How much truth there is to this, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care. I was told that the lunch specials and fish quality here were great for the price.</description></item></channel></rss>