<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>French on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/cuisine/french/</link><description>Recent content in French on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:20:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/cuisine/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>La Creperie De Paris</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-creperie-de-paris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:20:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-creperie-de-paris/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We entered Epcot around 10 AM on this Friday from the north end of the park, and we had to walk all the way down to the France pavilion to try and ride Remy. The unfortunate part when we got there was that the wait time had already exceeded 90 minutes. I checked my Disney World app, and low and behold, we could do lighting passes for $11 per person. That felt worthwhile to do and not bake under the sun. Right next door was this crepe restaurant that had no one inside, so we thought we&amp;rsquo;d grab some brunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Be Our Guest</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/be-our-guest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 17:43:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/be-our-guest/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Be Our Guest restaurant is located in the Magic Kingdom park in the Beauty &amp;amp; the Beast section. When you enter the main hall, it looks similar to the movie but not as grand as I thought it would&amp;rsquo;ve been. To the left is a dark room where you can see the rose with falling petals, and to the right where we ate was the kitchen room. We had our expectations set reasonably given that there will be lots of kids here. Lastly, everything was served a prix fix menu &amp;ndash; meaning we get 1 appetizer, 1 entree, and the trio of desserts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Topolino's Terrace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/topolino/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 15:25:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/topolino/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first restaurant we visited on our first trip together to Walt Disney World. Topolino&amp;rsquo;s Terrace is located on the 10th floor of the Riviera Resort in Walt Disney World. Outside on the patio, the resort pump&amp;rsquo;s French music which remind you that you are on vacation. While taking in that breath, you&amp;rsquo;re also viewing a breathtaking panorama of some parts of Disney World. There are some social distanced lounge seats that you can relax on while waiting for the restaurant to text you that your table is ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>