<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nyc on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in nyc on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cafe Olé</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and SVL Souvlaki Bar. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, Marta, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food.</description></item><item><title>Le Gratin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:22:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re in a mood of exploring some of the food places down near the Financial District. I was looking around, and there weren&amp;rsquo;t too many options. Le Gratin happened to be from renown chef, Daniel Boulud, so I figure this would be a safe choice. This is located right next to the Beekman Hotel, and there are entrances via the street or through the hotel. We easily made reservations for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Friday without much advance notice.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as Saga, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.</description></item><item><title>Chica &amp; the Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:49:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</guid><description>Chica &amp;amp; The Don is a new Latin restaurant that opened in the Flatiron district. Despite their Yelp site pointing to Flatbush, it really is located in Manhattan. When you walk in, the restaurant has a long corridor to the main dining area. They just opened 3 weeks ago, so I was interested in checking this out before the hype were to build up. We were able to make a reservation relatively easy for 5:45 PM on a Friday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Udon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:48:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</guid><description>I just have this affinity for noodles. Their sibling location, Okiboru House of Tsukemen, was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the city when it comes to dipping ramen. This restaurant recently opened up marketing itself for udon. Like their tsukemen location, this one offers udon for dipping. Unlike traditional udon, these noodles are much wider and flatter. I was able to walk in by myself at 8 PM on a Tuesday evening, and I immediately was seated.</description></item><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Class on 38th</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:21:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</guid><description>Class on 38th was something that seemed interesting at first glance when I was browsing the &amp;ldquo;Hot and New&amp;rdquo; sections of Yelp. The menu looked like tapas with a price point that wasn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. I went here with a business partner, who was in town and looking for something to try. I made a reservation a few weeks back without any issues for 6 PM on a Thursday. When I walked in, they allowed me to sit early to wait for my guest to arrive.</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.</description></item><item><title>Fer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:03:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/fer/</guid><description>Fer is a nearby neighborhood restaurant that has similar spicy features comparable to other Chinese restaurants around the area. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of little shops because it usually means you can get your food pretty fast, and it feels casual. We stopped by late Saturday afternoon, and there was hardly anyone there. We were seated right away, and the food came out very fast. The menu has a lot of chili oil in all of their items, but luckily the spice was tolerable when ordered mild.</description></item><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss.</description></item><item><title>Red Sorghum</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:50:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-sorghum/</guid><description>Red Sorghum has recently opened in Long Island City, and is yet another spicy Chinese restaurant. It seems that there are quite a few around Long Island City. This location replaced the closed Penny Bridge. Because this was really close to our place and we were meeting friends, we decided on this restaurant to try different dishes. They proud themselves in baijiu, which is China&amp;rsquo;s liquor to Korean soju. There are several cocktails made with them if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.</description></item><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends.</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me.</description></item><item><title>Chu Ros Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chu-ros-thai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 12:54:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chu-ros-thai/</guid><description>We haven&amp;rsquo;t really explored much from the middle of Central Park and up. My partner&amp;rsquo;s friends live in East Harlem, which according to Google maps, begins East 96th and goes north. They chose this neighborhood Thai restaurant, Chu Ros Thai, that they adore and highly recommend. We basically took the local 6 train northbound from the N/W junction, which took about 20 minutes to go up. For a party of 4, we were able to walk in without reservations at around 4 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Vinyl Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 12:51:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</guid><description>Vinyl Steakhouse has been a steak place that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go for quite some time. The Flatiron area has been experiencing many new restaurant openings post pandemic, and this was one of them that was appealing. Similar to Turntable Chicken Jazz, this restaurant has a load of vinyls on display, and it plays music as requested. We were able to walk in on a Friday around 6:30 PM without reservations for 2.</description></item><item><title>Frevo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</guid><description>Frevo was a restaurant that has been on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for some time. When we went to Atomix Bar, the chef had also highly recommended the restaurant. The head chef Franco Sampogna is Brazilian and comes from the region that my partner is from. The entrance to the restaurant has a very tiny art gallery, and it&amp;rsquo;s been recognized on the Michelin Guide with 1 star. We were able to reserve this a few weeks back without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The team that created this restaurant also helped create Don Angie, Quality Eats, Quality Italian, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item></channel></rss>