<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UES on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/ues/</link><description>Recent content in UES on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/ues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Le Veau d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</guid><description>Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;Or is French for &amp;ldquo;the golden calf&amp;rdquo;. Making reservations for 2 for this was incredibly difficult as it gets sniped the moment the reservations come up. Luckily I checked a random time, and I noticed there was some 5:00 PM slots opened on a Wednesday. This is one of the hottest restaurants in the city because it&amp;rsquo;s a revived restaurant from the Frenchette and Le Rock chef/owners, Lee Hanson and Riad Nasr.</description></item><item><title>Lolita's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 13:44:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</guid><description>We were out and about in Central Park taking pictures, and we were looking for a place to check out midday. This no-frills Mexican-like restaurant was near where we walked out of Central Park. We were a bit skeptical of this restaurant since the menu was on the smaller side, but we decided to give it a try. We were seated without reservations pretty easily around 1 PM on a Sunday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Aperitivo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aperitivo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 19:11:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aperitivo/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s yet another Friday, and my partner had to pick up some items around the southeast part of Central Park. This area is fairly close to the Plaza Hotel and the flagship Apple store. This restaurant was on my eyes for a while, but my partner hadn&amp;rsquo;t built their tolerance or appreciation for Italian food until recently. Fortunately, I finally had a chance to suggest this restaurant as our Friday getaway.</description></item><item><title>Piccola Cucina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 15:28:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Piccola Cucina other than that it&amp;rsquo;s real close to Bloomingdales in Midtown. When we tried to stop in at 5:30 PM as a walk-in many months ago, they told us there was a 2 hour wait. Since we knew today we were going to be around the area, I saw they had a few openings and quickly booked a reservation for 6 PM for 2. This review is for the Midtown Uptown location.</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 16:12:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</guid><description>We were in the Midtown area shopping yet again. The previous night we went to Serafina, which was pretty awful. Luckily we had more choices, and this restaurant was nearby. It caught my eye because it had a nice indoor patio area that was lit by natural light similarly to The Milling Room. The menu seemed reasonable as well as the price, so maybe there can be some value found here.</description></item><item><title>Mission Ceviche</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/mission-ceviche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 17:48:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/mission-ceviche/</guid><description>We had to go to the Upper East to return some items, and of course that allowed us to also explore some restaurants around that area. I recall Mission Ceviche having a stall in the Gainsvoort/Chelsea food hall, but I never actually tried it. They actually have a few locations in the city, and fortunately we were near their Upper East Side location. My partner is a ceviche fanatic, so we thought we&amp;rsquo;d take a look.</description></item><item><title>Jojo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 17:00:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</guid><description>This restaurant is very close to the Bloomingdales along Lexington in the Upper East side. Surprisingly it has been here for a while, but we seldom come to this neighborhood to grab food. It just so happens we were on an errand run, so my partner was able to grab an early reservation. This is one of the more price friendly restaurants of Jean Georges although it arguably is still on the pricy side.</description></item><item><title>Daikanyama</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/daikanyama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:24:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/daikanyama/</guid><description>We had walked over the Queensboro bridge to do some casual shopping at the Bloomingdales on Lexington on the Monday of a Memorial Day weekend. Surprisingly, there weren&amp;rsquo;t many people out and about probably due to people escaping town. Because this was around lunch time, we decided not to trek too far from the department store. This Japanese restaurant was connected indoors to the first floor of the department store. On the outside, they had private transparent glass huts with their own heaters, but we decided to eat indoors.</description></item><item><title>Smoke Jazz and Supper Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/smoke-jazz-and-supper-club/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 18:25:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/smoke-jazz-and-supper-club/</guid><description>Summary We came here on a date night to do the dinner and jazz thing. We purchased our tickets online, then head over. With the tickets, there&amp;rsquo;s a required minimum of 1 drink per person if you&amp;rsquo;re not having dinner, or if you are having dinner, there is a required 1 entree per person sans appetizer.
On this night, it was the Harold Mabern Trio.
The cocktails were ok. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, so I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember exactly what these were.</description></item><item><title>Uva</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/uva/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 16:20:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/uva/</guid><description>Summary This place is located in the Upper East, and arguably walkable from the MET.
The spiedino di gamberetti was OK to me. Nothing really memorable, but they gave you a decent amount of shrimp.
The antipasto misto was actually pretty good, and they gave a decent variety of meats and cheese. For 2 people, this was quite filling.
The pappardelle al ragu di vitello was good as expected. The pasta could have been cooked just a tad less, but the sauce it sat in was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Portugrill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 15:52:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</guid><description>Summary The food here was just like one of those casual fast food centric places. It&amp;rsquo;s on Seamless (food delivery service), so enough said.
The churrasco was $18 and was mildly satisfying. They gave you a decent amount of meat, and it was quite tender when ordered &amp;ldquo;medium rare&amp;rdquo;. It came with this mayonnaise like green sauce, that had only a mild kick to it. With this, I opted for french fries and pineapple on the side.</description></item><item><title>Boqueria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/boqueria/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 16:32:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/boqueria/</guid><description>Boqueria is an east coast Spanish tapas chain. The food here is quintessential Spanish shareables, including large paellas. We originally ate here with some friends in the Upper East, but we have also tried this restaurant in Flatiron. Reservations are fairly easy to secure, and it does get busy during core hours. If you have a decent sized party, this is probably a decent restaurant to bring folks that might be into family style sharing.</description></item><item><title>Flora Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flora-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:19:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flora-bar/</guid><description>Seafood centric. Ambience is good, but the food is eh.</description></item><item><title>Tal Bagels</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/tal-bagels/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:12:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/tal-bagels/</guid><description>Believe it or not, their pastrami was actually better than Pastrami Queen.</description></item><item><title>Pastrami Queen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/pastrami-queen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:05:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/pastrami-queen/</guid><description>Pretty good pastrami. It&amp;rsquo;s no Katz, and it&amp;rsquo;s not filling, but it was good. It&amp;rsquo;s thin sliced meats.</description></item><item><title>Grazie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/grazie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:49:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/grazie/</guid><description>I only ate here because it was close to the MET. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what I had, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only written that it was good.</description></item></channel></rss>