<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Natal on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/neighborhood/natal/</link><description>Recent content in Natal on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/neighborhood/natal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Curió</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:04:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</guid><description>Curio is a local bar restaurant around where we were staying. My partner wanted to meet their friends locally here since it was new to them, and in the evenings, it appeared to be a very happening place. We were able to walk in for 4 people at around 6 PM without any issues. We had the option of sitting right in the outdoor area in front of the restaurant with security guards around, but we opted to sit inside toward the back.</description></item><item><title>Zeh Cozinha</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:59:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</guid><description>Zeh Cozinha is located in the Midway shopping mall in Natal. It&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a local restaurant with many options of steak or seafood. The price is not too expensive for locals, and this restaurant is competing for business against Camarões and Outback in the same level of the shopping mall. Along with the foods, it also has a decent selection of drinks. We were really excited to try this restaurant out to get a feel for what&amp;rsquo;s a popular local restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Camarões</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:53:44 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</guid><description>Camarões is a very popular seafood restaurant which got its start in Natal, Brazil. If you meet anyone from this northeast region, they will say they love this restaurant. My partner has been talking about this since day 1 that I met them. Now, I have the opportunity to try this out to see what the rave is all about. Camarões has since expanded to more locations in Natal, as well as a location in São Paulo city, which is a food mecca for Brazilians.</description></item></channel></rss>