<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Natal on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/neighborhood/natal/</link><description>Recent content in Natal on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:44:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/neighborhood/natal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sal E Brasa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/sal-e-brasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:44:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/sal-e-brasa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sal-e-brasa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sal e Brasa is a Brazilian churrascaria (steakhouse) chain that has all-you-can-eat meats, salads, and foods. In the outside, you can see these gigantic ribs on spits rotating. I have no idea if those were real, but they were pretty cool. We were able to walk in with seating for a party of 6 very easily in the middle of the afternoon. This was going to be our last meal before we head back to the U.S., and I was worried if I was going to get full fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nau</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nau/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:10:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/nau/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nau%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nau is a nicer seafood restaurant that also has several locations in Brazil. Many families come here to celebrate weddings or other moments. This restaurant is located in an area near the technology university, and it has a parking lot. We were able to walk in with a party of 4 without reservations easily around 7 PM local time. The moment you step in, the decor felt quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lotus</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/lotus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:09:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/lotus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lotus%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to try some less authentic Brazilian food, and we received a recommendation from a friend to try out this place. They mentioned they were very impressed by the quality of the fish and felt it would meet our expectations, especially for sushi. This was one of the few Asian-centric restaurants in Natal. We were able to walk in around 7:00 PM here without any reservations. To our surprise, there were plenty of seats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dobradinha Do Lucas</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dobradinha-do-lucas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:06:59 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/dobradinha-do-lucas/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/dobradinha-do-lucas%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dobradinha do Lucas literally translates to &amp;ldquo;Tripe of Lucas&amp;rdquo;. Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re coming here to eat tripe. My partner had been a frequent visitor to this restaurant during their university days, and they decided to bring me here to give this a shot. The area is a little sketchy, but we came here mid-day when there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of traffic or people. We sat outside along in their half covered patio on plastic tables and seats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Curio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:04:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/curio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/curio%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curio is a local bar restaurant around where we were staying. My partner wanted to meet their friends locally here since it was new to them, and in the evenings, it appeared to be a very happening place. We were able to walk in for 4 people at around 6 PM without any issues. We had the option of sitting right in the outdoor area in front of the restaurant with security guards around, but we opted to sit inside toward the back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zeh Cozinha</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:59:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/zeh-cozinha/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/zeh-cozinha%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zeh Cozinha is located in the Midway shopping mall in Natal. It&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a local restaurant with many options of steak or seafood. The price is not too expensive for locals, and this restaurant is competing for business against Camar천es and Outback in the same level of the shopping mall. Along with the foods, it also has a decent selection of drinks. We were really excited to try this restaurant out to get a feel for what&amp;rsquo;s a popular local restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Camaroes</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 09:53:44 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/camaroes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/camaroes%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camar천es is a very popular seafood restaurant which got its start in Natal, Brazil. If you meet anyone from this northeast region, they will say they love this restaurant. My partner has been talking about this since day 1 that I met them. Now, I have the opportunity to try this out to see what the rave is all about. Camar천es has since expanded to more locations in Natal, as well as a location in S찾o Paulo city, which is a food mecca for Brazilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>