<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Midtown East on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-east/</link><description>Recent content in Midtown East on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:45:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-east/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benjamin Steakhouse Prime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:45:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/benjamin-steakhouse-prime%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restaurant Week is notorious for it&amp;rsquo;s multi-course offerings that feature items that aren&amp;rsquo;t on their respective restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menus. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun tip. Steak places are typically a really good bang for the buck as they typically offer you things on their menu. As a way to chill out and celebrate solo, I went to Benjamin Prime. I walked in on a Friday around 4:30 PM without any issues alone. They asked if I wanted a table for 1 or sit at a bar, and I asked for a table which they accommodated. This location is a very close walking distance from Bryant Park.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:20:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/raon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raon is a new Korean tasting restaurant from Chef Soogil Lim and his wife, Sasook Youn. Their other restaurant, Soogil, is located in the East Village, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to open a more intimate fine dining type of restaurant. One of the key features that attracted me to this was that they would a tasting menu centered around kimchi. When we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, we simply adored it. So we wanted to see how this would compare because both restaurants emphasize that kimchi is a key part of the experience. I was able to book a 5:00 PM reservation for a Saturday without much issue. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s because the restaurant is still fairly new. The restaurant is very close to the N/W train off of Lexington and Bloomingdales.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monkey-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/"&gt;Au Cheval&lt;/a&gt; and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-delbianco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss. The prices seemed reasonable, so we decided to try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monterey%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me. We were able to make a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday night with no hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St. You can&amp;rsquo;t miss it because there&amp;rsquo;s a carpet laid out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Olle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 20:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/olle%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you visit sample sales frequently, there are 2 nearby the Nomad and Koreatown area. Because the sample sales close at 7 PM sharp, it compels you to look for food during core dinner hours. Fortunately if you go shop right after work and finish around 6 PM on weekdays, foot traffic to restaurants won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Olle is a Korean restaurant about a block away from the sample sale store on 5th Ave. We were able to walk in with no reservations at around 5:30 PM, which the restaurant started coincidentally getting busy around 6 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Okdongsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:37:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/okdongsik%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is from a renowned Korean chef (Ok Dongsik) and is a 6 time &lt;a href="https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/seoul-capital-area/kr-seoul/restaurant/okdongsik"&gt;Michelin Seoul Bib Gourmand restaurant&lt;/a&gt;. We were nearby at a popular sample sale, and this was on my list for a while to checkout. The menu is very small and is straight forward. We were able to walk in at around 6:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without reservation. They turn over seats fairly quickly even though there can easily be a line of people waiting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tempura-matsui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/"&gt;Secchu Yokota&lt;/a&gt;. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant. It was very easy to make reservations for one person the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ophelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 16:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ophelia%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ophelia is a cocktail bar located in Midtown East near 1st Ave and 50th. It&amp;rsquo;s located at the top of Beekman Tower. This was built in 1928, and it was originally known as the Panhellenic Tower. The bar and hotel originally served as a womens-only club and hotel space for Greek sororities. When you walk into the lobby of the hotel, take the middle elevator to the 26th floor for entrance. We did have to make reservations ahead of time, but they are pretty easy to procure weeks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empell칩n</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:54:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/empellon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we were again running some errands in this Midtown East area close to Central Park. We are running a bit dry on Italian options, so fortunately my partner finally said &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to a Mexican restaurant that I have wanted to go to for a long time. I vaguely recall Empell칩n having a Michelin Star a while back, but I cannot find any information on it at this time. I even asked ChatGPT, and they thought it had received a star in the Michelin 2019 NYC guide. Regardless, I have wanted to come here to try their infamous dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aquavit%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have &lt;strong&gt;2 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/"&gt;Aska&lt;/a&gt; recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>T치n</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:45:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner saw this restaurant on their Instagram feed, and since it&amp;rsquo;s a new Mexican restaurant, we thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to check out. I know absolutely nothing about the Chef Richard Sandoval and Chef Jonat치n Gomez Luna Torres, but the menu looked pretty interesting and looks like it can bring an upscale experience and taste of Mexican cuisine. We were able to get 5 PM reservation easily on a Thursday evening, and they still have not gotten their liquor license by our visit tonight. That&amp;rsquo;s fine because they do offer mocktails, which I am a huge fan of in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Reading Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:37:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-reading-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reading Room is a restaurant that caught my eye on Yelp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New and Hot&amp;rdquo; list. The menu is fairly small, simple, but seemed like it could be a good one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for restaurants around my work area that I could potentially refer others for drinks or a not too expensive dinner. This restaurant is located in the back of The Gotham Hotel on 46th between Madison and Fifth Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system &lt;a href="https://www.tock.com"&gt;Tock&lt;/a&gt;. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week. I quickly made the reservation, and then ultimately decided to keep both the bar tasting and the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting reservations. This post will be for the Atomix Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter menu. To read about the Atomix Bar tasting experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix. This one is about the bar. To read the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Crab House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:14:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot recall the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve cracked open crab shells and eaten a huge chunk of crab meat. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a lot of seafood buffets, and they would always have a plethora of snow crab legs that you could eat for hours on end. We decided today to venture out to this all you can eat seafood buffet in the city. We were able to walk in with no reservations for 2 around 5:30 PM on a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Izakaya Toribar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:44:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people say Manhattan has practically endless restaurants, it&amp;rsquo;s quite true. There&amp;rsquo;s not enough time, money, and health to try all the different restaurants out there. For this visit into the city, we decided to go after yakitori since that was fairly close around the area we were at. We have had previously been to Torishin, a former Michelin 1-star, so I wanted to show my partner different yakitori places that were less upscaled. This one looked like a good candidate. This restaurant, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the outdoors setup, would&amp;rsquo;ve been a little difficult to spot because it&amp;rsquo;s in the basement of a building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nerai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:32:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, we were fortunate to book this restaurant in Midtown East at the very last minute. This was always on our list since outdoor dining was a thing as the pictures of its settings looked quite appealing. Most tables have their own electric heater that sat directly above the table, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too cold compared to other places. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, it was in the high 30s with some wind chills. We did dress warmer just in case though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ravagh</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 14:13:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the other cuisines in NYC, Persian food is not something that we actively seek out. However, we often are around this area shopping at the now-closed Bed Bath &amp;amp; Beyond and tend to look for restaurants that are very close. This restaurant was something we surprisingly haven&amp;rsquo;t tried, so we checked it out. I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t had Persian food since I moved from LA back in 2016, so I am curious to relive those moments again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Allora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 19:34:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was our second anniversary, and it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat difficult to find a decent restaurant that has an outdoor garden that is away from the crowd. After staying up till 4 AM looking for one, I finally found one that was decent. The garden seating area is actually in the back of the restaurant, so there&amp;rsquo;s very little foot traffic from random people. Luckily the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t hot at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kaoru</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kaoru/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 15:39:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kaoru/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is basically chirashi haven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kaoru%2F1_miso_soup.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;miso soup&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kaoru%2F2_uni_don.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;uni don&lt;/strong&gt; came with hamachi and spicy tuna and shiso leaf. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a fan of the spicy tuna compared to some other places, but it was still pretty good. The spicy tuna had a very particular flavor that was masked of course when you use soy sauce with wasabi. Otherwise, the fish tasted pretty fresh overall. The &lt;em&gt;butter of the sea&lt;/em&gt; was delicious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empire Steak House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 14:10:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were looking for a decent steak place that was walkable from where we were. The best steak house in my opinion in the city is Keen&amp;rsquo;s Steakhouse, so expectations were set pretty low. This venue is fairly nice. It&amp;rsquo;s close to Smith and Wollensky and located inside some hotel. This was one of the few steakhouses at this time that had hardly any people, so one can only think that this place wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nonono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nonono%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonono is a restaurant from the people behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/her-name-is-han/"&gt;Her Name is Han&lt;/a&gt;. This is located just a few blocks from Korea town. They are part of the &lt;a href="https://www.handhospitality.com/"&gt;Hand Hospitality&lt;/a&gt; network, which also includes &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atoboy/"&gt;Atoboy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cho-dang-gol/"&gt;Cho Dang Gol&lt;/a&gt;, and many more. The restaurant offers Japanese grill cuisine with a twist. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the restaurant several times, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a decent value and choice for any small gatherings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambiance feels like a normal Japanese restaurant where there was a lot of activity. The tables are relatively close to each other, so it can get a little tight. However, it was fine talking to your party, so the sound acoustics were good. They have both a floor table area and a second floor area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bap</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:47:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food here was surprisingly decent. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t expect many places in Midtown East to be good, let alone Asian ethnic foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bap%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered a pineapple &lt;strong&gt;Mocktail&lt;/strong&gt; and a glass of &lt;strong&gt;Hite&lt;/strong&gt;, which is nothing to write home about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bap%2F2_banchan.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;banchan&lt;/strong&gt; here was pretty good, although portion size is on the smaller side. You can ask for additional banchan as needed. Here you got kimchi, mixed salad, jalapenos, pickled cauliflower, pickled daikon cubes, and pickled daikon slices. For sauces, you got some soy sauce centric thing that I never remember the name of, salt and pepper, and bean paste. On the top you have fresh large lettuce leaves for wrapping.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paname</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 23:49:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of brunch at all, so this was the first restaurant in the area I was in that seemed interesting to me. I completely forgot it was Easter Sunday, but luckily their prixe fix menu had all the regulars on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/paname%2F1_bread.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;bread&lt;/strong&gt; was nothing to write home about. It came slightly on the cold side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/paname%2F2_escargots.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;escargots de bourgogne in baby potatoes&lt;/strong&gt; were actually pretty good. Albeit slightly salty in some bites, they tasted better than the other appetizers on the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kung Fu Little Steamed Buns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/kung-fu-little-steamed-buns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 19:02:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/kung-fu-little-steamed-buns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good XLB. Was flavorful, BUT the price is pretty expensive for what you get. The dessert XLB filled with nutella/banana was gimmicky but tasted good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kung-fu-little-steamed-buns%2F1_xlb.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Baked by Melissa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/baked-by-melissa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:45:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/baked-by-melissa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;These are super tiny one bite mini cupcakes. Pretty good though the flavor profiles aren&amp;rsquo;t that different from each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Strip House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/strip-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:57:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/strip-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Steak was just OK. Service was slow as hell. Truffle cream of spinach was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>American Cut</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/american-cut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:56:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/american-cut/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent for the price. This is Marc Forgione&amp;rsquo;s steak house.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>212 Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/212-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:54:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/212-steakhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, this place is the only legit place in NYC that has real kobe certified beef from Japan. It was delicious and cheap&amp;hellip; with the groupon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Grand Central Oyster Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/grand-central-oyster-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:30:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/grand-central-oyster-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Grand Central Oyster Bar is a pretty famous spot in New York City located in the Grand Central Terminal off of 42nd St. This is the central train hub that people take to go towards upstate New York and beyond such as Connecticut. I had been here a while back, but this would be the first time for my partner. What better way is there other than to grab some oysters before jumping on a train back home. This location is at the lower level right close to the dining concourse and right next to the 4 columns that has a distinct sound acoustics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momosan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:32:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momosan-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ok. Broth is not great, but tuna bowl is good. I think this restaurant is owned by Morimoto.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Macchina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/macchina/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:26:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/macchina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;They are known on Instagram for their Burrata pizza which was about $25. It was ok. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go out of my way to get it because it literally is just a margarita style pizza with a big piece of burrata cheese in the middle. The burrata wasn&amp;rsquo;t that soft when cut for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fine and Rare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been here a few times already, so this is now a proper post for it. This is a Jazzy restaurant that you can dine-in without paying a cover which is nice. The jazz itself is pretty fun, although predictable if you don&amp;rsquo;t listen to a special guest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fine-and-rare%2F1_blackberry_gimlet.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;strong&gt;blackberry gimlet&lt;/strong&gt; which has reyka vodka, fresh blackberries, and fresh lime. It was pretty good, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Her Name Is Han</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/her-name-is-han/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:58:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/her-name-is-han/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good Korean food. Fairly priced and family style. They have BOSSAM, and it was really good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tonkatsu Matsunoya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tonkatsu-matsunoya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:36:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tonkatsu-matsunoya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is pretty bomb and NO TIP NEEDED! Would come back here again. The crust was really good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Relais De Venise L'entrecote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:08:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This review is for the Midtown East location of Le Relais De Venise L&amp;rsquo;entrecote. The previous review I had was for the &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/le-relais-de-venise-l-entrecote-new-york-3"&gt;closed SOHO location&lt;/a&gt;, which I was complaining that they charged $5.50 for tap water back in 2018. Fast forward about 3 years later post pandemic, how does this location fare compared to the previous one? I will say much better. Note that this location did not appear to charge for tap water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Zaiya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/cafe-zaiya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:14:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/cafe-zaiya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent black sesame bubble milk tea with red bean dessert bakery stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>