<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Midtown East on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-east/</link><description>Recent content in Midtown East on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-east/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss.</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me.</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item><item><title>Olle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 20:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</guid><description>If you visit sample sales frequently, there are 2 nearby the Nomad and Koreatown area. Because the sample sales close at 7 PM sharp, it compels you to look for food during core dinner hours. Fortunately if you go shop right after work and finish around 6 PM on weekdays, foot traffic to restaurants won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Olle is a Korean restaurant about a block away from the sample sale store on 5th Ave.</description></item><item><title>Okdongsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:37:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</guid><description>This restaurant is from a renowned Korean chef (Ok Dongsik) and is a 6 time Michelin Seoul Bib Gourmand restaurant. We were nearby at a popular sample sale, and this was on my list for a while to checkout. The menu is very small and is straight forward. We were able to walk in at around 6:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without reservation. They turn over seats fairly quickly even though there can easily be a line of people waiting.</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at Secchu Yokota. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Ophelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 16:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</guid><description>Ophelia is a cocktail bar located in Midtown East near 1st Ave and 50th. It&amp;rsquo;s located at the top of Beekman Tower. This was built in 1928, and it was originally known as the Panhellenic Tower. The bar and hotel originally served as a womens-only club and hotel space for Greek sororities. When you walk into the lobby of the hotel, take the middle elevator to the 26th floor for entrance.</description></item><item><title>Empell칩n</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:54:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</guid><description>As usual, we were again running some errands in this Midtown East area close to Central Park. We are running a bit dry on Italian options, so fortunately my partner finally said &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to a Mexican restaurant that I have wanted to go to for a long time. I vaguely recall Empell칩n having a Michelin Star a while back, but I cannot find any information on it at this time.</description></item><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have 2 Michelin Stars, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, Aska recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.</description></item><item><title>T치n</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:45:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</guid><description>My partner saw this restaurant on their Instagram feed, and since it&amp;rsquo;s a new Mexican restaurant, we thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to check out. I know absolutely nothing about the Chef Richard Sandoval and Chef Jonat치n Gomez Luna Torres, but the menu looked pretty interesting and looks like it can bring an upscale experience and taste of Mexican cuisine. We were able to get 5 PM reservation easily on a Thursday evening, and they still have not gotten their liquor license by our visit tonight.</description></item><item><title>The Reading Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:37:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</guid><description>The Reading Room is a restaurant that caught my eye on Yelp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New and Hot&amp;rdquo; list. The menu is fairly small, simple, but seemed like it could be a good one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for restaurants around my work area that I could potentially refer others for drinks or a not too expensive dinner. This restaurant is located in the back of The Gotham Hotel on 46th between Madison and Fifth Avenue.</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system Tock. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week.</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix.</description></item><item><title>Crab House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:14:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</guid><description>I cannot recall the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve cracked open crab shells and eaten a huge chunk of crab meat. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a lot of seafood buffets, and they would always have a plethora of snow crab legs that you could eat for hours on end. We decided today to venture out to this all you can eat seafood buffet in the city. We were able to walk in with no reservations for 2 around 5:30 PM on a Friday.</description></item><item><title>Izakaya Toribar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:44:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</guid><description>Summary When people say Manhattan has practically endless restaurants, it&amp;rsquo;s quite true. There&amp;rsquo;s not enough time, money, and health to try all the different restaurants out there. For this visit into the city, we decided to go after yakitori since that was fairly close around the area we were at. We have had previously been to Torishin, a former Michelin 1-star, so I wanted to show my partner different yakitori places that were less upscaled.</description></item><item><title>Nerai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:32:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</guid><description>Summary For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, we were fortunate to book this restaurant in Midtown East at the very last minute. This was always on our list since outdoor dining was a thing as the pictures of its settings looked quite appealing. Most tables have their own electric heater that sat directly above the table, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too cold compared to other places. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, it was in the high 30s with some wind chills.</description></item><item><title>Ravagh</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 14:13:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ravagh/</guid><description>Summary Unlike the other cuisines in NYC, Persian food is not something that we actively seek out. However, we often are around this area shopping at the now-closed Bed Bath &amp;amp; Beyond and tend to look for restaurants that are very close. This restaurant was something we surprisingly haven&amp;rsquo;t tried, so we checked it out. I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t had Persian food since I moved from LA back in 2016, so I am curious to relive those moments again.</description></item><item><title>Allora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 19:34:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</guid><description>Summary Today was our second anniversary, and it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat difficult to find a decent restaurant that has an outdoor garden that is away from the crowd. After staying up till 4 AM looking for one, I finally found one that was decent. The garden seating area is actually in the back of the restaurant, so there&amp;rsquo;s very little foot traffic from random people. Luckily the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t hot at all.</description></item><item><title>Kaoru</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kaoru/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 15:39:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kaoru/</guid><description>Summary This place is basically chirashi haven.
It&amp;rsquo;s miso soup.
The uni don came with hamachi and spicy tuna and shiso leaf. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a fan of the spicy tuna compared to some other places, but it was still pretty good. The spicy tuna had a very particular flavor that was masked of course when you use soy sauce with wasabi. Otherwise, the fish tasted pretty fresh overall.</description></item><item><title>Empire Steak House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 14:10:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</guid><description>Summary We were looking for a decent steak place that was walkable from where we were. The best steak house in my opinion in the city is Keen&amp;rsquo;s Steakhouse, so expectations were set pretty low. This venue is fairly nice. It&amp;rsquo;s close to Smith and Wollensky and located inside some hotel. This was one of the few steakhouses at this time that had hardly any people, so one can only think that this place wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that good.</description></item><item><title>Nonono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</guid><description>Nonono is a restaurant from the people behind Her Name is Han. This is located just a few blocks from Korea town. They are part of the Hand Hospitality network, which also includes Atoboy, Cho Dang Gol, and many more. The restaurant offers Japanese grill cuisine with a twist. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the restaurant several times, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a decent value and choice for any small gatherings.
Ambiance &amp;amp; Service The ambiance feels like a normal Japanese restaurant where there was a lot of activity.</description></item><item><title>Bap</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:47:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bap/</guid><description>Summary The food here was surprisingly decent. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t expect many places in Midtown East to be good, let alone Asian ethnic foods.
We ordered a pineapple Mocktail and a glass of Hite, which is nothing to write home about.
The banchan here was pretty good, although portion size is on the smaller side. You can ask for additional banchan as needed. Here you got kimchi, mixed salad, jalapenos, pickled cauliflower, pickled daikon cubes, and pickled daikon slices.</description></item><item><title>Paname</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 23:49:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of brunch at all, so this was the first restaurant in the area I was in that seemed interesting to me. I completely forgot it was Easter Sunday, but luckily their prixe fix menu had all the regulars on it.
The bread was nothing to write home about. It came slightly on the cold side.
The escargots de bourgogne in baby potatoes were actually pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Kung Fu Little Steamed Buns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/kung-fu-little-steamed-buns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 19:02:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/kung-fu-little-steamed-buns/</guid><description>Good XLB. Was flavorful, BUT the price is pretty expensive for what you get. The dessert XLB filled with nutella/banana was gimmicky but tasted good.</description></item><item><title>Baked by Melissa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/baked-by-melissa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:45:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/baked-by-melissa/</guid><description>These are super tiny one bite mini cupcakes. Pretty good though the flavor profiles aren&amp;rsquo;t that different from each other.</description></item></channel></rss>