<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michelin (1) on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-1/</link><description>Recent content in Michelin (1) on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Musket Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</guid><description>The Musket Room has been around for a while, and it is located close to the Broadway/Lafayette train in Manhattan. Chef Mary Attea is the head chef of this restaurant, and according to the Michelin Guide, the kitchen is predominantly women. We picked this restaurant to try for tonight primarily because the menu looked like a slightly different take on New American than what we were used to. I was easily able to book a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance.</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as Saga, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.</description></item><item><title>Frevo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</guid><description>Frevo was a restaurant that has been on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for some time. When we went to Atomix Bar, the chef had also highly recommended the restaurant. The head chef Franco Sampogna is Brazilian and comes from the region that my partner is from. The entrance to the restaurant has a very tiny art gallery, and it&amp;rsquo;s been recognized on the Michelin Guide with 1 star. We were able to reserve this a few weeks back without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Torien</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 15:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</guid><description>As a Christmas celebration before we embark on a trip, I wanted to knock this final yakitori tasting off the list. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to a slew of yakitori tasting places, and this is the last one that is on the higher end. Torien still has 1 Michelin Star in 2023, and it also has a sister 1 Michelin Star restaurant, Torishiki, in Tokyo Japan. We were able to make a reservation for this for a Saturday a few weeks back without issues.</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.
The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.</description></item><item><title>Bōm</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:29:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</guid><description>Bom is a restaurant located in the back room of its sibling restaurant, Oiji Mi. We had been to that before, and I thought it was pretty decent. Bom was always on my list of things to try, but at $295 per person, I was pretty hesitant and skeptical. This restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a Michelin Star yet. Since reservations are fairly easy and Oiji Mi was pretty good, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this a try since we were celebrating two major milestones in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at Secchu Yokota. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Jua</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 18:54:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</guid><description>Jua is one of those new-ish Korean restaurants that has received a number of praises from all sorts of diners. I was able to get a 2-seater a few days before Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day on a Saturday evening. It did require me to sit and snipe on Resy, which fortunately was not as difficult as trying to get reservations at Don Angie. Jua is a restaurant by chef Hoyoung Kim, who was the former executive chef of Jungsik.</description></item><item><title>Oiji Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:04:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</guid><description>I read about Oiji Mi somewhere, and my gourmand syndrome was kicking in since I felt like I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a prix fixe upper end restaurant in a while. Oiji Mi is relatively new, and it comes from the owners of the original East Village&amp;rsquo;s Oiji. It offers creative contemporary Korean dining composed uniquely for NYC. I saw that they offer a 5 course tasting menu for $125 per person, and the menu looked quite interesting.</description></item><item><title>Contra</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:24:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</guid><description>It was my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and they had asked for my partner to make a reservation to a Michelin Star restaurant that was not overwhelmingly expensive (&amp;lt; $120 per person before wine). My partner started looking for more contemporary cuisines, and stumbled onto this which was a bit below the radar of restaurants. I remembered looking at the menu a while back, and nothing really struck me as a must-have &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to trying to prove myself wrong.</description></item><item><title>Don Angie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</guid><description>Summary This restaurant had been on my peripheral for a while because of the lasagna dish. I didn&amp;rsquo;t decide to try to book a reservation until I learned it was awarded its first ever Michelin Star. I had tried a few times on Resy, but always missed it. Fortunately, I was able to land a reservation on a weekend at 5 PM EST. The restaurant itself is in West Village and felt like a typical trendy cafe in the area.</description></item><item><title>Cote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:00:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</guid><description>Summary Indoor dining finally opened again in NYC on September 30, 2020. There are those that feel it&amp;rsquo;s reckless in this COVID temperament, but we still decided to celebrate by booking an indoor reservation at Cote, a 1 Michelin Star Korean BBQ restaurant. Normally, this is difficult to get a reasonable time, so we were happy it was not too bad. Like all upscale restaurants, they take your temperature via the forehead, and each table is partitioned by a plastic partition.</description></item><item><title>Aldea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:31:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Portuguese food other than the pastels, so this is the first for me. This special occasion was for a birthday and to try out a different type of cuisine that is largely not as popular as the mainstream French or Asian themed Michelin Star restaurants.
We got the tasting menu with wine pairing. The hosts were very nice in that we mentioned we&amp;rsquo;d like to just have wine pairing for 1 person and not the other, so that we can share since we&amp;rsquo;re not big drinkers.</description></item><item><title>Oxomoco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 23:50:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</guid><description>Summary This apparently received a coveted 1 Michelin Star at this time of writing.
Went here for brunch, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to go back to try the dinner. Just like Casa Enrique, I find it pretty good but pricey for what you get.
The horchata was tasty, but does not beat those horchata machines back in LA. Also, it was loaded with ice, so the amount of liquid you get is pretty small for $6.</description></item><item><title>Hirohisa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 17:05:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</guid><description>Summary Hirohisa apparently has been around for a while, but they just received a Michelin star again this year.
With that in mind, I felt the price point $160 pp for the 9-course tasting + $70 sake pairing was a decent price for splurging for a special someone&amp;rsquo;s birthday dinner.
Just a note: they do respect some allergy restrictions. My guest had lobster specific allergies, and they were able to accomodate easy.</description></item><item><title>Delaware and Hudson</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:08:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</guid><description>2016 and 2017 Michelin 1 star. Tasting only for dinner. Atlantic food. Fantastic.</description></item><item><title>Casa Enrique</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:49:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</guid><description>Summary I had been to this Michelin 1 star restaurant with a friend for brunch. We were underwhelmed as we&amp;rsquo;ve been to several Mexican restaurants in Southern California. My partner hasn&amp;rsquo;t tried this before, so I thought to give it another shot for dinner. Note that the restaurant does not take reservations. We were able to walk in at 5 PM on a Saturday evening and be seated indoors right away.</description></item><item><title>Casa Mono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:06:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</guid><description>I had stumbled drunk here back in 2018 not realizing it was a Michelin restaurant. Fortunately, it was on our list to come back to have a more proper dinner where our memory would still function. Our friends wanted a taste of a Michelin type of experience, and in lieu of a tasting menu, we opted for a more shareable format. Reservations are fairly easy to come by, so on a Sunday night, the restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t super full at 5 PM.</description></item></channel></rss>