<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New American on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/cuisine/new-american/</link><description>Recent content in New American on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/cuisine/new-american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Makahiki (Dinner)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-dinner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 17:02:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/makahiki-dinner/</guid><description>Makahiki is a restaurant that is located on the first floor of the Disney Aulani resort. The restaurant actually serves breakfast and dinner at 2 different times, so this review will be for the dinner portion. Unlike breakfast, there was less of a crowd for dinner, so we were able to walk in with our reservations very quickly. We were seated in the outdoor section under the covered patio around 5:00 PM, which was when the sun started setting.</description></item><item><title>Ama Ama</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ama-ama/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 18:32:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/ama-ama/</guid><description>To get our gourmand fix in, we booked &amp;lsquo;Ama&amp;rsquo;Ama as our fine dining Disney Aulani reservation. The price for this four course tasting was $125 per person. The menu offers contemporary island cuisine, which has many local flavors. The restaurant iself was designed to resemble a beachside house, and it&amp;rsquo;s located next to the Waikolohe Valley pool area, just a few steps from the beach. The whole restaurant has a very nice open and chill vibe.</description></item><item><title>Bar Māze</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 17:31:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/bar-maze/</guid><description>For our last day in the Waikiki/Honolulu area before we head over to the western part of Oahu for Aulani, we decided to splurge on something a little nicer to eat. Of all the choices we had, we decided on this Bar Māze place that the internet had raved about. The dining room is quite small, and when we entered, we were seated at the counter. We noticed that many of the cooks were quite young, but they were also very professional with a lot of attention on making sure the food is cooked right.</description></item></channel></rss>