<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flatiron on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/flatiron/</link><description>Recent content in Flatiron on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/flatiron/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gallery by Odo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/the-gallery-by-odo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 14:06:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/the-gallery-by-odo/</guid><description>The Gallery by odo is a fusion of a restaurant and art space in the Flatiron area. It&amp;rsquo;s actually right next door to the odo restaurant and bar. I was easily able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:15 PM a few days in advance. When we walked in, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think much of it as an art space. It does have some paintings of outdoor forests hung up on walls and also what appears to be a for-sale dinnerware selection on a table.</description></item><item><title>odo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/odo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 20:29:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/odo/</guid><description>Odo is a Michelin 2-star restaurant located in the Flatiron district of Manhattan. It comes from Chef Hiroki Odo, who moved to New York in 2012 and won a Michelin Star as the head chef at Kajitsu. We looked on the Michelin guide, and we saw this was a 2-star restaurant that we haven&amp;rsquo;t been to yet. We were able to make a reservation for 2 for 6 PM on a Sunday night without issues.</description></item><item><title>Time and Tide</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</guid><description>Time and Tide comes from the Kent Hospitality Group, which owns restaurants such as Saga and Crown Shy. The head chef, Top Chef winner Danny Garcia, overhauled the menu recently, and we got a chance to experience it. The restaurant was inspired to be a steakhouse modeled fish restaurant. I was easily able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night because the restaurant snipers have moved onto newer restaurants.</description></item><item><title>La Tete d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:54:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</guid><description>La Tête d&amp;rsquo;Or by Daniel is a tribute to timeless flavors and traditions with infusion of French flavors. What attracted me with this restaurant was that chef Daniel Boulud has a pretty decent track record of delivering good refined flavors. We went to Le Gratin previously, and we were very impressed by the taste of everything. As usual because he also holds some type of celebrity status, this restaurant is located in a posh area very close to Eleven Madison.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Zaffri</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:45:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</guid><description>Cafe Zaffri has been opened for just a week and are going through an early preview of their menu. The executive Chef Mary Attea heads the menu by tapping into her Lebanese roots and incorporating Levantine flavors into a modern menu. Along with the Chef, owners Jennifer and Nicole Vitagliano also came from The Musket Room. We were able to make a reservation for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day at 5:30 PM just a few days before because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet been fully discovered by the populous.</description></item><item><title>Hawksmoor</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/hawksmoor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:52:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/hawksmoor/</guid><description>Hawksmoor is a London restaurant that has a few other locations in the U.S. This is the first New York City location. In the UK, Hawksmoor is known for its food integrity, drinks, and visually appealing dining areas. They claim they have found the perfect way to cook steaks. One of the biggest appeals for me was they have a &amp;ldquo;Sunday Roast&amp;rdquo;, which is supposed to be a heavy Sunday meal.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Carmellini</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:26:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</guid><description>For Thanksgiving, we decided to try Cafe Carmellini out because their menu seemed pretty decent and had offerings that were present on their normal menu. My partner is a fan of turkey, so I already know what they were going to get. We made a reservation for 12 PM on Thanksgiving with no issues at all. When we walked in, they had us sit at the bar as they were preparing for Thanksgiving service.</description></item><item><title>Giorgio's of Gramercy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 21:51:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</guid><description>In our quest to find all the &amp;ldquo;Baked Alaska&amp;rdquo; restaurants in NYC, this was one that I was surprised to have it priced reasonably. Looking at the menu, everything was affordable compared to the rest of Manhattan. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest that I have never heard of this restaurant, and this came up randomly in my search. We easily made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday.</description></item><item><title>The Clocktower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 19:39:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</guid><description>The Clocktower has been on my list for a while and was a former 1 Michelin Star restaurant a few years ago. I ended up circling back to this restaurant because we&amp;rsquo;re desiring to eat as many baked Alaska places as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how many permutations of this dessert exists. We were able to book a reservation for 2 for a Friday evening without issue. The restaurant is located inside The Edison hotel on the second floor.</description></item><item><title>Chica &amp; the Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:49:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</guid><description>Chica &amp;amp; The Don is a new Latin restaurant that opened in the Flatiron district. Despite their Yelp site pointing to Flatbush, it really is located in Manhattan. When you walk in, the restaurant has a long corridor to the main dining area. They just opened 3 weeks ago, so I was interested in checking this out before the hype were to build up. We were able to make a reservation relatively easy for 5:45 PM on a Friday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Vinyl Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 12:51:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</guid><description>Vinyl Steakhouse has been a steak place that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go for quite some time. The Flatiron area has been experiencing many new restaurant openings post pandemic, and this was one of them that was appealing. Similar to Turntable Chicken Jazz, this restaurant has a load of vinyls on display, and it plays music as requested. We were able to walk in on a Friday around 6:30 PM without reservations for 2.</description></item><item><title>Bōm</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:29:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</guid><description>Bom is a restaurant located in the back room of its sibling restaurant, Oiji Mi. We had been to that before, and I thought it was pretty decent. Bom was always on my list of things to try, but at $295 per person, I was pretty hesitant and skeptical. This restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a Michelin Star yet. Since reservations are fairly easy and Oiji Mi was pretty good, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this a try since we were celebrating two major milestones in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Tacos Güey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacos-guey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 16:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tacos-guey/</guid><description>We were in the Flatiron area running errands, and unfortunately the nearby S&amp;amp;P sandwich shop was closed for dinner. As we scoured for food, we did ultimately end up at this Tacos Güey place. I vaguely had remembered that this was a relatively new restaurant, so we opted to try it out. We were able to walk in on a Friday evening at 6:30 PM and find a pair of seats in the bar.</description></item><item><title>Nubeluz</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 21:47:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</guid><description>Nubeluz is a bar from Chef José Andrés located on the 50th floor of The Ritz-Carlton in Nomad with the intent to show visitors the NYC skyline. He has another recently opened restaurant, Zaytinya, on the first floor of this hotel. We were able to make reservations for 4:00 PM on a Sunday a few weeks in advanced. When you walk into the hotel, check in with the concierge who will swipe you up to the floor.</description></item><item><title>Jua</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 18:54:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</guid><description>Jua is one of those new-ish Korean restaurants that has received a number of praises from all sorts of diners. I was able to get a 2-seater a few days before Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day on a Saturday evening. It did require me to sit and snipe on Resy, which fortunately was not as difficult as trying to get reservations at Don Angie. Jua is a restaurant by chef Hoyoung Kim, who was the former executive chef of Jungsik.</description></item><item><title>Ilili</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ilili/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:30:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/ilili/</guid><description>On our Fridays, we typically plan a post-work dinner somewhere. Throughout the week, we eat at home a very basic chicken and vegetables dinner, and we use our end of weeks to eat out. This time around, my partner had picked Ilili because it had been on their list for quite some time. I looked online and noticed that they charge $50 if you cancel a reservation, so we decided to risk doing a walk-in right at 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Lysée</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/lysee/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 22:44:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/lysee/</guid><description>Dessert bars are not a new thing in NYC, but finding a very good one can be difficult. This one comes from Chef Eunji Lee, who comes from renowned Jungsik. My partner did see the chef in the kitchen when we were there. We were able to make a reservation for this several weeks in advance surprisingly without any hassle. When you walk in, there is a floor level section and an upper level section.</description></item><item><title>Zaytinya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zaytinya/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 14:29:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zaytinya/</guid><description>Zaytinya is located right next to the N (yellow) line off 28th St inside of the luxurious Ritz-Carlton hotel on the first floor. This is another restaurant of José Andrés, and the menu has a lot of classical Turkish, Greek, and Lebanese influences. What was appealing to us was the menu had hummus, and the prices did not seem too expensive despite being inside a luxury hotel. When you enter the restaurant, it has a very open and modern Greek ambiance to it, similar to many other Greek restaurants in the city.</description></item><item><title>Oiji Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:04:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</guid><description>I read about Oiji Mi somewhere, and my gourmand syndrome was kicking in since I felt like I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a prix fixe upper end restaurant in a while. Oiji Mi is relatively new, and it comes from the owners of the original East Village&amp;rsquo;s Oiji. It offers creative contemporary Korean dining composed uniquely for NYC. I saw that they offer a 5 course tasting menu for $125 per person, and the menu looked quite interesting.</description></item><item><title>Mr Mistah Oh</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mr-mistah-oh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 23:03:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mr-mistah-oh/</guid><description>On this very humid Friday afternoon, I had to make my way into the Flatiron area to run some errands. This Korean restaurant was something that seemed appealing since we haven&amp;rsquo;t had Korean food in a while. Normally for decent Korean, you&amp;rsquo;d have to venture into midtown, but the menu looked pretty decent online. We were fortunate that that they still had the NY restaurant week menu which was quite alluring.</description></item><item><title>Cote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:00:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</guid><description>Summary Indoor dining finally opened again in NYC on September 30, 2020. There are those that feel it&amp;rsquo;s reckless in this COVID temperament, but we still decided to celebrate by booking an indoor reservation at Cote, a 1 Michelin Star Korean BBQ restaurant. Normally, this is difficult to get a reasonable time, so we were happy it was not too bad. Like all upscale restaurants, they take your temperature via the forehead, and each table is partitioned by a plastic partition.</description></item><item><title>Mazete</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:50:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</guid><description>Summary Typically when we walk north on 6th ave towards Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s for groceries, we stop by Cava across the street for a snack. We saw this seemingly new interesting restaurant opened with no one in it. The space is very bright, modern, and definitely has a Japanese cafe-chic vibe to it. This dry &amp;ldquo;ramen&amp;rdquo; place just opened along 6th Avenue between 20th and 21st Street.
This is another one of those &amp;ldquo;pick X of this and Y of that&amp;rdquo; type of restaurant except the theme here is Japanese.</description></item><item><title>Baodega</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/baodega/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 23:20:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/baodega/</guid><description>Summary This little spot closed to the edge of Flatiron is a decent place if you&amp;rsquo;re into Shanghainese food and are not close to Chinatown.
The passion fruit lemonade was good. You can taste the passion fruit, and it mixed well with the lemonade.
The chilled marinated cucumbers were also good too although I felt the cucumbers were not marinated long enough. They were crunchy with an OK kick to them.</description></item><item><title>Aldea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:31:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Portuguese food other than the pastels, so this is the first for me. This special occasion was for a birthday and to try out a different type of cuisine that is largely not as popular as the mainstream French or Asian themed Michelin Star restaurants.
We got the tasting menu with wine pairing. The hosts were very nice in that we mentioned we&amp;rsquo;d like to just have wine pairing for 1 person and not the other, so that we can share since we&amp;rsquo;re not big drinkers.</description></item><item><title>ABC Cocina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/abc-cocina/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:34:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/abc-cocina/</guid><description>Summary This apparently is one of Jean Georges Vongerichten&amp;rsquo;s upscale farm-fresh eatery, and it has a Latin American fusion influence. We came here without reservations on a weekday night and were seated at the communal table.
The spring pea guacamole with warm crunchy tortillas was actually pretty good. The chips themselves were nicely salted, and the big tortilla that came with the guacamole was more crunchy than the latter. The split pea guacamole had a nice fresh texture.</description></item></channel></rss>