<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Solo on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/solo/</link><description>Recent content in Solo on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 18:26:25 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/solo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BKK New York</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/bkk-new-york/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 18:26:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/bkk-new-york/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bkk-new-york%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Thai restaurants are located around the Midtown area. This one is a modern Thai restaurant inspired by the flavors of Bangkok street food. Unlike other Thai restaurants, the menu here has some interesting options that lured us in. The name comes from the airport code for Bangkok in Thailand. Since we were around the area, I made a reservation for 2 just a few hours before very easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Benjamin Steakhouse Prime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:45:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/benjamin-steakhouse-prime%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restaurant Week is notorious for it&amp;rsquo;s multi-course offerings that feature items that aren&amp;rsquo;t on their respective restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menus. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun tip. Steak places are typically a really good bang for the buck as they typically offer you things on their menu. As a way to chill out and celebrate solo, I went to Benjamin Prime. I walked in on a Friday around 4:30 PM without any issues alone. They asked if I wanted a table for 1 or sit at a bar, and I asked for a table which they accommodated. This location is a very close walking distance from Bryant Park.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kisa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kisa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 13:16:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kisa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kisa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kisa is a Korean restaurant that is serving &lt;em&gt;Baek Ban&lt;/em&gt;, which is a traditional Korean meal comprising of rice, soup, and banchan. If you&amp;rsquo;re into set menus similarly to Japanese bento boxes, this will satisfy that itch. I love Korean food in this manner because it&amp;rsquo;s all usually really tasty and very solo friendly. I was able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hamburger America</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:40:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hamburger-america%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamburger America is a luncheonette-style restaurant with counters for eating a burger. It comes from an American chef George Motz, who is offering an homage to the history of the hamburger. It&amp;rsquo;s received a number of positive reviews from food critics for some reason, and Yelpers and food bloggers alike rave about this place. I came here as a quick stop around 4:30 PM on a Thursday evening, and I could walk in and sit on the stool without any trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Revelie Luncheonette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 18:00:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/revelie-luncheonette%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a quick and solo type of restaurant around the Hudson Square area. I decided to look into burgers, and I was debating Hamburger America and this Revelie Luncheonette. This restaurant is walk-in only and is across the street from Raoul&amp;rsquo;s. Since the burgers seem enticing and the restaurant received decent reviews, I decided to give this a try. I was able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Thursday and find an empty stool seat.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>