<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bars on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/bars/</link><description>Recent content in Bars on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/bars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Ophelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 16:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</guid><description>Ophelia is a cocktail bar located in Midtown East near 1st Ave and 50th. It&amp;rsquo;s located at the top of Beekman Tower. This was built in 1928, and it was originally known as the Panhellenic Tower. The bar and hotel originally served as a womens-only club and hotel space for Greek sororities. When you walk into the lobby of the hotel, take the middle elevator to the 26th floor for entrance.</description></item><item><title>Nubeluz</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 21:47:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/nubeluz/</guid><description>Nubeluz is a bar from Chef José Andrés located on the 50th floor of The Ritz-Carlton in Nomad with the intent to show visitors the NYC skyline. He has another recently opened restaurant, Zaytinya, on the first floor of this hotel. We were able to make reservations for 4:00 PM on a Sunday a few weeks in advanced. When you walk into the hotel, check in with the concierge who will swipe you up to the floor.</description></item><item><title>Refinery Rooftop Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/refinery-rooftop-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 14:43:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/refinery-rooftop-bar/</guid><description>On this very cloudy Sunday, we originally were planning to go to a &amp;ldquo;rooftop&amp;rdquo; outdoor film viewing on top of a hotel. Unfortunately, it got cloudy fast, and it rained throughout most of the day. The hosts cancelled the event, but we still desired to meet up with some friends. We ended up at Refinery Rooftop, which is just around the corner from the cancelled event. Fortunately, they were able to accept walk-ins around 4:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.</description></item><item><title>Valerie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:28:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</guid><description>Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s yet another day of the year to spend more money on your partner! Valerie is a restaurant located in Midtown about 3 streets up from Bryant Park. My partner was craving crab cakes and aside from ordering from Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Famous Seafood, I was having a lot of trouble finding something. They gave me a list, and I noticed that there was crab cake on this menu. I had no idea what to expect on an early Saturday evening when we arrived.</description></item><item><title>Woodbines</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:58:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/woodbines/</guid><description>Woodbines is another craft beer and bar restaurant on Vernon Blvd in Long Island City that has fish and chips on the menu which my partner as craving for. At 5:00 PM, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people, and it was easy to get a seat inside the restaurant. Keep in mind, they do follow COVID protocols, so they asked us to check our temperature against the wall. They definitely have an outdoor setup, and that seemed to be more popular with the guests as the night went on.</description></item><item><title>The Elgin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 16:12:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</guid><description>Summary We were near Rockafeller and were craving some bar like food. Not too far around the corner is this new-ish bar. Walking in, the interior is very open and seems pretty nice. There are a lot of tables that you can stand or sit on a high stool for drinks. You can tell it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty social atmosphere. But let&amp;rsquo;s get to the food.
This is the Detroit pepperoni pan pizza.</description></item><item><title>Penthouse 808</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/penthouse-808/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 16:13:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/penthouse-808/</guid><description>Summary This bar / restaurant is located on the 6th floor in the Ravel Hotel in Long Island City. The view is fairly nice as you can see Midtown from the east, but it is not stellar since it sits slightly lower than the Queensborough bridge and there are 2 smoke stack obstructions as you look towards the Empire State building.
We ordered some bottles of Rose and an entree.</description></item><item><title>The Polynesian</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-polynesian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 15:32:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-polynesian/</guid><description>Summary This place is located near 42nd Street and 9 ave in the POD hotel. The restaurant decor is kind of interesting as it does give out a tropical-ish vibe to it. There is an outdoor area that has a lot of those basket woven seats with a cushion on them. From where we sat outdoors, we can see views of the H&amp;amp;M building and the Empire State Building in plain sight.</description></item><item><title>The 18th Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-18th-room/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 01:32:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-18th-room/</guid><description>Cool speak easy spot right next to Bathtub Gin. Seems to be Cuban driven. It has a very jazzy speak easy feel to it. The theme of the menu is pretty cool. On Wednesdays, they have a live cuban band.
The bartenders can craft drinks based on what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. I think weekdays are probably the best to come here. The music on the speakers is good and isn&amp;rsquo;t loud, and you can actually hear people.</description></item><item><title>The Huntress Whiskey N Wings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 21:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</guid><description>Summary The vibe in this place was pretty cool. It reminded me of being in one of those Lord of the Rings tavern.
The poutine was pretty salty, but it was a good match with the beers. I wish the cheese curds were a little warmer and more abundant.
The savage is actually regular hot wings. The hot wings tasted like they were fried first then doused in sauce after. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice texture combination, and it&amp;rsquo;s how I prefer my hot wings.</description></item><item><title>Spritzenhaus 33</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/spritzenhaus-33/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:53:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/spritzenhaus-33/</guid><description>Crowded AF. Really noisy, bartenders slow AF. Standard Biergarten is better as well as the other one in Billsburg.</description></item><item><title>Hotel Delmano</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/hotel-delmano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:52:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/hotel-delmano/</guid><description>Cool place. They have food. Not too expensive. Right next to the water sorta in Williamsburg.</description></item><item><title>Due West</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/due-west/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:51:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/due-west/</guid><description>Great bar/vibe. This new-ish place is definitely going to be popular.</description></item><item><title>The Ragtrader and Bo Beep Cocktail</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-ragtrader-and-bo-beep-cocktail/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-ragtrader-and-bo-beep-cocktail/</guid><description>Interesting bar. Bar upstairs is cool. Piano bar downstairs is really KEWL.</description></item><item><title>The Otheroom</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-otheroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:48:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-otheroom/</guid><description>Good date vibe in the West Village.</description></item><item><title>Elsa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/elsa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:47:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/elsa/</guid><description>Cool vibe. Good place to take people who live in Carroll Gardens area circa Smith St.</description></item><item><title>Dutch Kills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dutch-kills/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:45:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dutch-kills/</guid><description>Decent vibey bar similar to some LES places, but way out in Queens. But who knows maybe Long Island City might be the next spot after Williamsburg!</description></item><item><title>Public Hotel</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/public-hotel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:42:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/public-hotel/</guid><description>People come here to drink because they&amp;rsquo;re retarded. Terrible drinks. College-ish atmosphere. Pretentious for no reason.
Oh, it has the orange escalator hallway that everyone likes to take pictures of. There&amp;rsquo;s also that purple glass window back that people like too.</description></item><item><title>Dear Irving</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dear-irving/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:40:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dear-irving/</guid><description>Good old boys bar. Think jazzy-ish. Nice place.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Kills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/fresh-kills/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:39:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/fresh-kills/</guid><description>Decent stop for a drink before going elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>Post Office</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/post-office/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:37:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/post-office/</guid><description>Cool place for whiskeys.
But it&amp;rsquo;s CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>Attaboy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/attaboy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:35:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/attaboy/</guid><description>You tell them what ingredients you like in your drink, and they make something magical for you.</description></item><item><title>Golden Years</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/golden-years/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:34:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/golden-years/</guid><description>Fried chicken sandwich was ok. Has a kick to it just like every fried chicken sandwich place. Cash only though. Don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d care to come back.</description></item></channel></rss>