<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 21:11:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blue Hill Cafeteria at Stone Barns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-cafeteria-at-stone-barns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 21:11:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-cafeteria-at-stone-barns/</guid><description>Since we&amp;rsquo;re out in the Tarrytown area, just outside of NYC, we decided to also try out their lunch tray to see how it goes. A few nights ago, we went to a very fantastic, memorable tasting dinner at Blue Hill. For this lunch, we were expecting the ingredients to be very crispy, fresh, and delicious to commemorate everything we learned about the Blue Hill farm experience. I made a reservation for 2 for 1:00 PM on a Sunday without issues a few weeks back.</description></item><item><title>Blue Hill at Stone Barns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 20:07:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</guid><description>Blue Hill at Stone Barns has been on our hit list for over 4 years now. Every year, my partner attempted to book the reservation online, but they would always be unsuccessful. This year, I decided to take a shot at it, and I scored a June 19th, Thursday, reservation for 5 PM. This restaurant has 2 Michelin Stars, and it is located near Tarrytown in Westchester County. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to do a train ride up from the city and take an uber, but we opted to make a weekend trip out of it.</description></item><item><title>odo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/odo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 20:29:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/odo/</guid><description>Odo is a Michelin 2-star restaurant located in the Flatiron district of Manhattan. It comes from Chef Hiroki Odo, who moved to New York in 2012 and won a Michelin Star as the head chef at Kajitsu. We looked on the Michelin guide, and we saw this was a 2-star restaurant that we haven&amp;rsquo;t been to yet. We were able to make a reservation for 2 for 6 PM on a Sunday night without issues.</description></item><item><title>Bridges</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bridges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:41:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bridges/</guid><description>Bridges opened in the late fall last year, and is headed by chef Sam Lawrence who came from Estela, which is on our list to hit. Lately, this restaurant has been getting some notoriety for having good food and a good ambiance. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit difficult to get to since you have to walk a bit from the subway entrance. I was able to book a reservation for 2 for the bar about a few days in advance for 5:45 PM.</description></item><item><title>Matsunori</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:18:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</guid><description>Matsunori Handroll Bar, not to be confused with Matsunori Sushi Club, originated as a Boston handroll sushi bar. They decided to open an additional location in Long Island City, where there is an influx of Asians moving in. They do not accept reservations, so we decided to try to walk in around 6:30 PM on a Friday evening. Fortunately, we got there just before the lines, and we were able to sit at a table for 2.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger America</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:40:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/hamburger-america/</guid><description>Hamburger America is a luncheonette-style restaurant with counters for eating a burger. It comes from an American chef George Motz, who is offering an homage to the history of the hamburger. It&amp;rsquo;s received a number of positive reviews from food critics for some reason, and Yelpers and food bloggers alike rave about this place. I came here as a quick stop around 4:30 PM on a Thursday evening, and I could walk in and sit on the stool without any trouble.</description></item><item><title>Rosevale Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</guid><description>Today was another Broadway showing that we had to attend. Our theater district restaurant pool is thinning a bit, so this one was somewhat difficult to locate. It reminds me of a Midtown staple type of restaurant that is very friendly to the theater crowd, and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get in. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening around 5 PM without any issues.
From their website:</description></item><item><title>Crane Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/crane-club/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 17:00:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/crane-club/</guid><description>Crane Club is located across the street from Chelsea Market. It&amp;rsquo;s being led by executive chef Melissa Rodriguez, who formerly oversaw Al Coro, which earned 2 Michelin stars at one point. This restaurant is under the Tao Hospitality Group, which oversees some upscale trendy hot spots like Hakkasan, Lava, and TAO Asian Bistro. We were able to make a reservation for the dining room very easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday night.</description></item><item><title>Nubiani</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/nubiani/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:48:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/nubiani/</guid><description>Nubiani was a Korean BBQ restaurant that had been on my list for quite some time. I was only reminded of it when my partner wanted to go to it because one of their friends tried to walk-in and instead had to go to Love Korean BBQ. I was easily able to make a reservation for Friday, though they only had early PM openings at 4:30. This is located right across the street from Love, inside a building on the third floor.</description></item><item><title>Time and Tide</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</guid><description>Time and Tide comes from the Kent Hospitality Group, which owns restaurants such as Saga and Crown Shy. The head chef, Top Chef winner Danny Garcia, overhauled the menu recently, and we got a chance to experience it. The restaurant was inspired to be a steakhouse modeled fish restaurant. I was easily able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night because the restaurant snipers have moved onto newer restaurants.</description></item><item><title>Becco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:05:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</guid><description>Becco was on our list for a while. This restaurant in the Theater District was always full around theater times, so of course, that&amp;rsquo;s naturally alluring. It was first opened in 1993 by Lidia Bastianich and her son, Joe, who you might recognize from the U.S. version of the MasterChef series. The Yelp ratings of the food seem surprisingly low compared to the Google counterpart, so that increase our curiosity.</description></item><item><title>The Leopard at Des Artistes</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 21:17:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</guid><description>We had a show to catch at the Lincoln Center, and the area had a lot of New American and Italian restaurants within half a mile. We&amp;rsquo;ve rarely explored anywhere north of 60th St. This area is just across the street on the lower west side of Central Park. The restaurant itself is located in a historic residential building called Hotel des Artistes. I was easily able to make a reservation the day before for a 5:15 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Locanda Verde</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:55:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</guid><description>Chef Andrew Carmellini has some pretty good restaurants (NoHo Hospitality) that we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. Some recent ones that we really enjoyed include Cafe Carmellini and Carne Mare. Locanda Verde opened a second location in the Hudson Yards area. This is his ode to urban Italian cuisine, and we wanted to try this out because the exterior seemed very nice. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:15 on a Friday evening without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Revelie Luncheonette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 18:00:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/revelie-luncheonette/</guid><description>I was looking for a quick and solo type of restaurant around the Hudson Square area. I decided to look into burgers, and I was debating Hamburger America and this Revelie Luncheonette. This restaurant is walk-in only and is across the street from Raoul&amp;rsquo;s. Since the burgers seem enticing and the restaurant received decent reviews, I decided to give this a try. I was able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Thursday and find an empty stool seat.</description></item><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.</description></item><item><title>Le Veau d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</guid><description>Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;Or is French for &amp;ldquo;the golden calf&amp;rdquo;. Making reservations for 2 for this was incredibly difficult as it gets sniped the moment the reservations come up. Luckily I checked a random time, and I noticed there was some 5:00 PM slots opened on a Wednesday. This is one of the hottest restaurants in the city because it&amp;rsquo;s a revived restaurant from the Frenchette and Le Rock chef/owners, Lee Hanson and Riad Nasr.</description></item><item><title>Lolita's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 13:44:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</guid><description>We were out and about in Central Park taking pictures, and we were looking for a place to check out midday. This no-frills Mexican-like restaurant was near where we walked out of Central Park. We were a bit skeptical of this restaurant since the menu was on the smaller side, but we decided to give it a try. We were seated without reservations pretty easily around 1 PM on a Sunday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, Manhatta, and The Modern. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like.</description></item><item><title>Sozai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 17:43:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</guid><description>We finished watching a matinee of a Broadway show, and we&amp;rsquo;re running out of desirable early dinner options in the Midtown area. This one was on my list for quite some time as it looked like a restaurant that was a no frills izakaya type restaurant. This restaurant is about 2 doors down from Valerie, a pretty popular Midtown restaurant. We were able to walk in around 4:30 PM on a Saturday without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Don Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:45:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</guid><description>We decided Don Don because we&amp;rsquo;ve really been enjoying Chef Sungchul Shim&amp;rsquo;s restaurants, including Mari and Gui. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday just a few days ahead, and it was fairly easy. Located very close to Bryant Park, it&amp;rsquo;s along the way from Valerie, and it can be easily missed. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty discreet until you take a look at the front window.</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and Mari. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including Le Bernardin and Le Rock. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night.</description></item><item><title>La Tete d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:54:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</guid><description>La Tête d&amp;rsquo;Or by Daniel is a tribute to timeless flavors and traditions with infusion of French flavors. What attracted me with this restaurant was that chef Daniel Boulud has a pretty decent track record of delivering good refined flavors. We went to Le Gratin previously, and we were very impressed by the taste of everything. As usual because he also holds some type of celebrity status, this restaurant is located in a posh area very close to Eleven Madison.</description></item><item><title>Raon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:20:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</guid><description>Raon is a new Korean tasting restaurant from Chef Soogil Lim and his wife, Sasook Youn. Their other restaurant, Soogil, is located in the East Village, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to open a more intimate fine dining type of restaurant. One of the key features that attracted me to this was that they would a tasting menu centered around kimchi. When we went to Meju, we simply adored it. So we wanted to see how this would compare because both restaurants emphasize that kimchi is a key part of the experience.</description></item><item><title>Roscioli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:46:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</guid><description>Roscioli has been on my list for a while since the original location of this restaurant is in Rome. This New York City alternative offers a pasta tasting menu, which looked quite interesting and affordable. I was able to book a reservation about a few weeks out for a 6 PM dinner. Keep in mind that the tasting is located downstairs, whereas the normal restaurant is located street level.</description></item><item><title>Smithereens</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:46:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</guid><description>Smithereens opened pretty recently in last November, and is from chef Nick Tamburo (Claud) and beverage director Nikita Malhotra (Momofuku Ko). This is a New England-style restaurant focused on fresh seafood and some different types of cocktails. Their wine list is pretty extensive, and they also have some pretty interesting glasses of white wines as well. I was able to book a reservation for 5:30 PM for 2 on a Friday evening about a week in advance.</description></item></channel></rss>