<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:58:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bourbon Steak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:58:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</guid><description>Michael Mina is an award winning chef and restaurateur that currently runs and operates over 40 restaurants worldwide. He opened this restaurant in the JW Marriott Essex House, right across from Central Park south and near Columbus Circle. This is his love letter to the classic American steakhouse. Bourbon Steak has multiple locations in the United States, so it&amp;rsquo;s not an entirely new restaurant. I picked this restaurant particularly because of their prix fixe menu that seems to give a pretty good spread of what this restaurant has to offer.</description></item><item><title>The Musket Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</guid><description>The Musket Room has been around for a while, and it is located close to the Broadway/Lafayette train in Manhattan. Chef Mary Attea is the head chef of this restaurant, and according to the Michelin Guide, the kitchen is predominantly women. We picked this restaurant to try for tonight primarily because the menu looked like a slightly different take on New American than what we were used to. I was easily able to book a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance.</description></item><item><title>Leitao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:14:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</guid><description>No, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the front of Leitão but a pic of the back. I stumbled onto this restaurant looking for Portuguese or Peruvian restaurants for our Friday dinners. My partner wanted this as the option for this evening, so I made a reservation for 2 at 5:30 PM on a nice Friday evening. The restaurant itself is located about a 0.5 mile (0.8 km) walk from the West 4th subway station.</description></item><item><title>Pure Thai Cookhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</guid><description>We won yet another lottery for one of the theater shows, so we were hoping to walk into Wondee Thai. As expected, there was a line outside and a wait inside, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble missing the show if we had waited. We instead opted to walk a block south to this restaurant which had no patrons. We were able to walk in for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Saturday night without reservations.</description></item><item><title>Artesano</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/artesano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 23:48:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/artesano/</guid><description>My partner adores Peruvian food, primarily for the ceviche. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to a handful of Peruvian in the city, but this is one of the first that I saw marketing itself to be more on the higher end. The head chef of this restaurant, Rodrigo Fernandini, came from Chiclayo (Peru) and opened this back in late 2023. We were able to make a reservation for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Friday very easily without trouble.</description></item><item><title>Giorgio's of Gramercy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 21:51:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</guid><description>In our quest to find all the &amp;ldquo;Baked Alaska&amp;rdquo; restaurants in NYC, this was one that I was surprised to have it priced reasonably. Looking at the menu, everything was affordable compared to the rest of Manhattan. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest that I have never heard of this restaurant, and this came up randomly in my search. We easily made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday.</description></item><item><title>Odre</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/odre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 20:49:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/odre/</guid><description>Odre recently opened a little over a month ago, and it was on my list to checkout. Similar to other Korean small-tasting restaurants, this offered an inexpensive tasting of Korean rustic-style cooking. The restaurant is part of the Hand Hospitality network, which includes Nonono, Cho Dang Gol, Jua, Okdongsik, and many more. I was able to make a reservation fairly easy a few days prior to our visit for a 5:30 PM Friday evening dinner.</description></item><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>We had previously been to The Bar at The Modern, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options.</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.</description></item><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything.</description></item><item><title>The Clocktower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 19:39:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</guid><description>The Clocktower has been on my list for a while and was a former 1 Michelin Star restaurant a few years ago. I ended up circling back to this restaurant because we&amp;rsquo;re desiring to eat as many baked Alaska places as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how many permutations of this dessert exists. We were able to book a reservation for 2 for a Friday evening without issue. The restaurant is located inside The Edison hotel on the second floor.</description></item><item><title>Chef Papa Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:42:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/chef-papa/</guid><description>The Long Island City area around Queensboro Plaza is definitely missing some Vietnamese restaurants. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Cyclo, and it was very mediocre. Since Knock Knock closed down, this family-owned restaurant from Flushing took over the location. We were able to stop by around 5 PM on a Sunday early evening without reservations. There was no one eating, and we asked to sit at the same bar that was located at Knock Knock.</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.</description></item><item><title>Claud</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</guid><description>For this week, I offered my partner an option of European or Chinese. Of course they said European. Claud comes from 2 veterans of the Momofuku Ko restaurant, chef Joshua Pinsky and wine expert Chase Sinzer. I remember this restaurant a while back, but it slipped off my radar with all these new openings in the last few years. When I checked Resy, I noticed there were openings on Friday, so the stars aligned.</description></item><item><title>Rice Thief</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:02:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</guid><description>Rice Thief is one of the few Korean raw marinated crab restaurants in New York City. The focus of this restaurant is to provide deeply marinated raw crabs with lots of seasoning in it. To the surprise of many, the raw crab meat is actually a little gooey but quite flavorful. My partner saw this restaurant on Instagram and expressed interest in trying this out, despite me wanting to avoid bringing them here.</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Jing Li</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:04:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</guid><description>Jing Li has been opened for a few years now in this location. It actually used to be a different Chinese restaurant, so I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s the same owners. The menu looks very typical of non Sichuan Chinese restaurants. Before we walked in, I already decided to go more of a pescatarian selection and hoping the food quality and taste would be similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve had before in the San Gabriel Valley.</description></item><item><title>Konban</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:44:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</guid><description>Konban was a new katsu restaurant that was on my radar for a while. When it first opened, reservations were hard to come by. Now a few months later, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a reservation a week out. Because Manhattan has so few katsu-specialized options, this was going to be a very special experience. I was able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night for two people.</description></item><item><title>Han Dynasty</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 14:43:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</guid><description>Han Dynasty is yet another Chinese restaurant that recently joined the Long Island City area. They already have some existing locations spread around other parts of NYC. Their food is the same Sichuan style that many of the local restaurants here aim to serve. I think this style of Chinese is becoming too plentiful here, such that competition is bound to be very difficult. We decided to try this out.</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind Au Cheval and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.</description></item><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly Sal e Brasa, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Ole</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and SVL Souvlaki Bar. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant Cafe Olé even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.</description></item></channel></rss>