<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.</description></item><item><title>Le Veau d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</guid><description>Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;Or is French for &amp;ldquo;the golden calf&amp;rdquo;. Making reservations for 2 for this was incredibly difficult as it gets sniped the moment the reservations come up. Luckily I checked a random time, and I noticed there was some 5:00 PM slots opened on a Wednesday. This is one of the hottest restaurants in the city because it&amp;rsquo;s a revived restaurant from the Frenchette and Le Rock chef/owners, Lee Hanson and Riad Nasr.</description></item><item><title>Lolita's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 13:44:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/lolitas-kitchen/</guid><description>We were out and about in Central Park taking pictures, and we were looking for a place to check out midday. This no-frills Mexican-like restaurant was near where we walked out of Central Park. We were a bit skeptical of this restaurant since the menu was on the smaller side, but we decided to give it a try. We were seated without reservations pretty easily around 1 PM on a Sunday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, Manhatta, and The Modern. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like.</description></item><item><title>Sozai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 17:43:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</guid><description>We finished watching a matinee of a Broadway show, and we&amp;rsquo;re running out of desirable early dinner options in the Midtown area. This one was on my list for quite some time as it looked like a restaurant that was a no frills izakaya type restaurant. This restaurant is about 2 doors down from Valerie, a pretty popular Midtown restaurant. We were able to walk in around 4:30 PM on a Saturday without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Don Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:45:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</guid><description>We decided Don Don because we&amp;rsquo;ve really been enjoying Chef Sungchul Shim&amp;rsquo;s restaurants, including Mari and Gui. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday just a few days ahead, and it was fairly easy. Located very close to Bryant Park, it&amp;rsquo;s along the way from Valerie, and it can be easily missed. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty discreet until you take a look at the front window.</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and Mari. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including Le Bernardin and Le Rock. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night.</description></item><item><title>La Tete d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:54:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</guid><description>La Tête d&amp;rsquo;Or by Daniel is a tribute to timeless flavors and traditions with infusion of French flavors. What attracted me with this restaurant was that chef Daniel Boulud has a pretty decent track record of delivering good refined flavors. We went to Le Gratin previously, and we were very impressed by the taste of everything. As usual because he also holds some type of celebrity status, this restaurant is located in a posh area very close to Eleven Madison.</description></item><item><title>Raon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:20:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</guid><description>Raon is a new Korean tasting restaurant from Chef Soogil Lim and his wife, Sasook Youn. Their other restaurant, Soogil, is located in the East Village, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to open a more intimate fine dining type of restaurant. One of the key features that attracted me to this was that they would a tasting menu centered around kimchi. When we went to Meju, we simply adored it. So we wanted to see how this would compare because both restaurants emphasize that kimchi is a key part of the experience.</description></item><item><title>Roscioli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:46:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</guid><description>Roscioli has been on my list for a while since the original location of this restaurant is in Rome. This New York City alternative offers a pasta tasting menu, which looked quite interesting and affordable. I was able to book a reservation about a few weeks out for a 6 PM dinner. Keep in mind that the tasting is located downstairs, whereas the normal restaurant is located street level.</description></item><item><title>Smithereens</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:46:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</guid><description>Smithereens opened pretty recently in last November, and is from chef Nick Tamburo (Claud) and beverage director Nikita Malhotra (Momofuku Ko). This is a New England-style restaurant focused on fresh seafood and some different types of cocktails. Their wine list is pretty extensive, and they also have some pretty interesting glasses of white wines as well. I was able to book a reservation for 5:30 PM for 2 on a Friday evening about a week in advance.</description></item><item><title>Kausa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</guid><description>We had won another theater tickets for this Sunday, so we looked for a place nearby. My partner desired Peruvian food again, specifically lomo saltado. The best lomo saltado place we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had was actually Mario&amp;rsquo;s in Los Angeles, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a comparable place, especially in New York City. We walked in on a late Sunday afternoon without issues, and we were seated promptly. Looking over the menu, they had your typical Peruvian options.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Zaffri</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:45:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</guid><description>Cafe Zaffri has been opened for just a week and are going through an early preview of their menu. The executive Chef Mary Attea heads the menu by tapping into her Lebanese roots and incorporating Levantine flavors into a modern menu. Along with the Chef, owners Jennifer and Nicole Vitagliano also came from The Musket Room. We were able to make a reservation for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day at 5:30 PM just a few days before because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet been fully discovered by the populous.</description></item><item><title>Xie Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:58:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</guid><description>We had a show this evening, and this &amp;ldquo;crab house&amp;rdquo; just recently opened in Manhattan. This originated from a Flushing stall, and their specialty is crab roe over rice or noodle. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening without reservations. The social media circuit really raved about this dish by showing off the roe, so we decided to try it. I figured there was no need to make reservations since Manhattan Midtown Chinese restaurants are usually pretty easy to get into.</description></item><item><title>Danji</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:18:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</guid><description>Danji is Chef Hooni Kim&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that opened 15 years ago. It earned a Michelin Star back in 2012 and closed in April 2023 due to a fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other Michelin Star restaurant, Meju, which was phenomenal for what it was. We decided to check out this to see how it was, so I made a reservation pretty easily a week prior for 5:30 PM for a Friday.</description></item><item><title>Hawksmoor</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/hawksmoor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:52:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/hawksmoor/</guid><description>Hawksmoor is a London restaurant that has a few other locations in the U.S. This is the first New York City location. In the UK, Hawksmoor is known for its food integrity, drinks, and visually appealing dining areas. They claim they have found the perfect way to cook steaks. One of the biggest appeals for me was they have a &amp;ldquo;Sunday Roast&amp;rdquo;, which is supposed to be a heavy Sunday meal.</description></item><item><title>Zimmi's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/zimmis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 11:34:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/zimmis/</guid><description>Zimmi&amp;rsquo;s is a new little French restaurant that recently just opened in the West Village. Its menu comes from chef Maxime Pradié, who draws influences from homestyle Southern French cooking. I looked on Resy, and I was able to get a reservation for 2 at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening. When I arrived, it really resonated the classic West Village restaurant, where the word &amp;ldquo;quaint&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;rustic&amp;rdquo; are often used together to describe the ambiance and food.</description></item><item><title>TabeTomo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:18:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tabetomo/</guid><description>I remember a few years ago before the pandemic, TabeTomo was a very new tsukemen centric restaurant, and it was always on my try list. However, I never was able to make it to the restaurant due to how sparse tsukemen was in general in Manhattan, as well as, the restaurant was closed at random times when I tried to visit. Finally tonight, I got a chance to try this out and to compare against other tsukemen places.</description></item><item><title>Octo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 13:32:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</guid><description>Octo is a Korean-Chinese restaurant that brings Chinese dishes developed in Korea. I visited South Korea back in the 2014s, and they definitely had their own spin on Chinese food, which is what attracted me to this restaurant. South Korea has its fair share of Chinese foods that are pretty similar, considered they have shared cultures. Located near Koreatown, we made a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night very easily.</description></item><item><title>Golden Wuish</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/golden-wuish/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:56:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/golden-wuish/</guid><description>The Golden Wuish (Duck House) was featured in several social media outlets, and my partner was craving for duck after returning from Boston. I remembered that this looked pretty gimmicky, so it could be fun whilst having a decent dinner. The restaurant is located in a dark spot next to a hotel, so it was initially somewhat odd to locate. When we walked in for our reservation at 5:30 PM on a Friday night, we were seated towards the front.</description></item><item><title>SAGA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 20:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</guid><description>SAGA is a Michelin 2-star restaurant run by the Kent Hospitality Group. The late Chef James Kent received a lot of good reviews for his restaurants, and this one was on my list to try, especially after trying Crown Shy. This restaurant is located in the same landmark Art Deco tower as Crown Shy. Crown Shy is located at the first floor, whereas this one is located on the 63rd floor.</description></item><item><title>Mitr Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:25:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</guid><description>Mitr Thai is a Midtown Thai restaurant that is located very close to Bryant Park. It can be a great option for Thai if you prefer to stay east of the Theater District. When we walked in around 5:30 PM on a Thursday night, we actually had to wait about 30-40 minutes. The restaurant was very full both downstairs and upstairs. We were seated upstairs in a 2-seater.
Ambiance &amp;amp; Service The interior decoration is dark and reminded me of a Tao-like upscale Asian restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Five Acres</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</guid><description>The one appeal that attracted me to try out Five Acres was that they offered a Chicago beef sandwich. For some reason, there are very few places that serve this sandwich that I know of. There used to be Hank&amp;rsquo;s Juicy Beef, but that closed down. The other Chicago beef place that I know of is in deep Brooklyn. Since we were around this Midtown area, I figured now is the right time to give this a shot.</description></item><item><title>Hamido Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:38:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve seen this restaurant Hamido Seafood on social media all over the place. Like many Astoria restaurants, they pride themselves in having the freshest seafood, and they are somewhat close to Taverna Kyclades down the street. We went to the original Hamido Seafood restaurant at 4 PM on a Saturday late afternoon, and we were lucky to be seated right away before the crowds came. They are located very close to the N/W train off the Ditmars train stop.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Carmellini</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:26:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</guid><description>For Thanksgiving, we decided to try Cafe Carmellini out because their menu seemed pretty decent and had offerings that were present on their normal menu. My partner is a fan of turkey, so I already know what they were going to get. We made a reservation for 12 PM on Thanksgiving with no issues at all. When we walked in, they had us sit at the bar as they were preparing for Thanksgiving service.</description></item></channel></rss>