<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in Nycs on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.</description></item><item><title>Claud</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</guid><description>For this week, I offered my partner an option of European or Chinese. Of course they said European. Claud comes from 2 veterans of the Momofuku Ko restaurant, chef Joshua Pinsky and wine expert Chase Sinzer. I remember this restaurant a while back, but it slipped off my radar with all these new openings in the last few years. When I checked Resy, I noticed there were openings on Friday, so the stars aligned.</description></item><item><title>Rice Thief</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:02:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</guid><description>Rice Thief is one of the few Korean raw marinated crab restaurants in New York City. The focus of this restaurant is to provide deeply marinated raw crabs with lots of seasoning in it. To the surprise of many, the raw crab meat is actually a little gooey but quite flavorful. My partner saw this restaurant on Instagram and expressed interest in trying this out, despite me wanting to avoid bringing them here.</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Jing Li</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:04:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jing-li/</guid><description>Jing Li has been opened for a few years now in this location. It actually used to be a different Chinese restaurant, so I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s the same owners. The menu looks very typical of non Sichuan Chinese restaurants. Before we walked in, I already decided to go more of a pescatarian selection and hoping the food quality and taste would be similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve had before in the San Gabriel Valley.</description></item><item><title>Konban</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:44:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</guid><description>Konban was a new katsu restaurant that was on my radar for a while. When it first opened, reservations were hard to come by. Now a few months later, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a reservation a week out. Because Manhattan has so few katsu-specialized options, this was going to be a very special experience. I was able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night for two people.</description></item><item><title>Han Dynasty</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 14:43:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/han-dynasty/</guid><description>Han Dynasty is yet another Chinese restaurant that recently joined the Long Island City area. They already have some existing locations spread around other parts of NYC. Their food is the same Sichuan style that many of the local restaurants here aim to serve. I think this style of Chinese is becoming too plentiful here, such that competition is bound to be very difficult. We decided to try this out.</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind Au Cheval and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.</description></item><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly Sal e Brasa, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Ole</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/cafe-ole/</guid><description>Whenever we go to Food Bazaar, we always frequent the area right across Northern Blvd to see what other restaurants might be decent. Some highlights around here include: [Pig Beach BBQ]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;pig-beach-bbq&amp;rdquo; }}) and SVL Souvlaki Bar. I saw that there&amp;rsquo;s this little quaint Spanish restaurant Cafe Olé even closer to the market, so we checked this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations around 3 PM on a Friday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, Marta, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food.</description></item><item><title>Le Gratin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:22:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re in a mood of exploring some of the food places down near the Financial District. I was looking around, and there weren&amp;rsquo;t too many options. Le Gratin happened to be from renown chef, Daniel Boulud, so I figure this would be a safe choice. This is located right next to the Beekman Hotel, and there are entrances via the street or through the hotel. We easily made reservations for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Friday without much advance notice.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as Saga, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.</description></item><item><title>Chica &amp; the Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:49:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</guid><description>Chica &amp;amp; The Don is a new Latin restaurant that opened in the Flatiron district. Despite their Yelp site pointing to Flatbush, it really is located in Manhattan. When you walk in, the restaurant has a long corridor to the main dining area. They just opened 3 weeks ago, so I was interested in checking this out before the hype were to build up. We were able to make a reservation relatively easy for 5:45 PM on a Friday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Udon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:48:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</guid><description>I just have this affinity for noodles. Their sibling location, Okiboru House of Tsukemen, was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the city when it comes to dipping ramen. This restaurant recently opened up marketing itself for udon. Like their tsukemen location, this one offers udon for dipping. Unlike traditional udon, these noodles are much wider and flatter. I was able to walk in by myself at 8 PM on a Tuesday evening, and I immediately was seated.</description></item><item><title>Jiang Nan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 15:39:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/jiang-nan/</guid><description>Due to a slew of Chinese spicy restaurants opening up in the Long Island City neighborhood, this was one that caught our attention. Jiang Nan has several locations spread around the tri-state areas and more, and the Flushing location even received a Michelin Bib Gourmand. The restaurant advertises itself as Asian fusion, but I noticed many of the restaurant ingredients were definitely more Chinese centric. We were able to walk in at 5 PM without reservations for 2 on a Saturday evening.</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Class on 38th</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:21:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</guid><description>Class on 38th was something that seemed interesting at first glance when I was browsing the &amp;ldquo;Hot and New&amp;rdquo; sections of Yelp. The menu looked like tapas with a price point that wasn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. I went here with a business partner, who was in town and looking for something to try. I made a reservation a few weeks back without any issues for 6 PM on a Thursday. When I walked in, they allowed me to sit early to wait for my guest to arrive.</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.</description></item></channel></rss>