<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/cuisine/seafood/</link><description>Recent content in Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 16:48:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/cuisine/seafood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Haleiwa Joe's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/haleiwa-joes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 16:48:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/haleiwa-joes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/haleiwa-joes%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haleiwa Joe&amp;rsquo;s at Haiku Gardens in Kaneohe is known for its lush, beautiful views overlooking its own tropical garden and koi pond with a backdrop of a breathtaking Ko&amp;rsquo;olau mountain range. The restaurant opens for dinner nightly at 4 PM, and when we arrived at 3:30, there was already a line forming because they do not take reservations. Fortunately once they open, there are plenty of tables, but it feels that people are trying to get the best view overlooking the gardens.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aloha Shrimp</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/aloha-shrimp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 20:37:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/aloha-shrimp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aloha-shrimp%2F0_truck.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shrimp truck is located on Kamehameha Highway towards the north east end of Oahu between Hauula and the Shrimp Shack. As you&amp;rsquo;re driving north on this highway, it will be on your left side. The truck seems not very mobile, and for whatever reason has very high ratings on Yelp. Because Hawaii is pretty well known for these shrimp trucks, we decided to check this out after our Kualoa excursion.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Herringbone</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 15:05:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/haw/herringbone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/herringbone%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herringbone is run by the &amp;ldquo;Tao Group Hospitality&amp;rdquo;, which operates more than 80 branded locations in 20 different markets. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what to expect, but per recommendations, we were able to do a walk in around 7 PM on a Monday. The restaurant is located on the top floor of the &amp;ldquo;International Market Place&amp;rdquo; where many restaurants are located, and it has a pretty laid back exterior. As you can vaguely tell from the picture, the right side is an outdoor covered patio letting in the Hawaiian breeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>