<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tastings on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tastings/</link><description>Recent content in Tastings on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:22:33 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/tastings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jungsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:22:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jungsik%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our yearly celebration, we decided to come to Jungsik, especially since it was the first NYC Korean restaurant to earn 3 Michelin Stars. I visited this restaurant on a special occasion around June 17, 2017, but I barely remember much about it and did not take pictures. Today is redemption day. I was able to make reservations for 2 fairly easily a few weeks out for a Sunday at 5 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Veau d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-veau-dor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/le-veau-dor%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;Or is French for &amp;ldquo;the golden calf&amp;rdquo;. Making reservations for 2 for this was incredibly difficult as it gets sniped the moment the reservations come up. Luckily I checked a random time, and I noticed there was some 5:00 PM slots opened on a Wednesday. This is one of the hottest restaurants in the city because it&amp;rsquo;s a revived restaurant from the Frenchette and Le Rock chef/owners, Lee Hanson and Riad Nasr. The food is expected to taste much better than the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s previous life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:20:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/raon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raon is a new Korean tasting restaurant from Chef Soogil Lim and his wife, Sasook Youn. Their other restaurant, Soogil, is located in the East Village, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to open a more intimate fine dining type of restaurant. One of the key features that attracted me to this was that they would a tasting menu centered around kimchi. When we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, we simply adored it. So we wanted to see how this would compare because both restaurants emphasize that kimchi is a key part of the experience. I was able to book a 5:00 PM reservation for a Saturday without much issue. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s because the restaurant is still fairly new. The restaurant is very close to the N/W train off of Lexington and Bloomingdales.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roscioli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:46:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/roscioli%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscioli has been on my list for a while since the original location of this restaurant is in Rome. This New York City alternative offers a pasta tasting menu, which looked quite interesting and affordable. I was able to book a reservation about a few weeks out for a 6 PM dinner. Keep in mind that the tasting is located downstairs, whereas the normal restaurant is located street level.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Odre</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/odre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 20:49:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/odre/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/odre%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Odre recently opened a little over a month ago, and it was on my list to checkout. Similar to other Korean small-tasting restaurants, this offered an inexpensive tasting of Korean rustic-style cooking. The restaurant is part of the Hand Hospitality network, which includes &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/"&gt;Nonono&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cho-dang-gol/"&gt;Cho Dang Gol&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/"&gt;Jua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/"&gt;Okdongsik&lt;/a&gt;, and many more. I was able to make a reservation fairly easy a few days prior to our visit for a 5:30 PM Friday evening dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sixty-three-clinton%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it. I was honestly nervous about the experience, but usually I will just go with the chefs&amp;rsquo; visions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/manhatta%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/marta/"&gt;Marta&lt;/a&gt;, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food. We were able to make a reservation for 2 for the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter without much issue for 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Frevo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/frevo%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frevo was a restaurant that has been on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for some time. When we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;Atomix Bar&lt;/a&gt;, the chef had also highly recommended the restaurant. The head chef Franco Sampogna is Brazilian and comes from the region that my partner is from. The entrance to the restaurant has a very tiny art gallery, and it&amp;rsquo;s been recognized on the Michelin Guide with 1 star. We were able to reserve this a few weeks back without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Torien</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 15:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/torien%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Christmas celebration before we embark on a trip, I wanted to knock this final yakitori tasting off the list. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to a slew of yakitori tasting places, and this is the last one that is on the higher end. Torien still has 1 Michelin Star in 2023, and it also has a sister 1 Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/tokyo-region/tokyo/restaurant/torishiki"&gt;Torishiki&lt;/a&gt;, in Tokyo Japan. We were able to make a reservation for this for a Saturday a few weeks back without issues. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this compares to the other yakitori tastings, considering they use a special oak for the taste.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-river-cafe%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bōm</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:29:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bom%2F0_napkin.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bom is a restaurant located in the back room of its sibling restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/"&gt;Oiji Mi&lt;/a&gt;. We had been to that before, and I thought it was pretty decent. Bom was always on my list of things to try, but at $295 per person, I was pretty hesitant and skeptical. This restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a Michelin Star yet. Since reservations are fairly easy and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/"&gt;Oiji Mi&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this a try since we were celebrating two major milestones in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tempura-matsui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/"&gt;Secchu Yokota&lt;/a&gt;. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant. It was very easy to make reservations for one person the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Secchu Yokota</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 21:47:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/secchu-yokota%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempura is one of those things in Japanese cuisine that is pretty expensive for what it is, but when you find the right batter with the right ingredients, it&amp;rsquo;s so good. In Torrance in California, it&amp;rsquo;s been over a decade since I tried specialized tempura, so I was craving it recently. Unfortunately my partner loathes tempura for some odd reason, so I opted to dine alone when they decided to watch a Broadway show. I was able to successfully book a reservation for 1 via their website (through their email link) the day prior for 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef's Table at Brooklyn Fare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table at Brooklyn Fare is a renown &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant by Chef Cesar Ramirez. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by Japanese cuisine with French technique, and the 13 course tasting menu tonight is focused on fish &amp;amp; shellfish with 1 meat course and 4 dessert courses. I was quite excited to come here since moving to NYC. This restaurant was always very difficult to get reservations, so it was great that we were able to when we wanted. This restaurant is currently rated number 61 out of 100 on the &lt;a href="https://www.theworlds50best.com/stories/News/the-worlds-50-best-restaurants-2023-51-100-list.html"&gt;The World&amp;rsquo;s Best 50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aquavit%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have &lt;strong&gt;2 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/"&gt;Aska&lt;/a&gt; recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Naro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:28:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/naro%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naro is a new Korean restaurant that opened right next to the Rockafeller ice skating rink. According to the menu, the Naro name was inspired by South Korea&amp;rsquo;s first ever space vehicle to successfully achieve Earth&amp;rsquo;s orbit and also from the Korean phrase nah-ro (which means &amp;ldquo;through me&amp;rdquo;). Naro focuses on Korean cuisine, drawing inspiration from classic dishes from different moments in Korean history. Lastly, this is the third restaurant from the Atomix and Attaboy founders, so there is definitely some expectations. We actually were able to book a reservation on a Wednesday evening for 5:30 PM without much issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system &lt;a href="https://www.tock.com"&gt;Tock&lt;/a&gt;. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week. I quickly made the reservation, and then ultimately decided to keep both the bar tasting and the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting reservations. This post will be for the Atomix Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter menu. To read about the Atomix Bar tasting experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix. This one is about the bar. To read the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Per Se</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:37:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/per-se%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per Se is Thomas Keller&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed interpretation of the French Laundry restaurant in New York City and has &lt;strong&gt;3 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a replacement for the French Laundry, but it might be indicative of what to expect if we did ever go to Napa Valley to try it out. This restaurant is located in Columbus Circle at the top floor inside the mall. When we walked in, we were astounded by the huge ceiling and the vast feeling of space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oiji Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:04:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I read about Oiji Mi somewhere, and my gourmand syndrome was kicking in since I felt like I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a prix fixe upper end restaurant in a while. Oiji Mi is relatively new, and it comes from the owners of the original East Village&amp;rsquo;s Oiji. It offers creative contemporary Korean dining composed uniquely for NYC. I saw that they offer a 5 course tasting menu for $125 per person, and the menu looked quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Genesis House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:14:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/genesis-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We saw this restaurant&amp;rsquo;s opening relatively recently on an NYC openings blog. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what exactly was the &amp;ldquo;Genesis House&amp;rdquo; or what &amp;ldquo;curated by Onjium&amp;rdquo; meant, but I figure post pandemic this was an excellent opportunity to make a reservation for something new to please my gourmand syndrome. The Genesis house is kind of interesting. The first floor is a showroom of Genesis vehicles where you can sit in the cars and talk to the different reps. The cars look nice, but this show room felt a little out of place for me. On the second floor is the library and restaurant, and on the lower level is an open meeting area. I learned that Onjium is a 1 Michelin Star out in Seoul. They curated the menu here with both modern and Korean techniques in iconic Korean recipes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aska</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I decided on this 2 Michelin Star restaurant located in the Williamsburg area. What appealed to me originally about this was that it was not just another French restaurant. French cuisine is great, but there are so many high end French restaurants around the city. Perhaps I am getting a little burnt out of having the same French tastes over and over, so I wanted something that was less normal. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had high end Scandinavian, so I thought today could be a good day. And to add, I had heard that they have non-alcoholic (juice) pairings, so I was excited to check this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:09:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Atera is a &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City. We&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go to this restaurant pre-pandemic, and each time we make a reservation, it was always cancelled due to shifts in NYC rules around the pandemic. Fortunately, the city is coming alive, and the reservation stuck this time around. We celebrated our very special anniversary at 5 PM. The cool thing about this restaurant that attracted me was that it had a temperament pairing of non-alcoholic juices. Although I would have liked to order the wine pairing, I always get full and drunk too fast with alcohol such that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the experience enjoyable. The restaurant is located on Worth Street, and it&amp;rsquo;s inside a building that looked very discreet on the outside. When you enter the building, the restaurant doors are directly on the left next to the elevators.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Bernardin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Le Bernardin is a &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City that primarily deals with seafood. The head chef is Eric Ripert, who is very well known in the higher end spectrum of the culinary world. We actually saw him on the floor with a mask on talking to some of the wait staff. This particular occasion was for a birthday celebration. Our reservation was at 5 PM, and it had to be reserved a month in advance. The spinning doors don&amp;rsquo;t actually open till 5 PM sharp, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a benefit to arrive before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:00:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indoor dining finally opened again in NYC on September 30, 2020. There are those that feel it&amp;rsquo;s reckless in this COVID temperament, but we still decided to celebrate by booking an indoor reservation at Cote, a 1 Michelin Star Korean BBQ restaurant. Normally, this is difficult to get a reasonable time, so we were happy it was not too bad. Like all upscale restaurants, they take your temperature via the forehead, and each table is partitioned by a plastic partition. Aside from air conditioning, there&amp;rsquo;s no way for your aerosols to hit another table unless you tried to spit a few feet up. There&amp;rsquo;s more than enough space between booths, so it was very enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Torishin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 14:29:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this special outing, Yakitori Torishin has been on my list ever since I moved to New York City. I finally had a chance to try this for the girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/torishin%2F1_restaurant.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted the regular yakitori experience as opposed to the select counter experience. The reason is that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine the value from yakitori at literally double the cost of a regular omakase. They brought us into the back room, and we were still seated in front of the chefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gabriel Kreuther</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be a big one. For our first anniversary, we treated ourselves to a nice French place that I think is generally underrated and under the radar. Gabriel Kreuthers has been something that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try, and it&amp;rsquo;s rated 2 Michelin Stars in 2019. We went bold with the &lt;strong&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Carte Blanche Tasting Menu&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a total of at least 28 dishes spread through of what they say is 9 courses.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ABC Cocina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/abc-cocina/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:34:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/abc-cocina/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This apparently is one of Jean Georges Vongerichten&amp;rsquo;s upscale farm-fresh eatery, and it has a Latin American fusion influence. We came here without reservations on a weekday night and were seated at the communal table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/abc-cocina%2F10_vanilla_fritters.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spring pea guacamole&lt;/strong&gt; with warm crunchy tortillas was actually pretty good. The chips themselves were nicely salted, and the big tortilla that came with the guacamole was more crunchy than the latter. The split pea guacamole had a nice fresh texture. I wish there was more citrus, but all in all a good start. The birthday friend I came here with thought it was amusing to interrupt my pictures during the n-times I took this picture. This one was the best of the collection of pics I took for this course.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blanca</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/blanca%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my first visit to Blanca back in September 2018, I was a solo diner and had just moved to New York City pretty recently. I wrote down, &amp;ldquo;Really good. Definitely get the drink pairing. Michelin 2 star. $300 per person including drinks.&amp;rdquo; The vibe and space was absolutely fantastic. I then met my partner, and the pandemic arrived. Blanca shutdown and just simply never reopened until a few weeks ago. Knowing how high in demand this restaurant was in the past, I decided to take my partner to this restaurant to re-live the experience again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blue Hill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/blue-hill/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:09:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/blue-hill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Place is pretty good but veggie centric. Pretty much farm to table kind of foods.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Delaware and Hudson</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:08:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;2016 and 2017 Michelin 1 star. Tasting only for dinner. Atlantic food. Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yuji Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yuji-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:20:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/yuji-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ramen omakase. Really good. Everything is homemade. $130 per person.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atoboy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atoboy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:52:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atoboy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Really good for the price point. $39 tasting 3 courses, no tip, and no dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 18:16:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marc-forgione%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;Marc Forgione&amp;rdquo;, this restaurant has moved from its prior Tribeca location to a different Tribeca location. Since then, they have lost their Michelin Star, but it is still a staple restaurant for those familiar with the history of this restaurant. It was quite easy to make reservations a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came here in 2012, I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Forgione is one of the Iron Chefs on Iron Chef America. This is his first restaurant, and at the time of this writing it has 1 Michelin Star. Like Michael Voltaggio, this restaurant is one of his babies, so he periodically is cooking in the kitchen to make sure everything comes out as he desires. Unfortunately he didn&amp;rsquo;t cook today, but I just want to preface this by saying this is definitely one of my favorite restaurants ever that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WD~50</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 17:59:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/wd-50%2F0_wylie.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first found out about WD~50 from my friend who wanted to try it out for the longest time. On research, I found out one of the Bravo&amp;rsquo;s Top Chef previous contestant owns this restaurant. His name is Wylie Dufresne. He is well known for pushing a movement towards molecular gastronomy, which is basically a different way to cook things. This 1 Michelin Star restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu is pretty sparse in choices in that you basically choose from 2 different types of tasting menus, the cheaper or the more expensive. Optionally, you could order 2 items off any of the tasting menus at the bar for $25. We of course opted for the expensive one considering we have no plans on coming back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>