<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brooklyn on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/brooklyn/</link><description>Recent content in Brooklyn on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/brooklyn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Din Soup Dumplings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:48:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/din-soup-dumplings/</guid><description>We had some tickets to attend one of those Fever &amp;ldquo;Candlelight&amp;rdquo; concert events that was located at a church right next to the &amp;ldquo;Court St&amp;rdquo; R-stop in Brooklyn. There was not too many options in terms of food within close vicinity. I looked at the prices for this soup dumpling place, and to my surprise, Din Soup Dumplings seemed not bad. My partner was also in a dumpling mood, so it was convenient to go check this place out.</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.
The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.</description></item><item><title>Gage and Tollner</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:28:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</guid><description>Gage and Tollner has been on my list for quite a while now. I was casually browsing for restaurants with baked alaska, and this had shown up high on people&amp;rsquo;s list. Whenever I had tried to look at reservations, it was pretty booked. I was very lucky to have found an open reservation for 2 at 5 PM on a Sunday the night before. So how did it go?</description></item><item><title>Hanon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hanon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 19:18:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hanon/</guid><description>Hanon is located in the North Williamsburg area and is literally across the street on Union St. from the Metropolitan G stop and diner. It has been awarded the Michelin 2021 Bib Gourmand award. It originated in Kamakura, Japan in the summer of 2018. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about this restaurant much at all and stumbled onto this through Yelp&amp;rsquo;s Hot &amp;amp; New filters. I wanted to try this restaurant out because the pictures of the udon sets look quite interesting, and the price point was pretty reasonable.</description></item><item><title>Republic Latin Fusion</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/republic-latin-fusion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 15:12:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/republic-latin-fusion/</guid><description>North Williamsburg just keeps on growing and gentrifying. I had lived here when I first moved to NYC, and 5+ years later, there are even more restaurants within such a small area. Similar to Manhattan, many restaurants are rotating ownership and leases. This restaurant is a relatively new latin fusion restaurant that had opened back in September 2021. It sits very close to McCarren park a few doors away from one of my favorite cheese steak places, Federoff&amp;rsquo;s Steaks.</description></item><item><title>Aska</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</guid><description>For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I decided on this 2 Michelin Star restaurant located in the Williamsburg area. What appealed to me originally about this was that it was not just another French restaurant. French cuisine is great, but there are so many high end French restaurants around the city. Perhaps I am getting a little burnt out of having the same French tastes over and over, so I wanted something that was less normal.</description></item><item><title>Bacchus</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/bacchus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 05:41:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/bacchus/</guid><description>We have not tried too many Brooklyn restaurants near the Barclays Center area for quite some time due to the pandemic. On this early brisk and semi-cold night, we had an interactive theater outing over at the One Hanson Place building in Brooklyn. After the event was over, a friend that we met at the event impromptly invited us to meet his friend at this restaurant. This was less than a mile away, and since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have other plans, we decided to try it out.</description></item><item><title>Andrea's Chicken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/andreas-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 20:45:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/andreas-chicken/</guid><description>My partner is fanatical about ceviche, and I am fanatical about lomo saltado. Our level of comparison is Mario&amp;rsquo;s in Los Angeles, and there has yet been a tolerable comparison to that so far. There are not too many Peruvian options in the Williamsburg area. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Chimu Bistro which was decent, and Llama Inn was a little too upscale. On this super sunny and muddy day after getting my hair chopped and despite all the plethora of options for anything but Peruvian, we decided to check out this restaurant based on recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Dokebi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/dokebi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:04:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/dokebi/</guid><description>Summary This Korean BBQ restaurant has been in North Williamsburg for a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to go to this, but prior to the pandemic, it was always easier to go to Koreatown since I was always in Manhattan. We arrived here at an early rainy Sunday afternoon. They follow COVID protocol very well, and there were very few people inside. The waitress took our temperature and address as usual, and then we were seated after.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Mogador</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-mogador/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:39:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-mogador/</guid><description>Summary To the outside world, the pandemic is wreaking havoc like wildfire. However for me personally, the only difference is that people are much more careful about cleanliness. In North Williamsburg, the brunch hipster spots are still thriving, and as you can imagine are very meticulous to avoid any type of spread.
Cafe Mogador has been one of those frequent brunch places that many flock to for weekend brunch. This is not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been here as I&amp;rsquo;ve always been neutral, but at least this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken pictures of some of the food.</description></item><item><title>Westlight</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 16:29:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</guid><description>Summary Westlight sits on the 22nd floor of the William Vale hotel in North Williamsburg. When you enter the lobby of the hotel, there is a line to the right that directs you to board the elevator. Upon arrival, the host will seat you on 1 of 2 floors. The 1st floor might be for reservations and has a waiter, whereas the 2nd floor might be for walk-ins. The 2nd floor has a fake grassy area with some patio tables/chairs, and you don&amp;rsquo;t get waiter service.</description></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aurora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 14:22:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aurora/</guid><description>Summary It&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to restart eating out again. Usually we just resort to delivery or takeout from various places nearby. However, it seems that many restaurants that are trying to outlast the pandemic by coming up with ideas to do the outdoor dining experience. Some restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t have a real patio, and you&amp;rsquo;re seated outside on the sidewalk within reach of people. And some restaurants like this one have a legit patio experience away from bystanders without worry.</description></item><item><title>High Lua Vietnamese Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 20:52:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/high-lua-vietnamese-kitchen/</guid><description>Summary As usual, the North Williamsburg area is a pretty hot spot for restaurants to eat at. I had lived in this area for about 2 years, but I still come back time to time to get a haircut. Usually after the haircut, I&amp;rsquo;ll check out something. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a decent pho place that is close enough to me such that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to travel to Flushing.</description></item><item><title>Kor Tor Mor</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/kor-tor-mor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 19:58:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/kor-tor-mor/</guid><description>Summary What&amp;rsquo;s nice about Thai food is they are rarely bad, and they are very consistent even at different restaurants. We were in Cobble Hill after an errand, and this place was relatively close by and open for a late afternoon dinner.
We got 2 different Thai teas. The first was the regular Thai tea and the other is Lychee Thai tea. Both were pretty good. The lychee might be sweet for some, but it tastes literally like the fruit.</description></item><item><title>Zen Yai Pho Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:38:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/zen-yai-pho-noodle-bar/</guid><description>Summary Pho vietnamese restaurants are generally pretty scarce in the city compared to Los Angeles. If you do find one, they usually don&amp;rsquo;t give you all the fixins and are timid about their offerings. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a restaurant called Phorage pretty frequently where their broth was very rich, and their meats were rare but tender. So how would this compare?
We started off with thai tea and matcha thai.</description></item><item><title>La Cafette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-cafette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 17:03:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-cafette/</guid><description>Summary This restaurant has been on my list for a while. Before I moved out of North Williamsburg, I wanted to eat something with pork. Unfortunately at the time, they were closed on a Tuesday for whatever reason, so I did not have the opportunity to try this place until today.
The ambiance is a dimly lit romantic setting right near the corner of Havenmayer. There were a lot of candles all over, and the tables were pretty close to each other reminding me of my time in Paris.</description></item><item><title>Paulie Gee's Slice Shop</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees-slice-shop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 19:47:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees-slice-shop/</guid><description>Summary This is Paulie Gee&amp;rsquo;s sliced pizza. You can order a whole pie if you want. All in all though, I think Vinnie&amp;rsquo;s in Brooklyn is better.
The pepperoni pizza was good but not great for slice. If you come here expecting a similar crust to what the original Paulie Gee&amp;rsquo;s serves, prepare to be disappointed. The crust is not that great compared to a lot of NYC sliced pizza places.</description></item><item><title>Paulie Gee's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 22:32:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees/</guid><description>Summary Came here around 5:30 PM on a Saturday, and the wait was quoted 60 minutes. In reality, it was just 45 minutes, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad.
The pizza itself is similar to Roberta&amp;rsquo;s. The pizza dough is pretty fluffy, and it tastes pretty good.
The Benny Gee had much better taste than Ricotta Be Kiddin Me. The ricotta pizza was more salty, but the Benny Gee definitely had a better well rounded profile.</description></item><item><title>Dinosaur BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/dinosaur-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 23:33:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/dinosaur-bbq/</guid><description>Summary I heard good raves about Dino BBQ from other people. The pickling of the salad is pretty good in general.
In the trio of meat, you will find pork belly, chicken, and brisket. The brisket to me was just ok. I think Hometown was much better. The pork belly was also ok. Surprisingly, I liked the chicken the best. It was tender and full of flavor and not overcooked. The collard greens were not memorable and neither was the cornbread.</description></item><item><title>Oxomoco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 23:50:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</guid><description>Summary This apparently received a coveted 1 Michelin Star at this time of writing.
Went here for brunch, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to go back to try the dinner. Just like Casa Enrique, I find it pretty good but pricey for what you get.
The horchata was tasty, but does not beat those horchata machines back in LA. Also, it was loaded with ice, so the amount of liquid you get is pretty small for $6.</description></item><item><title>Di an Di</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 19:28:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/di-an-di/</guid><description>The pho was ok, and so was the dried vermicelli. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit expensive for what you get, but also not bad. I probably would still prefer to go to other Vietnamese places, though good Vietnamese places are hard to find in Manhattan. The decor is nice, but food wise - if anyone likes this place, I don&amp;rsquo;t trust their palette.</description></item><item><title>Chimu Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chimu-bistro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/chimu-bistro/</guid><description>The ceviche was good, but the lomo saltado was surprisingly pretty good. Beef slices were tender.</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn Banh Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:15:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brooklyn-banh-mi/</guid><description>Best banh mi I&amp;rsquo;ve had so far in New York. Cheap too.
But this place is CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>Blanca</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</guid><description>In my first visit to Blanca back in September 2018, I was a solo diner and had just moved to New York City pretty recently. I wrote down, &amp;ldquo;Really good. Definitely get the drink pairing. Michelin 2 star. $300 per person including drinks.&amp;rdquo; The vibe and space was absolutely fantastic. I then met my partner, and the pandemic arrived. Blanca shutdown and just simply never reopened until a few weeks ago.</description></item><item><title>Delaware and Hudson</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:08:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</guid><description>2016 and 2017 Michelin 1 star. Tasting only for dinner. Atlantic food. Fantastic.</description></item></channel></rss>