<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>las on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/las/</link><description>Recent content in las on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 14:28:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/las/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>L'Atelier de Joel Robuchon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/latelier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 14:28:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/latelier/</guid><description>On the same weekend that I went to Sage, I also visited Joel Robuchon&amp;rsquo;s L&amp;rsquo;Atelier in the MGM Grand. The pricing of the food is slightly cheaper than the main Joel Robuchon restaurant next door. He also has a dozen of L&amp;rsquo;Atelier locations spread across the world. I heard this one was suppose to be pretty good, and after dining here, this hands down is the best Las Vegas restaurant I have been to so far.</description></item><item><title>Sage</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/sage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 14:08:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/sage/</guid><description>Sage is a popular American contemporary restaurant located in the Aria hotel on the Las Vegas strip. The head chef, Shawn McClain, won a few chef awards in the past decade. His executive chef, Richard Camarota, beat Iron Chef Marc Forgione on the the Food Network. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of name dropping here and there, so since my party was staying here, we decided to try this restaurant out based on the rave reviews on Yelp.</description></item><item><title>Burger Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/burger-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 14:01:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/burger-bar/</guid><description>Burger Bar is a small burger chain by French chef Hubert Keller. This place is basically a higher scale build-your-own burger restaurant where just about every ingredient costs some extra money.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. Las Vegas, even back in 2012, was pretty cool for a food haven. They had a ton of options, and they go through turnover pretty quickly.</description></item><item><title>RM Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/rm-seafood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 13:45:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/rm-seafood/</guid><description>In Las Vegas, Rick Moonen&amp;rsquo;s Seafood at the Mandalay Bay is suppose to be pretty good. There are 2 restaurants of his here: one is the fixed course meal higher end restaurant, and the other (this one) is just a middle tier restaurant. The menu is a little strange as they have your typical American no frills seafood AND sushi. My buddy ordered the sushi portions, and he was quite unimpressed.</description></item></channel></rss>