<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Italian on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/italian/</link><description>Recent content in Italian on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:18:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Santi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/santi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:18:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/santi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/santi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santi is a fine-dining Italian restaurant starring Chef Michael White. What was most noticeable for me was that he co-opened Marea, which ended up getting multiple accolades, including a coveted 2 Michelin Star. This restaurant is located very close to the 5th Ave and 53rd subway, and reservations were quite easy to get a few days in advance. The outside seemed different in that it felt like it was a side entrance into a place on the side a building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sartiano's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sartianos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sartianos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sartianos%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sartiano&amp;rsquo;s opened around June 2023, replacing the former &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/"&gt;The Mercer Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;. The menu is helmed by James Beard Award-winning chef Alfred Portale. This is located near the SOHO shopping area right across the street from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lure-fishbar/"&gt;Lure Fishbar&lt;/a&gt;. I easily made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM a few days in advance. When we arrived, the place was beginning to become lively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interior is very dark, just like the former Mercer Kitchen restaurant. In many ways, they did not change much of the ambiance here. It felt like a very glowing, happening night spot for a nice night out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Isabelle's Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/isabelles-osteria/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:57:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/isabelles-osteria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/isabelles-osteria%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a scramble to look for a restaurant in the Union Square area, I stumbled onto this one, which is about 3 streets north of Union Square. The menu itself looked pretty normal, and when I arrived, the weather was very nice and calm. They had patio seating, and they opened the windows to let the fall breeze seep into the area. I made a reservation for 2 for 6 PM easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cecconi's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cecconis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 12:42:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cecconis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cecconis%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a new camera to play with, we&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to make an effort to travel around the city to practice taking pictures and learning more about the camera. At some point, I&amp;rsquo;ll start another website sharing and expressing what I got. For now, we were hungry in the Dumbo area, and the bathroom lines to wash your hands were long in the public restroom area within the Timeout Market section. My partner was really irked, so we decided to just walk into Cecconi&amp;rsquo;s to see if we can be seated. The outdoor section had a wait of upwards of 50 minutes, but the indoor seating was all ready to go. We were seated immediately at 4:30 PM on a Saturday late afternoon without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Becco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:05:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/becco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becco was on our list for a while. This restaurant in the Theater District was always full around theater times, so of course, that&amp;rsquo;s naturally alluring. It was first opened in 1993 by Lidia Bastianich and her son, Joe, who you might recognize from the U.S. version of the MasterChef series. The Yelp ratings of the food seem surprisingly low compared to the Google counterpart, so that increase our curiosity. We were able to easily make a reservation the earlier in the day for 5:15 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Leopard at Des Artistes</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 21:17:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-leopard-at-des-artistes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-leopard-at-des-artistes%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show to catch at the Lincoln Center, and the area had a lot of New American and Italian restaurants within half a mile. We&amp;rsquo;ve rarely explored anywhere north of 60th St. This area is just across the street on the lower west side of Central Park. The restaurant itself is located in a historic residential building called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hotel_des_Artistes"&gt;Hotel des Artistes&lt;/a&gt;. I was easily able to make a reservation the day before for a 5:15 PM on a Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Locanda Verde</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:55:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/locanda-verde%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef Andrew Carmellini has some pretty good restaurants (&lt;a href="https://www.nhgnyc.com/"&gt;NoHo Hospitality&lt;/a&gt;) that we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. Some recent ones that we really enjoyed include &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/"&gt;Cafe Carmellini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/"&gt;Carne Mare&lt;/a&gt;. Locanda Verde opened a second location in the Hudson Yards area. This is his ode to urban Italian cuisine, and we wanted to try this out because the exterior seemed very nice. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:15 on a Friday evening without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/il-divino%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roscioli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:46:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/roscioli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/roscioli%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roscioli has been on my list for a while since the original location of this restaurant is in Rome. This New York City alternative offers a pasta tasting menu, which looked quite interesting and affordable. I was able to book a reservation about a few weeks out for a 6 PM dinner. Keep in mind that the tasting is located downstairs, whereas the normal restaurant is located street level.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giorgio's of Gramercy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 21:51:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giorgios-of-gramercy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/giorgios-of-gramercy%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our quest to find all the &amp;ldquo;Baked Alaska&amp;rdquo; restaurants in NYC, this was one that I was surprised to have it priced reasonably. Looking at the menu, everything was affordable compared to the rest of Manhattan. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest that I have never heard of this restaurant, and this came up randomly in my search. We easily made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/azalea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sicily%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-delbianco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss. The prices seemed reasonable, so we decided to try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/amarone-scarlatto%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bad-roman%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/about/the-team/"&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; that created this restaurant also helped create &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/"&gt;Quality Eats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant is very bustling, with lots of noise and all types of clientele. You will find many on their date nights, and you will find big parties celebrating something as if they were celebrities. The noise level is pretty loud, and you are seated pretty close to other tables. The music is also on the louder side too, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t uncomfortably loud. At times it was hard to hear our server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria Morini</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-morini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 21:01:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-morini/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-morini%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nice part about Manhattan is you can always find something and somewhere to eat, no matter where you are in the city. On this brisk, cold night, my partner was running errands in Soho, so I was tasked with looking up something. Of course, it takes me about 30 minutes to find something, and Osteria Morini is what we ended up on. Even though they had restaurant week menus, we decided to just order off the regular menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:56:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally during every Thanksgiving Thursday, I cook for my partner some poultry thing whether it be quail or turkey breast. This year we decided to relieve me the duties of frantically looking for materials and cooking for 6 hours for the 2 of us. Marea was closed for a few months, and we&amp;rsquo;ve always had this on our list. Because it just reopened in October, I decided to pursue the Thanksgiving tasting menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aperitivo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aperitivo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 19:11:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aperitivo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aperitivo%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s yet another Friday, and my partner had to pick up some items around the southeast part of Central Park. This area is fairly close to the Plaza Hotel and the flagship Apple store. This restaurant was on my eyes for a while, but my partner hadn&amp;rsquo;t built their tolerance or appreciation for Italian food until recently. Fortunately, I finally had a chance to suggest this restaurant as our Friday getaway. We were able to do a walk-in on a Friday evening around 5:45 PM without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trattoria Dell'arte</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/trattoria-dellarte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/trattoria-dellarte/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/trattoria-dellarte%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near this area because we stopped by Nordstroms for some shopping. This area is pretty close to the southern side of Central Park, and we&amp;rsquo;ve almost tapped out all the restaurants here (or so I thought). Luckily my partner has continued to show interest in Italian foods because I love it. I found this restaurant that wasn&amp;rsquo;t that far from where we were, and it was also offering a 3 course prix fixe restaurant week menu for $45. We were able to walk in around 4:30 PM on a Sunday without any reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giardino 54</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/giardino-54%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near Broadway and 50th to watch the Back to the Future musical, which was actually surprisingly good. After, we had wanted Thai food, but the restaurant was closed briefly. My partner didn&amp;rsquo;t use the restrooms at the theater, so I scrambled for another option that had a restroom and found this restaurant off of 54th. We were able to walk in without reservations for 2 at around 5:30 PM on a Saturday night. The host said that the &amp;ldquo;garden&amp;rdquo; was saved for just reservations, which we were fine with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cucina 8 1/2</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cucina-8.5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:25:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cucina-8.5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cucina-8.5%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were running errands around 5th Avenue, and this restaurant was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list. I learned that my partner picked this restaurant because it was on Sex &amp;amp; The City, so I had very low expectations. We stopped by around 5:30 PM on a Friday night, and we were able to walk in without reservations. The restaurant itself is at the bottom of the staircase as you walk in. We were seated in one of the private booths, which was quite comfortable and serene.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pizzarte</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 12:06:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pizzarte%2F0_logo.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PizzArte is one of those casual Italian pizza-esque restaurants in the Midtown area. Their goal is to deliver the spirit of Naples with affordable costs. We ended up here after looking for a cheaper Italian restaurant in the area that also had lasagna since we had more expensive plans the next day. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Friday evening around 7:30 PM and were seated upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria La Baia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-la-baia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:13:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-la-baia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-la-baia%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s an Italian restaurant in Midtown that didn&amp;rsquo;t require reservations at 6 PM on a Friday evening after work? This one. It&amp;rsquo;s very close to the Rockafeller area, right across the street from a food hall. There&amp;rsquo;s a small car with a ton of flowers coming out of it. You can&amp;rsquo;t really miss it. We were able to walk in pretty easily, and we were seated towards the front. Because this restaurant is not exactly super popular, the attention and seating was quite comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Duomo 51</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/duomo-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:06:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/duomo-51/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/duomo-51%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Memorial Day weekend, we&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying our free time just idling at home and doing chores. For Monday, my partner wanted to run some errands, and we were around the Rockafeller area. Because it was still a bit early around 4 PM, it was difficult to find restaurants that had already turned over to their dinner time. Eventually, my partner pointed out this restaurant, and we decided to give it a try. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the 7th floor of the Hilton DoubleTree hotel on 5th Ave and 51st.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Olio E Più</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/olio-e-piu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 15:27:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/olio-e-piu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/olio-e-piu%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olio e Più is a trattoria &amp;amp; enoteca restaurant run by the same group that manages &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/"&gt;Boucherie&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s close to the West 4th station in the Village, and it usually has a very lively crowd as it gets toward evening hours. Before the pandemic, the restaurant table space was quite small and tight. Since, they&amp;rsquo;ve expanded structurally a patio that extends out of the main building, as well as little sidewalk area that is enclosed. If you desire to sit in the actual indoor areas (i.e. not the patio area or the sidewalk area), you probably have to make a reservation a few weeks in advance and book the &amp;ldquo;Standard&amp;rdquo; area in OpenTable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Masseria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 16:35:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-masseria%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had tickets to watch Phantom of the Opera before it closes in April, and my partner was scouring for some type of restaurant week menu to eat. They landed on this restaurant which is pretty close by as it had last minute vacancy. I already had very low expectations on some of these Italian restaurants that are close to theaters especially ones that are restaurant week driven. The restaurant week menu had some overlap with the normal dishes, but the ingredients to me did not really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Felice</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/felice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 16:35:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/felice/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/felice%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felice appears to be an Italian premium chain restaurant with locations around New York and Florida. We were around the area shopping and walking around for errands of course, and my partner fortunately has been on an Italian binge recently. They really love lasagna, and this restaurant nearby had it on its menu. We were able to walk in on a Sunday without reservation at around 5:30 PM. When you walk in, it appears to be a coffee shop with a barista. The restaurant is actually located on the bottom floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cotenna</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cotenna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:30:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cotenna/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cotenna%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Village is an area that we had walked through at times, but we never really tried many restaurants. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible from both where my partner works and where I work. They picked this restaurant at the whim, and the menu looked pretty interesting and also straight forward. I was able to secure a reservation for 5:30 PM the day of without much difficulties. When you arrive here, there seems to be a little sibling restaurant, Aria Wine bar, across the street which seems to have a similar menu. Unfortunately, I did not see a restaurant sign for this one until I stared at the menu taped to the wall and noticed it said Cotenna.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Piccola Cucina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 15:28:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Piccola Cucina other than that it&amp;rsquo;s real close to Bloomingdales in Midtown. When we tried to stop in at 5:30 PM as a walk-in many months ago, they told us there was a 2 hour wait. Since we knew today we were going to be around the area, I saw they had a few openings and quickly booked a reservation for 6 PM for 2. This review is for the Midtown Uptown location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Serafina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serafina/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 15:18:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serafina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/serafina%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near the Columbus Circle area just shopping and walking around. Generally, this area doesn&amp;rsquo;t have too many great places to eat, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide what we were in the mood for. I had proposed the thought of Serafina since I&amp;rsquo;ve never been there and my partner had a fantastic experience back in their home country. We were able to walk in without reservations during the core hours of dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Piatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:10:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow gotten my partner to enjoy pasta a bit more. Some sacrifices have to be made such as looking for lasagna, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. I have to thank Tony Soprano and how he always made Italian sandwiches and pasta look so delicious. We had to stop by the pharmacy, and nearby was this incognito Italian wood fire pizza place. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Saturday evening around 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Da Andrea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/da-andrea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 19:59:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/da-andrea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having been on a Sopranos binge, the first thought that came to mind was just simply pasta. We were in the Flatiron area and decided to walk down to 13th to check out this Italian restaurant because the menu looked simple and straight forward. We arrived at 5:30 PM on a Saturday evening as a party of 2, and they accommodated us in the back of the restaurant without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/carne-mare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quality Italian</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 19:31:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were around the Bloomingdales area running some errands back and forth around the Midtown East area and decided to take the risk of looking for a restaurant without making reservations since we normally eat dinner fairly early. This Quality Italian seems to be from the same owners of Quality Meats and Quality Bistro which are on my list. Quality Italian is a modern take on the Italian American steakhouse tradition, and the prices are probably on the mid to high range.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Manducatis Rustica</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 16:43:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/manducatis-rustica/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve visited most of the Long Island City restaurants around the Vernon Blvd area. We had stopped by Blend on the Water hopefully for a walk-in, but there was already a wait. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by Manducatis Rustica several times, and we figured it was worth a shot to see if they can take us. When we arrived, there was hardly anyone there. They told us that they had garden seating, so we opted for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Milkflower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 17:02:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/milkflower/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Astoria has a lot of nice gems for affordable prices. My partner wanted to do a nice walk and try out this restaurant per recommendation from their friend. At first glance at the menu, I was thinking this seems kind of ok. I had already done the artisan pizza several times, so my expectations were pretty low. I read many reviews, but I was skeptical because they were all pretty positive. But this is Astoria, and it&amp;rsquo;s known for having good food, so I was very pleasantly surprised how my experience turned out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Levante</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/levante/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new Trader Joes opened up in Long Island City, and I was hoping to make turkey tacos with guacamole. Unfortunately, the avocados were not ripe enough yet, so I mentioned to my partner we can eat out. The first thought that came to their mind was this place because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few nearby restaurants we have not tried yet but have seen a lot of people standing outside. Ever since I moved here, I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept glancing at the menu, but nothing really screamed at me that I have to try it. But now that I have tried it, how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Angie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant had been on my peripheral for a while because of the lasagna dish. I didn&amp;rsquo;t decide to try to book a reservation until I learned it was awarded its first ever Michelin Star. I had tried a few times on Resy, but always missed it. Fortunately, I was able to land a reservation on a weekend at 5 PM EST. The restaurant itself is in West Village and felt like a typical trendy cafe in the area. The tables were social distanced, and had a nice romantic setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Allora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 19:34:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/allora/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was our second anniversary, and it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat difficult to find a decent restaurant that has an outdoor garden that is away from the crowd. After staying up till 4 AM looking for one, I finally found one that was decent. The garden seating area is actually in the back of the restaurant, so there&amp;rsquo;s very little foot traffic from random people. Luckily the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t hot at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aurora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 14:22:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/aurora/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to restart eating out again. Usually we just resort to delivery or takeout from various places nearby. However, it seems that many restaurants that are trying to outlast the pandemic by coming up with ideas to do the outdoor dining experience. Some restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t have a real patio, and you&amp;rsquo;re seated outside on the sidewalk within reach of people. And some restaurants like this one have a legit patio experience away from bystanders without worry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Maiella</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 15:42:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/maiella%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight was another venture out to the area around Vernon Blvd. There are so many restaurants here to try. This one here is an Italian restaurant near Gantry park. There are a lot of cars for some reason compared to other parts of Long Island City. The restaurant was able to accommodate us as a pair of walk-ins at around 6:30 PM on a Saturday evening easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tony's Di Napoli</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/tonys-di-napoli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 22:35:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/tonys-di-napoli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tony&amp;rsquo;s Di Napoli is a NYC Italian American restaurant that has been around for a number of decades. It&amp;rsquo;s probably comparable to Buca Di Beppo or Maggiano, but it is less of a domestic chain than a NYC chain. They serve family style portions, and they have both half and full sizes of many of their pastas. This particular location is located in Times Square, and normally I shy away from this. So how did it go?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wolf</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/wolf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 17:37:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/wolf/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re around the Rockafeller area and are looking for pretty decent Italian food at a not overly expensive price, this restaurant might be a good candidate. It is located on the 2nd floor of the Nordstrom NYC flagship store near the watches section. We walked in without reservations around 5:30 PM, and we were seated at the bar fairly quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/wolf%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Nordstrom doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the drinks menu online, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping my memory serves me well. The left is a &lt;strong&gt;mai thai&lt;/strong&gt;, and the right is a &lt;strong&gt;mezcal cocktail&lt;/strong&gt;. The mai thai was doused with passion fruit liqueur which is why I got it in the first place. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too strong, and everything tasted very tropically and subtle. The mezcal cocktail had a slight smokey flavor to it. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what else was in this though, but it definitely was sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Go Nonna</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/go-nonna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 22:44:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/go-nonna/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a local restaurant to Long Island City that classifies itself as an Italian Argentine restaurant. The place is super small, but it feels nice and cozy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/go-nonna%2F1_chicken_piccata.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;chicken piccata&lt;/strong&gt; is served with capers in a lemon and butter sauce, served with roasted potatoes. This dish was actually really good. The potatoes had a nice crunch to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/go-nonna%2F2_lasagna_marchigiane.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;lasagna marchigiane&lt;/strong&gt; has bechamel, bolognese, and parmigiano. The tomato sauce was pretty good. It was sweet with a little sour to it, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was homemade or not. I wish the texture was more chunky though, but still it was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Incident</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/spaghetti-incident/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:12:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/spaghetti-incident/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another restaurant on my list to go. I am not crazy about Italian, but I was hungry and wanted something pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/spaghetti-incident%2F1_lasagna.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;lasagna bolognese&lt;/strong&gt; came with ground beef, béchamel, and tomato sauce. The pasta consisted of several very thin sheets with a thin layer of ground beef between each. Careful though, the lasagna was piping hot. It was pretty good, but I think I would&amp;rsquo;ve preferred more sauce and more cheese as an ode to the normal lasagnas you&amp;rsquo;d normally get. Otherwise, I think it was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vapiano</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/vapiano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 14:02:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/vapiano/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vapiano seems like it&amp;rsquo;s a chained Italian fast eatery. For the NYC location, the front desk gives you a card, and you walk up to a pasta station if you want pasta or a pizza station if you want pizza. You then tell the cook what you want, and they make it fresh in front of you. They ask that you take the card and tap the screen with it to get it charged with what you ordered. After you finish your meal, you pay as the cashier as you exit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Uva</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/uva/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 16:20:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/uva/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is located in the Upper East, and arguably walkable from the MET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/uva%2F1_spiedino_di_gamberetti.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spiedino di gamberetti&lt;/strong&gt; was OK to me. Nothing really memorable, but they gave you a decent amount of shrimp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/uva%2F2_antipasto_misto.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;antipasto misto&lt;/strong&gt; was actually pretty good, and they gave a decent variety of meats and cheese. For 2 people, this was quite filling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/uva%2F3_pappardelle_al_ragu_di_vitello.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pappardelle al ragu di vitello&lt;/strong&gt; was good as expected. The pasta could have been cooked just a tad less, but the sauce it sat in was pretty good. The cheese on top was freshly grated by the server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Serra at La Birreria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serra-at-la-birreria/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 15:35:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serra-at-la-birreria/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came by in the spring when they boasted of lush flowers and decorations. Apparently the flowers were not real, but that still does not stop it to become a very photo friendly place. It still is nice during the day because they opened the canopy, and so there was a nice breeze coming in. I think for food, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of hit, but the ambiance is pretty appealing to those who want to get a drink and just enjoy the colors for photos.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sosta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-sosta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:58:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-sosta/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place was ok. Pasta was good, but it needs protein. The meat cheese board was just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lilia Caffe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lilia-caffe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:56:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lilia-caffe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Had to make reservations 30 days ahead of time. Food was decent. Interior is nice. Homemade pasta. Good date place. Slightly overrated. Very similar to Culver City Bucato (before it shuttered) a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Sodi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/i-sodi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:55:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/i-sodi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Food was just ok even though it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended by people. Probably a good date place though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lasagna Ristorante</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lasagna-ristorante/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:53:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/lasagna-ristorante/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of food for lunch and just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gran Sasso</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/gran-sasso/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:51:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/gran-sasso/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Really good. Homemade pasta, and steak was good. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t that expensive either. Has been renamed to Scriptum Brooklyn. Not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s the same place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Grazie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/grazie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:49:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/grazie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I only ate here because it was close to the MET. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what I had, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only written that it was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bacaro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/bacaro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 15:50:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/bacaro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bacaro%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of food porn pics that I haven&amp;rsquo;t put online yet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll get through it. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know already, I went to New York City this past February and tried out some of the local hot spots. This is my first time to the east coast, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t care for any of the touristy places. My buddy and I, per recommendation, went to Bacaro which is Italian inspired cuisine. My plane had just landed about an hour and a half ago, and this is the first place that we went to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>