<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Animal Kingdom Lodge on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/animal-kingdom-lodge/</link><description>Recent content in Animal Kingdom Lodge on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:51:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/animal-kingdom-lodge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/boma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:51:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/boma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Boma is the last African centric restaurant that we&amp;rsquo;ve made reservations for on this trip. It sits across from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/jiko/"&gt;Jiko&lt;/a&gt; on the first floor of the Animal Kingdom Lodge. Around dinner time, this area was quite busy and seemed to have a lot of people. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much expectations at all since it was just a buffet, but it was interesting to see how they laid the food outside and let people get what they want instead of being served.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jiko</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/jiko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 13:07:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/jiko/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jiko recently reopened a few weeks ago, and we were fortunate to nab a reservation for 5. The unfortunate part was that it was real late at night at around 9 PM. Despite this inconvenience, we were very much looking forward to this dinner because we had heard great things about it prior to its closure. African cuisine is unfamiliar to my palette, so it was quite exciting to see how Disney would present it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sanaa Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/sanaa-lounge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:13:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/sanaa-lounge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is our first day of our 2022 Disney World trip and what a rush this day was. Our flight from NYC was delayed by 3 hours, and it was inevitable that we were going to miss our original booking for Sanaa. Fortunately when we arrived very late, the restaurant accommodated us into the lounge. We had reservations much later in the evening for Jiko, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get too full. Sanaa is located in the Kidani village which is further down the road as you enter the Animal Kingdom Lodge area. There is a convenient shuttle that goes back and forth between the Kidani Village villas and the main Animal Kingdom Lodge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>