<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flushing on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/flushing/</link><description>Recent content in Flushing on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/flushing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Woodam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/woodam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 20:02:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/woodam/</guid><description>Woodam is a Korean gukbap house that serves a very few options in the Flushing area. Gukbap is basically a Korean dish where you can put rice into a very flavorful soup, and it is iconic rustic, comfort food in Korean homes. We were in the area, and I thought this was basic enough to take some elders that were sensitive to sodium and strong spices. We were able to walk in for a party of 4 around lunch time without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Gan Hoo BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:11:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/gan-hoo-bbq/</guid><description>Flushing is the NYC mecca for Chinese food. It&amp;rsquo;s at the end of the 7 train line heading east, and it takes about 40 minutes from Manhattan on weekends. Many restaurants and stalls only accept cash, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite different than being in Manhattan or Long Island City. My partner had a friend that wanted to meet in Flushing to try out Korean BBQ. I thought there would be several near Main Street, but it seems all the decent Korean BBQ places are least a mile east of the Main street subway station.</description></item><item><title>Imperial Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/imperial-palace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 22:13:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/imperial-palace/</guid><description>Summary It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a trek, but it&amp;rsquo;s a much cheaper place for Peking Duck.
The whole peking duck was actually pretty good and reasonably price. The skin was a nice crisp, and the duck was pleasantly fat.
The fried shrimp was mistakenly ordered. We thought it was going to be the whole pepper salted shrimp with head. Even then, it was also decent.
The other dishes, pea sprouts and yang chow fried rice, were not much different than other Chinese places.</description></item><item><title>Shanghai You Garden</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shanghai-you-garden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 13:43:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/shanghai-you-garden/</guid><description>Known for their XLBs, it was pretty darn tasty. They also have stinky tofu too and it&amp;rsquo;s all pretty cheap.</description></item><item><title>ChaTime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/chatime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:27:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/chatime/</guid><description>Passion fruit green tea was just OK.</description></item><item><title>Kulu Desserts</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/kulu-desserts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:25:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/kulu-desserts/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s ok. Lots of durian stuff. Black sesame wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great.</description></item><item><title>Prince Tea House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/prince-tea-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:18:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/prince-tea-house/</guid><description>Good crepes and milk tea. The decor is interesting here.
The iced passionfruit green tea was a nice drink for the hot summer weather.
The takoyaki was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>New May Wah 359</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/new-may-wah-359/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:32:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/new-may-wah-359/</guid><description>Taiwanese food. Rice cakes good. Everything else eh. Cash only.
This place is PERMA closed.</description></item><item><title>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:29:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</guid><description>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao is one of those XLB restaurants that is not often brought up in the XLB fights because it&amp;rsquo;s not that accessible. The original location is in Flushing, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit far from Manhattan. Many people do end up going to Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai to get their fix, but fortunately now a Manhattan location of this restaurant has opened in Koreatown.
I had originally gone to the Flushing location and said the following:</description></item></channel></rss>