<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Theater District on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/theater-district/</link><description>Recent content in Theater District on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 21:45:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/theater-district/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baires Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 21:45:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/baires-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw an early afternoon theater show, and right after, we decided to check out Argentine food. Baires Grill was appealing because it is a Miami chain, and this is their only non-Miami location. We are planning on visiting Miami in the near future, so I was curious to see how this food differs than other Argentine restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. We walked in around 4 PM on a Saturday without reservations, and they seated us immediately without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rosevale Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rosevale-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was another Broadway showing that we had to attend. Our theater district restaurant pool is thinning a bit, so this one was somewhat difficult to locate. It reminds me of a Midtown staple type of restaurant that is very friendly to the theater crowd, and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get in. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening around 5 PM without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Becco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:05:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/becco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becco was on our list for a while. This restaurant in the Theater District was always full around theater times, so of course, that&amp;rsquo;s naturally alluring. It was first opened in 1993 by Lidia Bastianich and her son, Joe, who you might recognize from the U.S. version of the MasterChef series. The Yelp ratings of the food seem surprisingly low compared to the Google counterpart, so that increase our curiosity. We were able to easily make a reservation the earlier in the day for 5:15 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/il-divino%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-view%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/"&gt;Manhatta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Modern&lt;/a&gt;. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like. Previously when this was opened, it was a buffet with &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/the-view-restaurant-and-lounge-new-york"&gt;not-so-great rated food&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/"&gt;Mari&lt;/a&gt;. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/"&gt;Le Bernardin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/"&gt;Le Rock&lt;/a&gt;. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night. The restaurant is located on the second floor, but you check in on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kausa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kausa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had won another theater tickets for this Sunday, so we looked for a place nearby. My partner desired Peruvian food again, specifically lomo saltado. The best lomo saltado place we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had was actually &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/"&gt;Mario&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a comparable place, especially in New York City. We walked in on a late Sunday afternoon without issues, and we were seated promptly. Looking over the menu, they had your typical Peruvian options.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xie Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:58:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xie-bao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show this evening, and this &amp;ldquo;crab house&amp;rdquo; just recently opened in Manhattan. This originated from a Flushing stall, and their specialty is crab roe over rice or noodle. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening without reservations. The social media circuit really raved about this dish by showing off the roe, so we decided to try it. I figured there was no need to make reservations since Manhattan Midtown Chinese restaurants are usually pretty easy to get into.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Danji</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:18:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/danji%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danji is Chef Hooni Kim&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that opened 15 years ago. It earned a Michelin Star back in 2012 and closed in April 2023 due to a fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, which was phenomenal for what it was. We decided to check out this to see how it was, so I made a reservation pretty easily a week prior for 5:30 PM for a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SaiTong Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 11:11:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/saitong-thai%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SaiTong Thai was a relatively new Thai restaurant that opened near the Theater District. One of its allures is that it appears to be an upscale Thai restaurant. The menu when I glanced at it seemed pretty decent although the prices were on the higher side. Since we had a theater date, we decided to check this restaurant out. We easily made a reservation for a Saturday at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pure Thai Cookhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pure-thai-cookhouse%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won yet another lottery for one of the theater shows, so we were hoping to walk into Wondee Thai. As expected, there was a line outside and a wait inside, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble missing the show if we had waited. We instead opted to walk a block south to this restaurant which had no patrons. We were able to walk in for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Saturday night without reservations. There seemed to be 2 sections to this restaurant, a left and a right. We were seated on the left on a small table with stools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/azalea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mari%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cafe-un-deux-trois%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sicily%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/amarone-scarlatto%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heno Heno</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:42:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/heno-heno%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had won some tickets to watch Appropriate on Broadway starring Sarah Paulson. The show starts at 8, but we had to pick up the will-call tickets by 7:30. I saw this Japanese small eatery was nearby the theater on 46th St, and I thought this would be a decent restaurant to try out since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of little things we can order. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening at around 5:30 PM before it got busy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Havana Central</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/havana-central%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was raining on this gloomy Friday, and we wanted to eat somewhere close to Rockafeller. I recalled we had tried to walk into this restaurant on prior days with no success. I looked them up on OpenTable and saw that they had openings throughout the night. We figured it was worth a shot to try to walk in, and we found success. We were seated next to the door inside a glass section of the restaurant towards the front at around 6:30 PM. There was a live trio band playing Cuban style music, and some people dancing near the entrance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Roosters</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 13:11:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/three-roosters%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been just demolishing a ton of restaurants around the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/theater-district/"&gt;Theater District&lt;/a&gt; since we&amp;rsquo;ve been going to a lot of Broadway shows. This restaurant was on our eyes to go to, but they always take a small break between 4 to 5 PM, so it can put a little time crunch if you have a show around 6:30 to 7 PM. However despite the restaurant being small with probably 5 or 6 tables, we were able to walk in on a Sunday evening around 5:30 PM without reservations. The food here is less about your normal Thai food, and more about chicken set meals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hunt &amp; Fish Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:02:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hunt-and-fish-club%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner was able to secure another show lottery near Times Square. Because I work near here and the fact that they have been able to win so many lottery shows, we&amp;rsquo;re running out of choices for restaurants. We were walking along 44th, and we stumbled onto this restaurant. After looking at the menu and the ability to walk in without reservations, we decided to try out this restaurant, Hunt &amp;amp; Fish Club. We were able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Friday without reservations easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari.ne Handroll</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:57:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marine-handroll%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari.ne (MariNe) Hand-Roll Bar is similar to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kazunori/"&gt;KazuNori&lt;/a&gt; where it&amp;rsquo;s simply a &amp;ldquo;hand roll&amp;rdquo; bar. The hand rolls are fairly small, but quite delightful and fresh. You can order them in different flavors, and it&amp;rsquo;s sure to satisfy anyone that enjoys sushi in hand roll format. We were able to walk in at around 5:45 PM on a Monday evening, but we were told that we had to be done by 6:30 PM due to an upcoming reservation. More on this in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avra Estiatorio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:32:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/avra-estiatorio%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avra Estiatorio was a restaurant that we wanted to check out for a while now. Because we were going to watch Gutenberg Musical at 8 PM, this fit perfectly for the opportunity. Avra has several locations spread throughout the United States: 3 in Manhattan, 1 in Miami, and 1 in Beverly Hills. It&amp;rsquo;s a rather posh Greek seafood restaurant, and it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to all the other upper end ones, such as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/"&gt;Limani&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/"&gt;Milos&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to walk in at around 6 PM without reservations, and we were seated at the upper floor. When we met the hostess, they asked if we were seeing a show, and we acknowledged that we were.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Four Four South Village</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/four-four-south-village%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese food is one of the types of cuisines that is seldomly found in Manhattan and just simply cannot compare to the San Gabriel Valley in the greater Los Angeles area in California. I asked my partner before a show if they wanted to check this out, and to my surprise they said yes! Normally they are not fond of this type of food, especially when noodles are around. This is not too far from Broadway theaters. We were able to walk in around 5:30 PM on a Monday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chalong</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 19:25:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chalong%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show to go to around 43rd and 9th Ave, so we decided to look around the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. In this area from my research, there seems to be some pretty good Thai restaurants that have been here for a bit or are opening up. We had recently gone to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/lumlum/"&gt;LumLum&lt;/a&gt;, which focused on more Northern Thai cuisine. Here in Chalong which is on 9th Ave between 51st and 52nd, they are focused on more Southern Thai. This restaurant is a few months old, and we were able to get a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM the night prior to our arrival.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oceana</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:13:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oceana%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice parts of living and working in Manhattan is that there is so much you can do and improvise after work. We had a show at 8 PM from winning a lottery, so it was easy to meet up after work and look for something to eat. Pre-theater prix fixe menus are a nice thing. They are basically a small tasting menu that won&amp;rsquo;t fill your belly too much, and the price is reasonable. We ended up at Oceana here since we realized we were within its small pre-theater hours of 5-6 PM on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Charlie Palmer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/charlie-palmer%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had yet another show to catch, so we decided to look around the Bryant Park area. I stumbled onto Charlie Palmer, and it had been on my list of steak places to try. What was nice about this place specifically is they offered a 2-course pre-theatre menu for $49 which included a starter and entree. If you wanted dessert, you would have to pay an additional $10. Lucky for us, we weren&amp;rsquo;t that hungry, so a 2-course meal sounded fine for us. The waiter mentioned that the portion size for either course was the same as if you ordered in peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sake Bar Hagi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-bar-hagi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 16:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-bar-hagi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sake-bar-hagi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re back from Hawaii, we went to go see Sweeney Todd, a musical that was one of my favorites. Nearby, we decided to eat something quick and light, so we opted for izakaya. Sake Bar Hagi, according to their website, says it&amp;rsquo;s New York&amp;rsquo;s first authentic izakaya since 1985. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what that really means, but we&amp;rsquo;ll find out. We arrived around 5:30 PM on a Saturday evening, and we were seated immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prime Meat Rokko</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/prime-meat-rokko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 23:01:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/prime-meat-rokko/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/prime-meat-rokko%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area catching up on a Broadway musical called &amp;ldquo;MJ: The Musical&amp;rdquo; based on Michael Jackson. This area we have rarely explored much, considering early post-pandemic, this area was quite dangerous with the drug users and harassers. Nevertheless, this katsu restaurant has been on my list for years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to check this out. We were able to walk in on a Sunday at around 5:30 PM without any issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Masseria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 16:35:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-masseria%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had tickets to watch Phantom of the Opera before it closes in April, and my partner was scouring for some type of restaurant week menu to eat. They landed on this restaurant which is pretty close by as it had last minute vacancy. I already had very low expectations on some of these Italian restaurants that are close to theaters especially ones that are restaurant week driven. The restaurant week menu had some overlap with the normal dishes, but the ingredients to me did not really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gordon Ramsay Fish and Chips</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 23:09:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Times Square area, and this new fast food fish and chips restaurant just opened from Gordon Ramsay. The restaurant also has locations in Las Vegas, Orlando, DC, and now New York City. Gordon Ramsay used to have restaurants opened in NYC, but they have all been closed for quite some time. This is the only restaurant that he now has in NYC. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Silky Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:41:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, I can grab food for myself after work, and I tend to look for noodles. My partner is not a fan at all of noodles, so I took this liberty to look for something that they would not enjoy. Despite the hot and humid weather in NYC, I rarely mind eating hot soups with noodles. Silky Kitchen has a location near where I live in Astoria, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try out its location out in Midtown near Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Black Iron Burger</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-iron-burger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 10:47:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-iron-burger/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/black-iron-burger%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rare occasion nowadays, I am able to sometimes grab dinner solo somewhere. I often debate about the cuisine, and I rarely want to eat something super posh right after work. I noticed a new location of a burger chain opened up. I often confuse the Black Iron Burger with the Blacktap Burger places but not this time. I walked in with no reservations at this 54th and 7th ave location and sat at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Grande Boucherie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-grande-boucherie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 18:02:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-grande-boucherie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/"&gt;Boucherie&lt;/a&gt; before on 6th Ave near the West Village. We expected the food here to be similar but not the same as that location. I was craving for prime rib, and disappointingly, all the other places in the city were pretty expensive at $70 and up. But this restaurant had roast beef for a reasonable price, so I was expecting it to be similar enough to satisfy that hunger. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amor Loco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/amor-loco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 16:01:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/amor-loco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We got some new Mexican restaurant coupons for a margarita/beer. This location is quite convenient near Times Square, just a few steps from the heart of it. We made a reservation for a 4:15 PM on a Saturday late afternoon, and the crowd traffic was fairly light outside and inside. The reservation was probably not needed, but you never know. When we arrived at the restaurant, they did ask for proof of vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Bernardin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Le Bernardin is a &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City that primarily deals with seafood. The head chef is Eric Ripert, who is very well known in the higher end spectrum of the culinary world. We actually saw him on the floor with a mask on talking to some of the wait staff. This particular occasion was for a birthday celebration. Our reservation was at 5 PM, and it had to be reserved a month in advance. The spinning doors don&amp;rsquo;t actually open till 5 PM sharp, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a benefit to arrive before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiran</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:18:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an updated review for the Midtown / Times Square (Theater District) location for Ichiran. I had been to the original Bushwick location years ago, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pictures nor remembered much about it. The only thing I wrote down was &lt;code&gt;it was a much better version of Shinsengumi&lt;/code&gt;. Shinsengumi was a popular Torrance (California) restaurant that served hakata style ramen. They also allowed you to select your flavor profiles, and it was far less busy than Ichiran.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>