<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Midtown West on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-west/</link><description>Recent content in Midtown West on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown-west/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Danji</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:18:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</guid><description>Danji is Chef Hooni Kim&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that opened 15 years ago. It earned a Michelin Star back in 2012 and closed in April 2023 due to a fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other Michelin Star restaurant, Meju, which was phenomenal for what it was. We decided to check out this to see how it was, so I made a reservation pretty easily a week prior for 5:30 PM for a Friday.</description></item><item><title>Mitr Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:25:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</guid><description>Mitr Thai is a Midtown Thai restaurant that is located very close to Bryant Park. It can be a great option for Thai if you prefer to stay east of the Theater District. When we walked in around 5:30 PM on a Thursday night, we actually had to wait about 30-40 minutes. The restaurant was very full both downstairs and upstairs. We were seated upstairs in a 2-seater.
Ambiance &amp;amp; Service The interior decoration is dark and reminded me of a Tao-like upscale Asian restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Five Acres</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</guid><description>The one appeal that attracted me to try out Five Acres was that they offered a Chicago beef sandwich. For some reason, there are very few places that serve this sandwich that I know of. There used to be Hank&amp;rsquo;s Juicy Beef, but that closed down. The other Chicago beef place that I know of is in deep Brooklyn. Since we were around this Midtown area, I figured now is the right time to give this a shot.</description></item><item><title>SaiTong Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 11:11:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</guid><description>SaiTong Thai was a relatively new Thai restaurant that opened near the Theater District. One of its allures is that it appears to be an upscale Thai restaurant. The menu when I glanced at it seemed pretty decent although the prices were on the higher side. Since we had a theater date, we decided to check this restaurant out. We easily made a reservation for a Saturday at 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>SEA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:58:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</guid><description>SEA is a casual South East Asian restaurant from Chef Jungsik Yim of two Michelin Star restaurant, Jungsik. The restaurant offers a raw bar, small plates, and shareable plates with creativity. We were able to make a reservation pretty last minute for 5:15 PM on a Friday evening fairly easy. We arrived a little early, and they were able to seat us without issue. We had some high expectations that this restaurant will have great flavors.</description></item><item><title>Twin Tails</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</guid><description>This new Southeast Asian restaurant is located on the third floor of the Columbus Circle mall. The restaurant is part of the &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurant group, which also included Quality Italian, Don Angie, and Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s to name a few. What was exciting about the menu here was that it was leaning into higher end Vietnamese and Thai flavors. We were able to make a reservation a few days in advance for two people at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening.</description></item><item><title>Bourbon Steak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:58:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</guid><description>Michael Mina is an award winning chef and restaurateur that currently runs and operates over 40 restaurants worldwide. He opened this restaurant in the JW Marriott Essex House, right across from Central Park south and near Columbus Circle. This is his love letter to the classic American steakhouse. Bourbon Steak has multiple locations in the United States, so it&amp;rsquo;s not an entirely new restaurant. I picked this restaurant particularly because of their prix fixe menu that seems to give a pretty good spread of what this restaurant has to offer.</description></item><item><title>Pure Thai Cookhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</guid><description>We won yet another lottery for one of the theater shows, so we were hoping to walk into Wondee Thai. As expected, there was a line outside and a wait inside, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble missing the show if we had waited. We instead opted to walk a block south to this restaurant which had no patrons. We were able to walk in for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Saturday night without reservations.</description></item><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>We had previously been to The Bar at The Modern, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options.</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.</description></item><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything.</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.</description></item><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly Sal e Brasa, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Class on 38th</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:21:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</guid><description>Class on 38th was something that seemed interesting at first glance when I was browsing the &amp;ldquo;Hot and New&amp;rdquo; sections of Yelp. The menu looked like tapas with a price point that wasn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. I went here with a business partner, who was in town and looking for something to try. I made a reservation a few weeks back without any issues for 6 PM on a Thursday. When I walked in, they allowed me to sit early to wait for my guest to arrive.</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The team that created this restaurant also helped create Don Angie, Quality Eats, Quality Italian, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Heno Heno</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:42:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</guid><description>My partner had won some tickets to watch Appropriate on Broadway starring Sarah Paulson. The show starts at 8, but we had to pick up the will-call tickets by 7:30. I saw this Japanese small eatery was nearby the theater on 46th St, and I thought this would be a decent restaurant to try out since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of little things we can order. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening at around 5:30 PM before it got busy.</description></item><item><title>Havana Central</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</guid><description>It was raining on this gloomy Friday, and we wanted to eat somewhere close to Rockafeller. I recalled we had tried to walk into this restaurant on prior days with no success. I looked them up on OpenTable and saw that they had openings throughout the night. We figured it was worth a shot to try to walk in, and we found success. We were seated next to the door inside a glass section of the restaurant towards the front at around 6:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Marea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:56:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</guid><description>Normally during every Thanksgiving Thursday, I cook for my partner some poultry thing whether it be quail or turkey breast. This year we decided to relieve me the duties of frantically looking for materials and cooking for 6 hours for the 2 of us. Marea was closed for a few months, and we&amp;rsquo;ve always had this on our list. Because it just reopened in October, I decided to pursue the Thanksgiving tasting menu.</description></item></channel></rss>