<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sawtelle on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/sawtelle/</link><description>Recent content in Sawtelle on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 20:22:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/neighborhood/sawtelle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tsujita Artisan Noodle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-artisan-noodle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 20:22:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-artisan-noodle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsujita-artisan-noodle%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few weeks ago, I went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/"&gt;Tsujita&lt;/a&gt; for dinner. I wanted to come back for lunch to try the tsukemen style ramen, which is what it&amp;rsquo;s most known for. Across the street nearby is its sister store, Tsujita Annex which serves ramen the entire day. This one for the time being only serves ramen for lunch, and it does have a slightly different menu. For a Sunday morning at 11 AM, there were no lines or wait. It pays to solo dine, sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tsujita Sushi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 20:37:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsujita-sushi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tsujita is known for their ramen, particularly at the location where the dinner menu is different than their lunch menu. I was curious to try it for dinner to see how it compares to other Japanese restaurants. Note that this is not the Annex location. The Annex location at the time of this writing is the only Tsujita location that serves ramen for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is #20 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tatsu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tatsu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 17:49:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tatsu-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tatsu-ramen%2F0_noodles.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sawtelle is a popular place in west LA that is like Little Tokyo where there are a slew of Japanese dining and goods establishments. For lunch, I went to this random place called Tatsu Ramen. Since I rarely go to Sawtelle, I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be good to at record what I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. Sawtelle is an area in the westside with a plethora of Japanese restaurants primarily in the middle/low budget tier. It&amp;rsquo;s real easy to find dinner around here, but parking is kind of a pain in that you have to park on the streets and be wary of the signs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Hayatemaru</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ramen-hayatemaru/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 23:38:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/ramen-hayatemaru/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having lived in Los Angeles the last 5 years including the South Bay/Gardena/Torrance areas, I&amp;rsquo;ve always sought after my personal BEST ramen place. The best ramen place to me must have a tasty well balanced broth and good tasting thick noodles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per recommendations, I checked out Ramen Hayatemaru in Torrance partly because they have half bowl sizes, so you can try more than 1 flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically like my ramen noodles thicker because I like to slurp (excuse my manners) my noodles like Naruto. The noodles at this place are pretty good. They were cooked well where they weren&amp;rsquo;t chewy but were slightly more cooked than al dente.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>