<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brazilian on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/brazilian/</link><description>Recent content in Brazilian on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:56:29 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/brazilian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/churrascaria-plataforma%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/bra/sal-e-brasa/"&gt;Sal e Brasa&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kilo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:12:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/kilo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We have been here before prior to the pandemic when it was a weigh by the pound buffet-style. My partner took me here once because they had been here before several times and said it was their favorite. However that one time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it because the meat was all overcooked, and the rest of the sides were very mediocre. They agreed with me and were surprised by how mediocre it was on that day. Years later, we decided to try it again to confirm if it was a one time mishap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice X Beans</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-x-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:02:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-x-beans/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On a hot day, my partner wanted to eat at a Brazilian restaurant pretty far from where we live. I ended up walking 2 miles for this Brazilian restaurant. At first, I thought it was supposed to be an expansion of a Rice and Beans place in the city, but I learned this was entirely different. The first thought that came in my head when I sat down was that this restaurant definitely is more of a typical locals stop with no frills fair priced Brazilian dishes. I was not expecting any amazing Brazilian food, but who knows maybe they would surprise me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brazil Brazil</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/brazil-brazil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 06:53:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/brazil-brazil/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually have eaten here before, but we totally forgot to take pictures and document. From the best recollection, we remembered this place as being one of our favorite Brazilian restaurants in NYC. So we decided to visit this again to document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/brazil-brazil%2F1_maracuja_caipirinha.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;maracuja caipirinha&lt;/strong&gt; we recalled being really good our first time doing. Ordered it again, and it was nothing but a disappointment. The tartness of the passion fruit tasted sour and borderlinen rotten. There was no sweetness, and it tasted very watered down and unflavored. We asked the waitress to bring it back to the bartender because of this. The bartender created another one, and it was slightly better but still didn&amp;rsquo;t taste fresh.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tap Nyc</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/tap-nyc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/tap-nyc/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little quaint Brazilian breakfast-ish shop near 72nd Street close to Strawberry Fields. Their specialty is tapioca, açai, and pão (i.e. TAP). Many of their main products are gluten free, for those that really care about that. The Brazilian tapioca can be interpreted to be a &lt;em&gt;crepe&lt;/em&gt;, but other than the shape, the texture isn&amp;rsquo;t really like a crepe at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tap-nyc%2F1_pao_de_queijo.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pão de queijo&lt;/strong&gt; is basically cheese balls. These are much bigger than what you would get at a typical Brazilian restaurant. They taste similar to it and were quite tasty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Portugrill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 15:52:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food here was just like one of those casual fast food centric places. It&amp;rsquo;s on Seamless (food delivery service), so enough said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/portugrill%2F1_churrasco.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;churrasco&lt;/strong&gt; was $18 and was mildly satisfying. They gave you a decent amount of meat, and it was quite tender when ordered &amp;ldquo;medium rare&amp;rdquo;. It came with this mayonnaise like green sauce, that had only a mild kick to it. With this, I opted for french fries and pineapple on the side. The french fries were just OK, and the pineapple was kind of bland. The pineapple skin was on at the top, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as great as other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Favela Cubana</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-cubana/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 19:59:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-cubana/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place has a nice patio and great service. The waitress was very attentive, and the ambiance is definitely very easy-going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/favela-cubana%2F1_mama_margarita_and_passionfruit_caipirinha.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;mama margarita&lt;/strong&gt; I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite like. It was rather strong and for whatever reason the fruits did not complement well. The &lt;strong&gt;pasionfruit caipirinha&lt;/strong&gt; was not bad, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t great. I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely had better elsewhere in the city. I did think that the drink was made a little strong to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Emporium Brasil</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/emporium-brasil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 23:13:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/emporium-brasil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote back in 2019 that this is one of my favorite Brazilian spots because the food and drinks were pretty good. I revisited this with some coworkers to introduce them to Brazilian food again. Keep in mind that this visit is post COVID, so the menu has changed a bit. Gone are the batidas, but fortunately they had other standard Brazilian dishes to order. It is located in &amp;ldquo;Little Brazil&amp;rdquo; in Midtown which is literally very few restaurants situated on half the block.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice N Beans</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-n-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 23:06:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/rice-n-beans/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The caipirinhas were decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rice-n-beans%2F1_caipirinha.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual I dislike the &lt;strong&gt;coconut&lt;/strong&gt; flavored ones but appreciate the &lt;strong&gt;passion fruit&lt;/strong&gt; ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rice-n-beans%2F2_feijoada.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;feijoada&lt;/strong&gt; was the actual star here. It&amp;rsquo;s much better than some of the other Brazilian places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. The meat was plentiful, and the flavor is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rice-n-beans%2F3_bife_acebolado.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;bife acebolado&lt;/strong&gt; was ordered medium rare, and it was cooked medium to medium well. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why Brazilian restaurants have problems cooking the meat less than butchering it again. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything great about this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Favela Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 14:55:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/favela-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Had the churrasco here, and it was pretty good. The chicken and sausage was good. Make sure the steak is ordered medium rare. We ordered medium, and it came out borderline medium well. The caipirinha was really good too. Get the passion fruit and guava. Avoid the kiwi.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ipanema</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/ipanema/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 18:52:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/ipanema/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2018, I wrote, &amp;ldquo;The food was surprisingly good, and it&amp;rsquo;s not pricey at all. They give you free sides of rice and beans, so no worries about ordering that.&amp;rdquo; Now that I am working out of Midtown and fairly close to some of these Brazilian restaurants, I&amp;rsquo;ve been curious to try some of them again especially after the pandemic. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the decor being as &amp;ldquo;fancy&amp;rdquo; before, but the menu looked more refined and sophisticated in a good way. We also did not take pictures the last time we were here, so we thought about trying this restaurant again even though we usually try to not repeat restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Berimbau Do Brasil</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 17:28:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/berimbau-do-brasil%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berimbau do Brasil is a fairly well known West Village Brazilian restaurant. According to my first and last notes, I had tried the feijoada and the picanha, and both were excellent. My partner was craving a lot of this food recently, so we decided to try the new Midtown location of this restaurant. The menu has changed decently, but we were interested to see if the flavors were still consistent to their West Village location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>