<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sushi on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/sushi/</link><description>Recent content in Sushi on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/sushi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gallery by Odo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/the-gallery-by-odo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 14:06:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/the-gallery-by-odo/</guid><description>The Gallery by odo is a fusion of a restaurant and art space in the Flatiron area. It&amp;rsquo;s actually right next door to the odo restaurant and bar. I was easily able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:15 PM a few days in advance. When we walked in, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think much of it as an art space. It does have some paintings of outdoor forests hung up on walls and also what appears to be a for-sale dinnerware selection on a table.</description></item><item><title>Matsunori</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:18:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/matsunori/</guid><description>Matsunori Handroll Bar, not to be confused with Matsunori Sushi Club, originated as a Boston handroll sushi bar. They decided to open an additional location in Long Island City, where there is an influx of Asians moving in. They do not accept reservations, so we decided to try to walk in around 6:30 PM on a Friday evening. Fortunately, we got there just before the lines, and we were able to sit at a table for 2.</description></item><item><title>Mari.ne Handroll</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:57:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</guid><description>Mari.ne (MariNe) Hand-Roll Bar is similar to KazuNori where it&amp;rsquo;s simply a &amp;ldquo;hand roll&amp;rdquo; bar. The hand rolls are fairly small, but quite delightful and fresh. You can order them in different flavors, and it&amp;rsquo;s sure to satisfy anyone that enjoys sushi in hand roll format. We were able to walk in at around 5:45 PM on a Monday evening, but we were told that we had to be done by 6:30 PM due to an upcoming reservation.</description></item><item><title>Lure Fishbar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lure-fishbar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:57:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lure-fishbar/</guid><description>Lure Fishbar is run by the same hospitality network thath also owns Bar Tulix and Mercer Kitchen, which is closed unfortunately. Whenever we were in the SOHO area, we always thought about checking this place out especially since we couldn&amp;rsquo;t walk into Balthazar. The restaurant is very seafood straight forward, and it always seems like it has a very steady crowd. The restaurant entrance is actually located down some stairs.</description></item><item><title>Sake Kawa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:42:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-kawa/</guid><description>One of the really cool things about the Astoria neighborhood that is different than Manhattan and maybe Brooklyn, is that Japanese food is reasonably priced compared to the other boroughs. I am thinking part of the cause is because of the density of the Asian demographics in the area and having to be competitive with other neighborhood restaurants. This particular restaurant was just a few blocks north of Suzuki Shokudo.</description></item><item><title>Daikanyama</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/daikanyama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:24:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/daikanyama/</guid><description>We had walked over the Queensboro bridge to do some casual shopping at the Bloomingdales on Lexington on the Monday of a Memorial Day weekend. Surprisingly, there weren&amp;rsquo;t many people out and about probably due to people escaping town. Because this was around lunch time, we decided not to trek too far from the department store. This Japanese restaurant was connected indoors to the first floor of the department store. On the outside, they had private transparent glass huts with their own heaters, but we decided to eat indoors.</description></item><item><title>Suzuki Shokudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 22:05:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/suzuki-shokudo/</guid><description>Summary Astoria has a lot of Mediterranean restaurants and is seldom appealing for its Asian food. However, in the last few months prior the pandemic, there have been several Korean and Chinese/Taiwanese restaurants that were opening, so it&amp;rsquo;s starting to make a presence. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by this neighborhood Japanese sushi joint several times and were surprised about how low key it is. After looking at the menu, we decided to give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Sapps</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sapps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 20:43:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sapps/</guid><description>Summary In this pandemic, restaurants are trying all sorts of ways to do outdoor dining. What was interesting about Sapps was that they set up dining tables next door in the front of a mechanic shop but with plenty of distance between tables. They also put out propane powered heat warmers. When you arrive, you can basically choose your own seat, and the waiters will bring the water to you.</description></item><item><title>Murasaki</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/murasaki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:39:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/murasaki/</guid><description>Summary Here is another nice neighborhood spot off Vernon Blvd in Long Island City. Reviews seem to rave about how good this neighborhood sushi spot is, so we decided to give it a try.
The peach sparkling sake was relatively inexpensive and mighty tasty. The peach flavor tasted artificial, but it was still pretty good. It felt like drinking champagne without the heavy alcohol taste and with that artificial peach sweetener.</description></item><item><title>Rawbar by Domodomo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/rawbar-by-domodomo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 15:13:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/rawbar-by-domodomo/</guid><description>Summary Close to NYU, this is next door to its parent restaurant Domodomo. This is primarily a rawbar, meaning somewhat affordable raw seafood.
The iced green tea is nice for a warm day. The green tea is quite flavorful, but of course if you want it to be sweeter, you can ask for sugar.
We ordered a dozen oysters. Essentially 2 of the following:
Half Moon (Cape Cod Bay, MA) : sweet, medium salnity, clean finish Wellfleet (Wellfleet Harbor, MA) : briny, creamy, high salinity Savage Harbour (PEI, Canada) : crisp, sweet, medium salinity Chekbooktook (New Brunswick) : buttery, sweet, delicate Duxbury (Duxbury Bay, MA) : briny, sweet, and buttery finish the daily oysters : can&amp;rsquo;t remember what the waiter said about these other than being the saltiest of the east coast They serve oysters with your choice of 2 condiments: cocktail sauce, mignonette, wasabi lime sorbet, thai chili, and ponzu.</description></item><item><title>Nonono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</guid><description>Nonono is a restaurant from the people behind Her Name is Han. This is located just a few blocks from Korea town. They are part of the Hand Hospitality network, which also includes Atoboy, Cho Dang Gol, and many more. The restaurant offers Japanese grill cuisine with a twist. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the restaurant several times, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a decent value and choice for any small gatherings.
Ambiance &amp;amp; Service The ambiance feels like a normal Japanese restaurant where there was a lot of activity.</description></item><item><title>Kazunori</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kazunori/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:31:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kazunori/</guid><description>Spawned off LA&amp;rsquo;s Sugarfish. Cheap 6 piece hand rolls. $32 includes tax, tip, and a Mexican coke. Still room for dessert unfortunately.</description></item></channel></rss>