<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Koreatown on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/koreatown/</link><description>Recent content in Koreatown on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/koreatown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Octo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 13:32:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/octo/</guid><description>Octo is a Korean-Chinese restaurant that brings Chinese dishes developed in Korea. I visited South Korea back in the 2014s, and they definitely had their own spin on Chinese food, which is what attracted me to this restaurant. South Korea has its fair share of Chinese foods that are pretty similar, considered they have shared cultures. Located near Koreatown, we made a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night very easily.</description></item><item><title>Ai Ki Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/ai-ki-ya/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 14:42:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/ai-ki-ya/</guid><description>We had to run errands around Macy&amp;rsquo;s, so this was a good chance to check out some restaurant that was fairly light and also didn&amp;rsquo;t have strong smells. We were able to walk in on a Saturday at 5:30 PM with no reservations. We noticed the menus had both skewers and hot pot as options. I saw that many people ordered hot pot with cotton candy on top, and we contemplated briefly but decided not to.</description></item><item><title>Love Korean BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/love-korean-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 20:53:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/love-korean-bbq/</guid><description>Summary As we enter the end of the year and NYC indoor dining is forced to be shutdown due to a COVID uptick, we wanted to get some last fixin with Korean BBQ. Even though we have tried many of the major Korean BBQ restaurants near Koreatown already, this is one of the few remaining ones to try. When we visited, they check your temperature and had glass dividers between tables.</description></item><item><title>Dim Sum Palace</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 15:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/dim-sum-palace/</guid><description>Summary It&amp;rsquo;s the evening and where could be a good place to get fairly traditional Cantonese style Chinese food? Dim Sum Palace!
The pork ribs (páigǔ; 排骨) is pretty decent. It came out piping hot with a lump of black bean that probably was suppose to be mixed in the sauce. It&amp;rsquo;s a little different than other dim sum places, but still pretty good.
The salted pepper prawns were really good.</description></item><item><title>Turntable Chicken Jazz</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/turntable-chicken-jazz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/turntable-chicken-jazz/</guid><description>Summary The vibe here is pretty cool if you&amp;rsquo;re into old school jazz environments. The walls have a load of records and lots of old music devices. It does get a little noisy, and sometimes people eat really slow to create a wait. It&amp;rsquo;s not too different than other typical Korean bar/chicken joints where they have lots of alcohol and Korean bar foods.
The drinks were ok. Started off with a passionfruit lemonade.</description></item><item><title>Anytime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/anytime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 14:45:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/anytime/</guid><description>Summary This place is interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s like a modern version of typical Korean tapas.
They have these idea cocktails that have flashing lights underneath it. You can click on the switch underneath to alter the different lighting patterns. It&amp;rsquo;s gimmicky, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure they are targeting that photo crowd. The drinks themselves were OK. I think I prefer Brazilian style fruit cocktails now.
The hamachi cevichee was decent. It&amp;rsquo;s just tartare with a different flavor profile, but otherwise, it tasted like what you&amp;rsquo;d expect.</description></item><item><title>Samwon Garden Bbq</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/samwon-garden-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:01:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/samwon-garden-bbq/</guid><description>Pretty decent Korean BBQ. Also a bit expensive, and not as good as Let&amp;rsquo;s Meat.
Let&amp;rsquo;s Meat</description></item><item><title>Let's Meat</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/lets-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:00:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/lets-meat/</guid><description>Pretty decent Korean BBQ. A bit expensive, but everything was good.</description></item><item><title>Jongro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jongro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:48:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jongro/</guid><description>Pretty good. No Korean rice wrap, but meat quality was good.</description></item><item><title>Abiko Curry</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/abiko-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:10:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/abiko-curry/</guid><description>Abiko Curry is a Japanese curry restaurant that I had visited before in Koreatown way back in September of 2018. We were near the neighborhood, and I thought to check it out again. I remembered the curry and flavors being one of my favorite Japanese curry places in the city, but I also remembered that the &amp;ldquo;medium spicy&amp;rdquo; level was uncomfortably intense. This time around, I want to give it another try to see if I can get a better feel for it.</description></item><item><title>Grace Street</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/grace-street/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:37:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/grace-street/</guid><description>Desserts are pretty good, but I don&amp;rsquo;t get why there is always a line here.
The milk tea was just ok.
The donuts were good.</description></item><item><title>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:29:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</guid><description>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao is one of those XLB restaurants that is not often brought up in the XLB fights because it&amp;rsquo;s not that accessible. The original location is in Flushing, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit far from Manhattan. Many people do end up going to Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai to get their fix, but fortunately now a Manhattan location of this restaurant has opened in Koreatown.
I had originally gone to the Flushing location and said the following:</description></item></channel></rss>