<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>French on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/french/</link><description>Recent content in French on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Le Gratin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:22:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re in a mood of exploring some of the food places down near the Financial District. I was looking around, and there weren&amp;rsquo;t too many options. Le Gratin happened to be from renown chef, Daniel Boulud, so I figure this would be a safe choice. This is located right next to the Beekman Hotel, and there are entrances via the street or through the hotel. We easily made reservations for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Friday without much advance notice.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.</description></item><item><title>Frevo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</guid><description>Frevo was a restaurant that has been on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for some time. When we went to Atomix Bar, the chef had also highly recommended the restaurant. The head chef Franco Sampogna is Brazilian and comes from the region that my partner is from. The entrance to the restaurant has a very tiny art gallery, and it&amp;rsquo;s been recognized on the Michelin Guide with 1 star. We were able to reserve this a few weeks back without any issues.</description></item><item><title>Le Rock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 21:30:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/</guid><description>Le Rock is one of those new hot and busy restaurants around the Rockafeller area because it comes from the team of Frenchette. The majority of the menu is in French, and it had been receiving pretty stellar reviews for the most part. We walked in at 5:45 PM, and we were very fortunate that they were able to seat us due to a prior cancellation. We were told that we would have to be done with dinner within 90 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Pastis</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/pastis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 21:18:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/pastis/</guid><description>We were around the Meatpacking District area walking around, and I had stumbled onto this restaurant Pastis in my search for food. I remember reading that this restaurant was a happening place and was one of Keith McNally&amp;rsquo;s restaurants. Keith McNally is a restaurateur that has opened many NYC restaurants including Augustine, Balthazar, Minetta Tavern, and Cherche Midi. We were able to easily book a reservation for a Tuesday evening at 5 PM without any problems whatsoever.</description></item><item><title>Per Se</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:37:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</guid><description>Per Se is Thomas Keller&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed interpretation of the French Laundry restaurant in New York City and has 3 Michelin Stars. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a replacement for the French Laundry, but it might be indicative of what to expect if we did ever go to Napa Valley to try it out. This restaurant is located in Columbus Circle at the top floor inside the mall. When we walked in, we were astounded by the huge ceiling and the vast feeling of space.</description></item><item><title>Le Grande Boucherie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-grande-boucherie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 18:02:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-grande-boucherie/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been to Boucherie before on 6th Ave near the West Village. We expected the food here to be similar but not the same as that location. I was craving for prime rib, and disappointingly, all the other places in the city were pretty expensive at $70 and up. But this restaurant had roast beef for a reasonable price, so I was expecting it to be similar enough to satisfy that hunger.</description></item><item><title>Bacchus</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/bacchus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 05:41:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/bacchus/</guid><description>We have not tried too many Brooklyn restaurants near the Barclays Center area for quite some time due to the pandemic. On this early brisk and semi-cold night, we had an interactive theater outing over at the One Hanson Place building in Brooklyn. After the event was over, a friend that we met at the event impromptly invited us to meet his friend at this restaurant. This was less than a mile away, and since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have other plans, we decided to try it out.</description></item><item><title>Le Bernardin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</guid><description>Le Bernardin is a three Michelin Star restaurant in New York City that primarily deals with seafood. The head chef is Eric Ripert, who is very well known in the higher end spectrum of the culinary world. We actually saw him on the floor with a mask on talking to some of the wait staff. This particular occasion was for a birthday celebration. Our reservation was at 5 PM, and it had to be reserved a month in advance.</description></item><item><title>Tournesol</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/tournesol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 15:44:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/tournesol/</guid><description>Summary This French restaurant is located at the southern part of Vernon Blvd right across the street from Cafe Henri. We were able to walk in without reservations. The interior is quite cozy in this COVID environment as it has this very French (Paris) cafe feel to it. Each table was separated by a plastic wall. Be warned though that this place only accepts cash or AMEX. More on that later, so onto the food&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>M.Wells</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</guid><description>Summary This place is across the street from Food Cellar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in a garage and used to serve a lot of steak dishes. The menu has changed into a more casual patio like experience (I am guessing just for the summer). When we arrived, there was no table service. Instead you have to go to the counter and place your order there. The menus are shown via QRCode. After you place your order, you carry the utensils, dishes, and drinks back to your table.</description></item><item><title>American Brass</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 18:50:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</guid><description>Summary This is a restaurant from the same people that brought Maiella. Even though that restaurant was modern Italian, this one was more of a modern French. It sits across the park near the Hunters Point library.
We came here on a Sunday, prior to the day that New York City had to shutdown dining in restaurants due to the corona virus. Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t really out and about, the restaurant had many empty tables.</description></item><item><title>La Cafette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-cafette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 17:03:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-cafette/</guid><description>Summary This restaurant has been on my list for a while. Before I moved out of North Williamsburg, I wanted to eat something with pork. Unfortunately at the time, they were closed on a Tuesday for whatever reason, so I did not have the opportunity to try this place until today.
The ambiance is a dimly lit romantic setting right near the corner of Havenmayer. There were a lot of candles all over, and the tables were pretty close to each other reminding me of my time in Paris.</description></item><item><title>Gabriel Kreuther</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</guid><description>Summary This post is going to be a big one. For our first anniversary, we treated ourselves to a nice French place that I think is generally underrated and under the radar. Gabriel Kreuthers has been something that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try, and it&amp;rsquo;s rated 2 Michelin Stars in 2019. We went bold with the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Carte Blanche Tasting Menu. There are a total of at least 28 dishes spread through of what they say is 9 courses.</description></item><item><title>Lafayette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/lafayette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 16:41:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/lafayette/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here many times, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually ate here until now. One of our guests loves this place because of the burger.
The prime beef tartare was pretty good. It definitely was tender and tasted like good quality beef.
The rotisserie chicken was really tender. If I had to dock it points, it&amp;rsquo;d be for how salty the sauce and everything was. Also, it was oily too.</description></item><item><title>Paname</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 23:49:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/paname/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of brunch at all, so this was the first restaurant in the area I was in that seemed interesting to me. I completely forgot it was Easter Sunday, but luckily their prixe fix menu had all the regulars on it.
The bread was nothing to write home about. It came slightly on the cold side.
The escargots de bourgogne in baby potatoes were actually pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Dirty French</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/dirty-french/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 14:16:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/dirty-french/</guid><description>Summary This place is right around the corner of Katz in the Ludlow Hotel. We sat in the patio area which is much nicer and quieter than indoors where everyone else is sitting.
Starting off, they serve bread that seems to be freshly made for your table. The bread comes with some butter with oil on it, and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
We ordered 2 cocktails: Laboulaye which is the green one and Petite Socco which is the red one.</description></item><item><title>Boucherie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 20:50:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/</guid><description>Summary Walked in on a Saturday at 7 PM with no reservations, and it was packed despite it being pretty frigid outside.
Luckily, we got seats at the bar.
The french onion soup was really good. The gruyere cheese was nice and toasty, and the beef broth with the onions wasn&amp;rsquo;t salty like typical french onion soups.
The porterhouse of course was cooked a perfect medium rare. The strip side was preferred over the filet mignon.</description></item><item><title>Felix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:11:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/felix/</guid><description>Summary This place is CASH ONLY as well. Food was pretty good, and it seems like a nice date spot.
I got the steak with bone marrow. The potato (au gratin style) was also pretty good. It also came with a side of brussel sprouts and bacon mish mash. The sauce was salty, but the steak was cooked nicely for a medium rare.
Final Verdict I&amp;rsquo;d come back here again if I was near the South Village, had cash, and wanted to eat something French.</description></item><item><title>Taureau</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 19:09:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/taureau/</guid><description>This place is CASH ONLY. The chocolate fondu was good, but the cheese that we got was just ok. The meat quality was pretty good with the wine broth.</description></item><item><title>St Tropez</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/st-tropez/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/st-tropez/</guid><description>Great for the price, although I was here on a pescetarian date. I thought I could do pescetarian, and I can&amp;rsquo;t. Would come back for actual meats.</description></item><item><title>Cherche Midi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cherche-midi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:09:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cherche-midi/</guid><description>Same owner as the Minetta Tavern. Great for the price. I liked teh suckling pork because it was straight up fat with crispy skin. Got the whole fish, and it was great too.
Only problem is it is CLOSED.</description></item><item><title>Le Relais De Venise L'entrecote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:08:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</guid><description>This review is for the Midtown East location of Le Relais De Venise L&amp;rsquo;entrecote. The previous review I had was for the closed SOHO location, which I was complaining that they charged $5.50 for tap water back in 2018. Fast forward about 3 years later post pandemic, how does this location fare compared to the previous one? I will say much better. Note that this location did not appear to charge for tap water.</description></item><item><title>Le Singe Vert</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-singe-vert/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:06:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-singe-vert/</guid><description>Pretty good. Decent price. Don&amp;rsquo;t have much else to say I guess.</description></item></channel></rss>