<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Manhattan on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/manhattan/</link><description>Recent content in Manhattan on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/borough/manhattan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>We had previously been to The Bar at The Modern, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options.</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.</description></item><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything.</description></item><item><title>The Clocktower</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 19:39:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-clocktower/</guid><description>The Clocktower has been on my list for a while and was a former 1 Michelin Star restaurant a few years ago. I ended up circling back to this restaurant because we&amp;rsquo;re desiring to eat as many baked Alaska places as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how many permutations of this dessert exists. We were able to book a reservation for 2 for a Friday evening without issue. The restaurant is located inside The Edison hotel on the second floor.</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.</description></item><item><title>Claud</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/</guid><description>For this week, I offered my partner an option of European or Chinese. Of course they said European. Claud comes from 2 veterans of the Momofuku Ko restaurant, chef Joshua Pinsky and wine expert Chase Sinzer. I remember this restaurant a while back, but it slipped off my radar with all these new openings in the last few years. When I checked Resy, I noticed there were openings on Friday, so the stars aligned.</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it.</description></item><item><title>Konban</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:44:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/konban/</guid><description>Konban was a new katsu restaurant that was on my radar for a while. When it first opened, reservations were hard to come by. Now a few months later, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a reservation a week out. Because Manhattan has so few katsu-specialized options, this was going to be a very special experience. I was able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night for two people.</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind Au Cheval and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.</description></item><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Churrascaria Plataforma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:56:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/churrascaria-plataforma/</guid><description>In 2018, I wrote that I liked this place more than Fogo De Chão, which is a global AYCE Brazilian BBQ chain. After our recent trip to Brazil, particularly Sal e Brasa, I wanted to visit this NYC restaurant again to do a comparison. This restaurant is the only location that exists. We had a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday, and there was hardly anyone in the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, Marta, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food.</description></item><item><title>Le Gratin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:22:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re in a mood of exploring some of the food places down near the Financial District. I was looking around, and there weren&amp;rsquo;t too many options. Le Gratin happened to be from renown chef, Daniel Boulud, so I figure this would be a safe choice. This is located right next to the Beekman Hotel, and there are entrances via the street or through the hotel. We easily made reservations for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Friday without much advance notice.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as Saga, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.</description></item><item><title>Chica &amp; the Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:49:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/chica-and-the-don/</guid><description>Chica &amp;amp; The Don is a new Latin restaurant that opened in the Flatiron district. Despite their Yelp site pointing to Flatbush, it really is located in Manhattan. When you walk in, the restaurant has a long corridor to the main dining area. They just opened 3 weeks ago, so I was interested in checking this out before the hype were to build up. We were able to make a reservation relatively easy for 5:45 PM on a Friday early evening.</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Udon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:48:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</guid><description>I just have this affinity for noodles. Their sibling location, Okiboru House of Tsukemen, was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the city when it comes to dipping ramen. This restaurant recently opened up marketing itself for udon. Like their tsukemen location, this one offers udon for dipping. Unlike traditional udon, these noodles are much wider and flatter. I was able to walk in by myself at 8 PM on a Tuesday evening, and I immediately was seated.</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Class on 38th</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:21:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</guid><description>Class on 38th was something that seemed interesting at first glance when I was browsing the &amp;ldquo;Hot and New&amp;rdquo; sections of Yelp. The menu looked like tapas with a price point that wasn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. I went here with a business partner, who was in town and looking for something to try. I made a reservation a few weeks back without any issues for 6 PM on a Thursday. When I walked in, they allowed me to sit early to wait for my guest to arrive.</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.</description></item><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss.</description></item></channel></rss>