<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noodles on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/noodles/</link><description>Recent content in Noodles on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 15:10:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/noodles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Okiboru House of Udon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:48:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/okiboru-house-of-udon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/okiboru-house-of-udon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just have this affinity for noodles. Their sibling location, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/"&gt;Okiboru House of Tsukemen&lt;/a&gt;, was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the city when it comes to dipping ramen. This restaurant recently opened up marketing itself for udon. Like their tsukemen location, this one offers udon for dipping. Unlike traditional udon, these noodles are much wider and flatter. I was able to walk in by myself at 8 PM on a Tuesday evening, and I immediately was seated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Okiboru House of Tsukemen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/okiboru-house-of-tsukemen%2F0_store_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is tsukemen (つけ麺; pronounced &amp;ldquo;skee-men&amp;rdquo;)? It&amp;rsquo;s basically thick udon served cold with a side of a thick soup/broth for dipping. In Los Angeles, I frequented a place in Sawtelle near the Westside called &amp;ldquo;Tsujita&amp;rdquo; that also specialized in something similar. Okiboru recently opened in Manhattan, and it&amp;rsquo;s famed for being on Michelin&amp;rsquo;s Bib Gourmand list in Atlanta. They do not take reservations, so when we arrived at this location at 5:15 PM on a Friday, the line outside was about 10 parties ranging from 2 to 6 people per group. It took us about 30-45 minutes of wait before we were seated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Silky Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:41:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, I can grab food for myself after work, and I tend to look for noodles. My partner is not a fan at all of noodles, so I took this liberty to look for something that they would not enjoy. Despite the hot and humid weather in NYC, I rarely mind eating hot soups with noodles. Silky Kitchen has a location near where I live in Astoria, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try out its location out in Midtown near Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Spot</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-spot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ramen-spot%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner on a late Saturday evening was planning to get some food with their friend, so that means I can venture out on my own. As people know from reading this site, I&amp;rsquo;m a ramen fiend. I love to try all sorts of ramen, and I never mind eating it by myself. This ramen location recently opened only a few weeks ago, and I definitely prefer early dinners. It&amp;rsquo;s located very close to the 7 train Court Sq stop, and is just around the corner from the Long Island City Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zhongzhong Noodles</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/zhongzhong-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 22:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/zhongzhong-noodles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We planned to meet my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend on the wonderful Roosevelt Island. For those that haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Roosevelt Island, there are literally 3 different ways to get there: the F train, the tram (cable car), or transportation via bridge from the Astoria side. With the hopefully slim possibility of living there, my partner wanted to meet their friend and also check out local food delights. Zhongzhong Noodles had been on my list for quite a while, so I figured now is a good time to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hanon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hanon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 19:18:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hanon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hanon is located in the North Williamsburg area and is literally across the street on Union St. from the Metropolitan G stop and diner. It has been awarded the Michelin 2021 Bib Gourmand award. It originated in Kamakura, Japan in the summer of 2018. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about this restaurant much at all and stumbled onto this through Yelp&amp;rsquo;s Hot &amp;amp; New filters. I wanted to try this restaurant out because the pictures of the udon sets look quite interesting, and the price point was pretty reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Noodlecraft</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:09:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodlecraft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We walked by this restaurant one evening as we were walking back, and I was reminded that this was something I wanted to try. At a quick glance, the interior seemed pretty spacious, and I always go back and forth on whether we can go here. My partner is never fanatical about noodles, but luckily this restaurant has other things such as dim sum and cold cut appetizers. This restaurant opened last year during the pandemic in October and seemed to have a pretty steady flow of repeat customers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Soba Noodle Azuma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/soba-noodle-azuma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 11:44:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/soba-noodle-azuma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been deprived of noodles in the city for a number of months now. Sure, there are sometimes where I get some Taiwanese noodles, but I also love soba noodles too. I was around the Columbus Circle area, and I was scouring for some alternative ramen places. This one peaked my interest because their specialty was not ramen but soba also known as buckwheat noodles. Buckwheat noodles are supposed to be pretty healthy for you, and on a summer NYC day like today, it seems like a win when opting for cold buckwheat noodles with a cold dip.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Mian Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:26:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/la-mian-lounge/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astoria in the last few months has seen an uptick on Asian restaurants that aren&amp;rsquo;t fusion and are more authentic. This one just happens to be on Broadway near my partner&amp;rsquo;s old neighborhood. We&amp;rsquo;ve been around this area before going to eat Shanghainese food. Today, it&amp;rsquo;s for noodles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-mian-lounge%2F1_braised_beef_tendon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the &lt;strong&gt;braised beef tendon&lt;/strong&gt;. It was marinated in chili oil, garlic, scallions, sesame oil, and other things that I probably missed. It&amp;rsquo;s a very traditional cold appetizer dish. The beef tendon was actually quite crunchy but cooked properly and thoroughly. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Chinese restaurants in NYC where the tendons were hard as rock. But here, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that it was cooked thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mazete</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:50:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mazete/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically when we walk north on 6th ave towards Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s for groceries, we stop by Cava across the street for a snack. We saw this seemingly new interesting restaurant opened with no one in it. The space is very bright, modern, and definitely has a Japanese cafe-chic vibe to it. This dry &amp;ldquo;ramen&amp;rdquo; place just opened along 6th Avenue between 20th and 21st Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another one of those &amp;ldquo;pick X of this and Y of that&amp;rdquo; type of restaurant except the theme here is Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 13:08:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ramen place is near NYU and Union Station, so it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ichiba%2F1_spicy_miso_ramen.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spicy miso&lt;/strong&gt; ramen comes with ox bones and marrow broth, spicy miso garlic base, bean sprouts, roasted corn, toasted nori, naruto fishcake, soy braised beef, scallions, and thick wavy noodle. THe broth is super rich, far beyond what I was expecting. It&amp;rsquo;s not spicy per se, but the soup doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down super smooth for me. At the end, the spicy pepper would always surprise for some reason. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s attributed to the oil and thickness of the broth, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. Regardless, I thought the ramen was acceptable, but there are better ones in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tonchin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/tonchin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place has a pretty decent ambiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tonchin%2F1_yuzu_margarita.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yuzu margarita&lt;/strong&gt; was surprisingly pretty good. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had yuzu before and like citrus, I recommend you get this if it&amp;rsquo;s available. I just checked their website&amp;rsquo;s drink menu, and it&amp;rsquo;s not on there. This drink wasn&amp;rsquo;t strong at all, and had a really really good before and after taste. I would drink this over any regular margarita any day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xi'an Famous Food</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 22:27:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xian-famous-food/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to this restaurant multiple times in various neighborhoods, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t documented it till now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xian-famous-food%2F1_spicy_and_sour_spinach_dumplings.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually get the &lt;strong&gt;spicy tingly beef&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but to be honest I do like Very Fresh Noodles in the Chelsea Market more. However this place was next to me, so the convenience is much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xian-famous-food%2F2_spicy_tingly_beef_noodle.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spicy and sour spinach dumplings&lt;/strong&gt; are also really good too. I love the vinegary taste wih everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ivan Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ivan-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this ramen spot other than it was on Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, and how it really touched a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s hearts. So my review will be almost based solely on the food itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ivan-ramen%2F1_pork_musubi_bies.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pork musubi bites&lt;/strong&gt; were surprisingly good. Each bite is packed full of flavor, although I am rather doubtful that it&amp;rsquo;s worth $5 a piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ivan-ramen%2F2_japanese_fried_chicken.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Japanese fried chicken&lt;/strong&gt; were an interesting spin on karaage. The crust was nicely crisp, and the sauce was very tangy. There was a little kick to it too. They served this with a sauce on the side that I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember how it tasted like. I do remember that my first thought was that this was oversauced similar to how PF Chang&amp;rsquo;s would do orange chicken, but nonetheless it was decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mu Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/mu-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to start with this. I loathe cash only places considering the price of this is not exactly cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F1_u_&amp;amp;_i.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;U &amp;amp; I&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was really good but not for +$20. The bowl was rather small although the ingredients were pretty fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mu-ramen%2F2_the_flying_pig.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;flying pig&lt;/strong&gt; bowl was the biggest disappointment I&amp;rsquo;ve had. The broth was just OK. It&amp;rsquo;s subtly different than the normal tonkatsu style broth. I also opted for an ounce of the jamon iberico. I added an additional onsen tamago, which is basically a sous vide egg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>EAK Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:44:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/eak-ramen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EAK Ramen is located on 6th Ave close to 14th. I used to venture here all the time pre-pandemic, and there was always a line or people. I was curious to see how the restaurant was like since. Back in September 2018, I thought it was one of the better ramen places, but now, EAK also has a ton more competition all over the city. We were able to walk in on a Sunday early afternoon around 4 PM. We were the only diners, so we thought it was cool that we can eat at non-prime times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ippudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ippudo%2F0_napkin.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had visited Ippudo twice before this time throughout my whole life, once in London and once in the East Village. This original post just had a comment of &amp;ldquo;Overrated and pricey. I&amp;rsquo;d skip here any day of the week. Daikokuya in LA is way better&amp;rdquo;. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pics of my dinner nearly 4 years ago, I thought about revisiting this Midtown location to try to remember why I was underwhelmed. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I now remember why, and it makes perfect sense why I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for it before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiran</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:18:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an updated review for the Midtown / Times Square (Theater District) location for Ichiran. I had been to the original Bushwick location years ago, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pictures nor remembered much about it. The only thing I wrote down was &lt;code&gt;it was a much better version of Shinsengumi&lt;/code&gt;. Shinsengumi was a popular Torrance (California) restaurant that served hakata style ramen. They also allowed you to select your flavor profiles, and it was far less busy than Ichiran.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tsurutontan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:29:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsurutontan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Tsurutontan a few times already in various locations including Union Square and Midtown next to Rockafeller Center. When this Japan udon chain first opened in Manhattan a few years ago, there was a massive line because it was the first international location in the USA. The food was outstanding back then, and now it&amp;rsquo;s gone down a little in quality but still pretty good. This restaurant is known for having mammoth sized udon bowls which will most definitely satiate your appetite. They also have a variety of other Japanese sushi-esque dishes as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momofuku Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momofuku-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 18:29:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/momofuku-noodle-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/momofuku-noodle-bar%2F0_david_chang.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/"&gt;Ippudo&lt;/a&gt;, this was supposedly another must-try ramen place that was highly raved by the NYC food scene. I got to this spot right when they opened, and there was already a small line outside in this frigid cold weather. Inside, they have counter top seating for 1-2 people as well as a some picnic table setups for larger parties. There was no David Chang spotted here, but how was the food?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>