<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brunch on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/brunch/</link><description>Recent content in Brunch on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 16:32:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/brunch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/clinton-st-baking-co%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends. Right when they open, we were about the 6th small party in line, so we were able to be seated pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bubby's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/bubbys/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 21:02:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/bubbys/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bubbys%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of brunch as whole, but my partner&amp;rsquo;s friends were in town and they selected this restaurant due to their pancakes. Take note that on Sundays, they do not allow reservations, and only the completed parties can be seated. We arrived at around 10:30 AM, and we ended up waiting about 45 minutes until we were able to get in. Originally we were a group of 5, but luckily one didn&amp;rsquo;t show up, so we were able to be seated once our whole party arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sweet Chick</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:07:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/fried-chicken/sweet-chick/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having been to Sweet Chick before in North Williamsburg, I vaguely remember this place having pretty good crust. I often get Pies N Thighs confused with this. In Williamsburg, there&amp;rsquo;s always a line outside, so when we walked by here with no line, we decided on a spur of the moment to try this out. When you sit at a table, there is a QR code that you can scan and even place your order.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Mogador</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-mogador/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:39:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-mogador/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the outside world, the pandemic is wreaking havoc like wildfire. However for me personally, the only difference is that people are much more careful about cleanliness. In North Williamsburg, the brunch hipster spots are still thriving, and as you can imagine are very meticulous to avoid any type of spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cafe Mogador has been one of those frequent brunch places that many flock to for weekend brunch. This is not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been here as I&amp;rsquo;ve always been neutral, but at least this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken pictures of some of the food.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boqueria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/boqueria/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 16:32:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/boqueria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/boqueria%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boqueria is an east coast Spanish tapas chain. The food here is quintessential Spanish shareables, including large paellas. We originally ate here with some friends in the Upper East, but we have also tried this restaurant in Flatiron. Reservations are fairly easy to secure, and it does get busy during core hours. If you have a decent sized party, this is probably a decent restaurant to bring folks that might be into family style sharing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>