<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portuguese on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/portuguese/</link><description>Recent content in Portuguese on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:14:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/portuguese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leitao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:14:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/leitao%2F0_downstairs.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the front of Leitão but a pic of the back. I stumbled onto this restaurant looking for Portuguese or Peruvian restaurants for our Friday dinners. My partner wanted this as the option for this evening, so I made a reservation for 2 at 5:30 PM on a nice Friday evening. The restaurant itself is located about a 0.5 mile (0.8 km) walk from the West 4th subway station. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a picture of the front because it was difficult to take pics of the restaurant without having people&amp;rsquo;s faces directly in the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aldea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:31:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Portuguese food other than the pastels, so this is the first for me. This special occasion was for a birthday and to try out a different type of cuisine that is largely not as popular as the mainstream French or Asian themed Michelin Star restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got the tasting menu with wine pairing. The hosts were very nice in that we mentioned we&amp;rsquo;d like to just have wine pairing for 1 person and not the other, so that we can share since we&amp;rsquo;re not big drinkers. The hosts still gave us 2 glasses and poured smaller samples. I am pretty sure if I had the wine pairing to myself, I would be drunk before I reached the end due to my inability to have the enzymes to process alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Portugrill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 15:52:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/portugrill/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food here was just like one of those casual fast food centric places. It&amp;rsquo;s on Seamless (food delivery service), so enough said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/portugrill%2F1_churrasco.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;churrasco&lt;/strong&gt; was $18 and was mildly satisfying. They gave you a decent amount of meat, and it was quite tender when ordered &amp;ldquo;medium rare&amp;rdquo;. It came with this mayonnaise like green sauce, that had only a mild kick to it. With this, I opted for french fries and pineapple on the side. The french fries were just OK, and the pineapple was kind of bland. The pineapple skin was on at the top, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as great as other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>