<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michelin (2) on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-2/</link><description>Recent content in Michelin (2) on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have 2 Michelin Stars, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, Aska recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system Tock. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week.</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix.</description></item><item><title>Aska</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</guid><description>For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I decided on this 2 Michelin Star restaurant located in the Williamsburg area. What appealed to me originally about this was that it was not just another French restaurant. French cuisine is great, but there are so many high end French restaurants around the city. Perhaps I am getting a little burnt out of having the same French tastes over and over, so I wanted something that was less normal.</description></item><item><title>Atera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:09:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</guid><description>Atera is a two Michelin Star restaurant in New York City. We&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go to this restaurant pre-pandemic, and each time we make a reservation, it was always cancelled due to shifts in NYC rules around the pandemic. Fortunately, the city is coming alive, and the reservation stuck this time around. We celebrated our very special anniversary at 5 PM. The cool thing about this restaurant that attracted me was that it had a temperament pairing of non-alcoholic juices.</description></item><item><title>Jungsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/jungsik/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:10:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/jungsik/</guid><description>This place was really really good. Korean Michelin 2 star and well worth it. Probably one of the best Michelin star restaurants I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in NYC.</description></item></channel></rss>