<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>West Village on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/west-village/</link><description>Recent content in West Village on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 14:33:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/west-village/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sirrah</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/sirrah/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 14:33:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/sirrah/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sirrah%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sirrah is a fairly new restaurant near the Meatpacking District. One of its appeals to me was that it offers a relatively decently priced prix fixe menu. I felt like it was similar to some of these French restaurants, e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/"&gt;Le Relais de Venise L&amp;rsquo;Entrecote&lt;/a&gt;, that offered steak frites. Reservations are pretty easy to get, even a day before so we got a 5:30 PM reservation for a Friday. Because the weather was nice outside, they also opened the side doors to let fresh air in. The entrance to the restaurant is not very loud.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Chêne</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-chene/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:27:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-chene/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/le-chene%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Chêne (&lt;em&gt;Le Chene&lt;/em&gt;) is the first solo project for husband/wife team, Alexia Duchêne and Roman Duchêne Le May. The menu features refined French recipes with an extensive wine list. When I looked at the menu, it was appealing because it seemed to resonate French with a slight rustic feel to it. I was able to book a reservation for 2 a few weeks out without issues. You can&amp;rsquo;t miss this restaurant with its yellow door.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zimmi's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/zimmis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 11:34:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/zimmis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Zimmi&amp;rsquo;s is a new little French restaurant that recently just opened in the West Village. Its menu comes from chef Maxime Pradié, who draws influences from homestyle Southern French cooking. I looked on Resy, and I was able to get a reservation for 2 at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening. When I arrived, it really resonated the classic West Village restaurant, where the word &amp;ldquo;quaint&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;rustic&amp;rdquo; are often used together to describe the ambiance and food.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leitao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:14:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/leitao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/leitao%2F0_downstairs.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the front of Leitão but a pic of the back. I stumbled onto this restaurant looking for Portuguese or Peruvian restaurants for our Friday dinners. My partner wanted this as the option for this evening, so I made a reservation for 2 at 5:30 PM on a nice Friday evening. The restaurant itself is located about a 0.5 mile (0.8 km) walk from the West 4th subway station. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a picture of the front because it was difficult to take pics of the restaurant without having people&amp;rsquo;s faces directly in the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brasserie VietNam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 17:33:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/brasserie-vietnam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/brasserie-vietnam%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been difficult to find decent Vietnamese restaurants in general in NYC. A lot of them just don&amp;rsquo;t get the broth in pho right. This one seemed like a more upscale version of general Vietnamese cuisine, and I saw it open less than a year ago on Yelp. It was tough at first to walk in a few times, so fortunately the hype subsided, and I was able to get an easy reservation on Friday at 5:30 PM for 2 people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Olio E Più</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/olio-e-piu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 15:27:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/olio-e-piu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/olio-e-piu%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olio e Più is a trattoria &amp;amp; enoteca restaurant run by the same group that manages &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/"&gt;Boucherie&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s close to the West 4th station in the Village, and it usually has a very lively crowd as it gets toward evening hours. Before the pandemic, the restaurant table space was quite small and tight. Since, they&amp;rsquo;ve expanded structurally a patio that extends out of the main building, as well as little sidewalk area that is enclosed. If you desire to sit in the actual indoor areas (i.e. not the patio area or the sidewalk area), you probably have to make a reservation a few weeks in advance and book the &amp;ldquo;Standard&amp;rdquo; area in OpenTable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cotenna</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cotenna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:30:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cotenna/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cotenna%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Village is an area that we had walked through at times, but we never really tried many restaurants. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible from both where my partner works and where I work. They picked this restaurant at the whim, and the menu looked pretty interesting and also straight forward. I was able to secure a reservation for 5:30 PM the day of without much difficulties. When you arrive here, there seems to be a little sibling restaurant, Aria Wine bar, across the street which seems to have a similar menu. Unfortunately, I did not see a restaurant sign for this one until I stared at the menu taped to the wall and noticed it said Cotenna.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pastis</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/pastis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 21:18:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/pastis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pastis%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Meatpacking District area walking around, and I had stumbled onto this restaurant Pastis in my search for food. I remember reading that this restaurant was a happening place and was one of Keith McNally&amp;rsquo;s restaurants. Keith McNally is a restaurateur that has opened many NYC restaurants including Augustine, Balthazar, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/"&gt;Minetta Tavern&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cherche-midi/"&gt;Cherche Midi&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to easily book a reservation for a Tuesday evening at 5 PM without any problems whatsoever. When we walked in, we were welcomed with a very fun atmosphere that resembled somewhat of a French market/cafe.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oppa Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 16:16:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oppa-bistro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oppa-bistro%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are likely going to frequent the West Village weekly because we&amp;rsquo;ve nearly tapped out the heart of the Midtown area. This area is densely populated with a high number of restaurants that goes through frequent turnovers and change. Oppa Bistro was an audible call when we learned that Olio e Piu was very packed at around 5:30 PM on a Friday. We were able to walk into Oppa Bistro with no reservations at around 5:45 PM, and there was just a handful of diners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Flex Mussels</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flex-mussels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 21:46:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flex-mussels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had tickets to the Banksy exhibit later in the evening near the border of Chelsea and West Village. This mussel restaurant was something I had liked to go since I moved out to NYC, and finally all stars aligned. Surprisingly, there are not a lot of mussel restaurants in NYC. In Los Angeles in Culver City, I used to go to a place called &amp;ldquo;Meet in Paris&amp;rdquo;, and it had literally 10+ different types of mussel broths. This reminded me of those vibes, so I wanted to try this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Angie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant had been on my peripheral for a while because of the lasagna dish. I didn&amp;rsquo;t decide to try to book a reservation until I learned it was awarded its first ever Michelin Star. I had tried a few times on Resy, but always missed it. Fortunately, I was able to land a reservation on a weekend at 5 PM EST. The restaurant itself is in West Village and felt like a typical trendy cafe in the area. The tables were social distanced, and had a nice romantic setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>While We Were Young</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/while-we-were-young/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 21:36:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/while-we-were-young/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally we don&amp;rsquo;t care about brunches, but this restaurant was surprisingly good and not too expensive. Located in West Village near the &amp;ldquo;Friends&amp;rdquo; place and some touristy spots, this is a very quaint and small shop. If I recall, it only has like at most 5 tables with counters spread throughout the place. This place is small, so set your expectations accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/while-we-were-young%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered a glass of &lt;strong&gt;orange juice&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;One Night Stand&lt;/strong&gt;. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything particular about the orange juice other than they put ice cubes in it which I thought was weird. However, the One Night Stand was actually pretty refreshing. It&amp;rsquo;s tequila, watermelon, chili agave, and lime. It has that little spicy kick to it, but not too much. The watermelon rounds it out very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Love Panzerotti</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/i-love-panzerotti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 21:47:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/i-love-panzerotti/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This little &lt;em&gt;pizza&lt;/em&gt; shop is down right at the edge of South/West Village close to a Shake Shack. The panzerottis are like super thin calzones that are frieds as oppose to baked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/i-love-panzerotti%2F1_regular.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dough that they use here is really tasty. It&amp;rsquo;s chewy, has a nice bounce, and has a very nice flavor profile to it. The dough definitely has a distinct flavor to it that makes it taste super fresh. They make and fry the panzerotti for each order, so you can be sure it&amp;rsquo;s super hot when it comes out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boucherie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 20:50:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walked in on a Saturday at 7 PM with no reservations, and it was packed despite it being pretty frigid outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we got seats at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="french onion" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/boucherie%2F1_french_onion.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;french onion soup&lt;/strong&gt; was really good. The gruyere cheese was nice and toasty, and the beef broth with the onions wasn&amp;rsquo;t salty like typical french onion soups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/boucherie%2F2_porterhouse.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;porterhouse&lt;/strong&gt; of course was cooked a perfect medium rare. The strip side was preferred over the filet mignon. There was some sauce on the side, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t need to use the sauce on the side because the steak was seasoned well and had a good flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Berimbau Do Brasil</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 17:28:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/berimbau-do-brasil%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berimbau do Brasil is a fairly well known West Village Brazilian restaurant. According to my first and last notes, I had tried the feijoada and the picanha, and both were excellent. My partner was craving a lot of this food recently, so we decided to try the new Midtown location of this restaurant. The menu has changed decently, but we were interested to see if the flavors were still consistent to their West Village location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quality Eats</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:59:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Skirt steak was pretty good. Very affordable. Good date spot I think.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Salt &amp; Battery</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:20:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;British style fish &amp;amp; chips.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Menkoi Sato</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:49:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/menkoi-sato/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the old &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/mew-men"&gt;Mew Men&lt;/a&gt; place. Pretty good ramen. The spicy is actually spicy, and the broth is super flavorful. The only caveat is there is not a lot of stuff that comes with the soup. Just a few veggies, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. They should have some sort of combo or something.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>EAK Ramen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:44:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/eak-ramen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/eak-ramen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EAK Ramen is located on 6th Ave close to 14th. I used to venture here all the time pre-pandemic, and there was always a line or people. I was curious to see how the restaurant was like since. Back in September 2018, I thought it was one of the better ramen places, but now, EAK also has a ton more competition all over the city. We were able to walk in on a Sunday early afternoon around 4 PM. We were the only diners, so we thought it was cool that we can eat at non-prime times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Niu Noodle House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:41:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/niu-noodle-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Beef noodle ramen was not as good as Taiwanese beef noodle. Passssss.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramen Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:40:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ramen-ya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, there are 2 locations within neighboring vicinity of each other in the West Village. The ramen is similar to Shinsengumi. Slightly disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Baby Brasa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/baby-brasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/baby-brasa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The chicken was good, but it&amp;rsquo;s a little pricey though. Seems to be a common theme nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jeju Noodle Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jeju-noodle-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:53:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jeju-noodle-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good Korean ramyun. A little pricey though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sushi on Jones</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sushi-on-jones/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:28:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sushi-on-jones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another omakase. Decent sushi place. Fast in/out in 20 minutes. $58 total. Got an extra toro/uni hand roll which added another $20ish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nakazawa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nakazawa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:23:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nakazawa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an Omakase. Michelin 1 star. Very good for the price. Got sake pairing + sushi + EXTRAS&amp;hellip; only $220 per person. The lychee sorbet was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kosaka</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kosaka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:15:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kosaka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good kaiseki (~$180).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mew Men</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/mew-men/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:13:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/mew-men/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Japanese lunch was cheap and good. But this place is CLOSED now replaced by Menkoi Sato, a ramen place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Sodi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/i-sodi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:55:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/i-sodi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Food was just ok even though it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended by people. Probably a good date place though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>St Tropez</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/st-tropez/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/st-tropez/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Great for the price, although I was here on a pescetarian date. I thought I could do pescetarian, and I can&amp;rsquo;t. Would come back for actual meats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Grom</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/grom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:38:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/grom/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I like the gelato here. A bit expensive but good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dominique Ansel Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/dominique-ansel-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:35:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/dominique-ansel-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting desserts and pretty good. In the summer, they have burrata frozen yogurt as well as some type of watermelon frosty thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re also known for the Cronut, but it can be bought at the Spring location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Noodle King of Nyc</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodle-king-of-nyc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:47:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/noodle-king-of-nyc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Decent noodles. Cheap. Tastes kind of homely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Spotted Pig</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/the-spotted-pig/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:12:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/the-spotted-pig/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Burger was OK. Very bleu cheesy. The shoestring fries were annoying to eat and overly salty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chumleys</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/chumleys/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:11:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/chumleys/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Their burger is better than Minetta&amp;rsquo;s. Nuff said.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jack's Wife Freda</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/jacks-wife-freda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/jacks-wife-freda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Got the Shakshooka. I also asked for hot sauce, and it was some wet guacamole green looking thing. It has a nice kick to it. The shakshooka was also green too instead of the normal red sauce. Has a good kick to it and was also more sour than usual. Also got a side of the duck bacon which was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, skip the lines and sit at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Buvette</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/buvette/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:38:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/buvette/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place is really good. Their steamed eggs are super fluffy, but pretty expensive. It&amp;rsquo;s crowded but easy to walk in as 1.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mighty Quinn's BBQ</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/mighty-quinns-bbq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:16:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bbq/mighty-quinns-bbq/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Their brisket is always good for the price.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Due West</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/due-west/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:51:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/due-west/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Great bar/vibe. This new-ish place is definitely going to be popular.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Otheroom</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-otheroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:48:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-otheroom/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good date vibe in the West Village.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Standard Biergarten</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/standard-biergarten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:13:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/standard-biergarten/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Vibe reminds me of Wurstkuche in Los Angeles. But without the distinct dogs and beers. Still cool though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Employees Only</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/employees-only/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:05:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/employees-only/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s alright. Bar gets crowded. Food is decent. It&amp;rsquo;s a has been.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>