<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mandalay Bay on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/neighborhood/mandalay-bay/</link><description>Recent content in Mandalay Bay on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 14:01:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/neighborhood/mandalay-bay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Burger Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/burger-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 14:01:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/burger-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Burger Bar is a small burger chain by French chef Hubert Keller. This place is basically a higher scale build-your-own burger restaurant where just about every ingredient costs some extra money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. Las Vegas, even back in 2012, was pretty cool for a food haven. They had a ton of options, and they go through turnover pretty quickly. This restaurant as of this edit is surprisingly still open. I remember they were infamous for having a $100 burger which had lobster and truffles on it. It was definitely too rich for me though I had a $70 white truffle burger in New York City in 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>RM Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/rm-seafood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 13:45:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/las/rm-seafood/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In Las Vegas, Rick Moonen&amp;rsquo;s Seafood at the Mandalay Bay is suppose to be pretty good. There are 2 restaurants of his here: one is the fixed course meal higher end restaurant, and the other (this one) is just a middle tier restaurant. The menu is a little strange as they have your typical American no frills seafood AND sushi. My buddy ordered the sushi portions, and he was quite unimpressed. Then again, I would never order sushi from a restaurant like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>