<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prime Rib on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/prime-rib/</link><description>Recent content in Prime Rib on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:30:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/prime-rib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Dynamo Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-dynamo-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:30:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-dynamo-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-dynamo-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dynamo Room is a relatively new steakhouse located in the Penn District, right next to Madison Square Garden and in the heart of the area. The whole area feels like Times Square, considering how there are a lot of police presence with a lot of crowds. The restaurant seats 200 people, and I was easily able to make a reservation at 5:30 PM for 4 people without any issues. What initially attracted me to this restaurant was the summer restaurant week menu. For $45, it seemed like a good deal, especially given that the items seem to represent their normal menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-view%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/"&gt;Manhatta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Modern&lt;/a&gt;. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like. Previously when this was opened, it was a buffet with &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/the-view-restaurant-and-lounge-new-york"&gt;not-so-great rated food&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/"&gt;Mari&lt;/a&gt;. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/"&gt;Le Bernardin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/"&gt;Le Rock&lt;/a&gt;. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night. The restaurant is located on the second floor, but you check in on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Tete d'Or</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:54:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/la-tete-dor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-tete-dor%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Tête d&amp;rsquo;Or by Daniel is a tribute to timeless flavors and traditions with infusion of French flavors. What attracted me with this restaurant was that chef Daniel Boulud has a pretty decent track record of delivering good refined flavors. We went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-gratin/"&gt;Le Gratin&lt;/a&gt; previously, and we were very impressed by the taste of everything. As usual because he also holds some type of celebrity status, this restaurant is located in a posh area very close to Eleven Madison. I was able to book a reservation about a week out for 5:30 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monkey-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/"&gt;Au Cheval&lt;/a&gt; and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monterey%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me. We were able to make a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday night with no hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St. You can&amp;rsquo;t miss it because there&amp;rsquo;s a carpet laid out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keens Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 20:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For this memorial weekend, we wanted to go somewhere out of town, but we had to cancel plans including non refundable bus passes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching the Cooking Channel as my background noise, and they had an episode of steak. My partner hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Keen&amp;rsquo;s, and I thought this would be a great time to introduce them to it. I had been here back in 2018 for the first time, and it had a very delicious, if not the best, prime rib. Dinner reservations were difficult to make, so we opted for a lunch reservation instead which was quite easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gallagher's Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gallaghers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:05:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gallaghers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The cream of spinach tastes like Lawry&amp;rsquo;s. The horseradish cream was good. The prime rib not as good as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens"&gt;Keen&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Old Homestead</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:50:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first visit and not pictured, we got the aged rib eye for 2. It was surprisingly good and flavorful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/old-homestead%2F1_bacon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;applewood smoked slab of bacon&lt;/strong&gt; was thick and tasty. For 2 people, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to just get 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/old-homestead%2F2_prime_rib.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;prime rib&lt;/strong&gt; on the bone was super thick and good. Like Keen&amp;rsquo;s, this is a monster and can probably be shared by 2 people. I would say the thickness of this was probably close to 1.25 inches. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the whole thing comfortably. It came with cream of horseradish and chunky horseradish on the side. The cream of horseradish was delicious. The consistency was similar to sour cream but with that hint of horseradish in it. The steak itself was cooked a solid medium rare throughout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>