<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pizza on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/pizza/</link><description>Recent content in Pizza on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/pizza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pizzarte</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 12:06:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</guid><description>PizzArte is one of those casual Italian pizza-esque restaurants in the Midtown area. Their goal is to deliver the spirit of Naples with affordable costs. We ended up here after looking for a cheaper Italian restaurant in the area that also had lasagna since we had more expensive plans the next day. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Friday evening around 7:30 PM and were seated upstairs.</description></item><item><title>I Love Panzerotti</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/i-love-panzerotti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 21:47:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/i-love-panzerotti/</guid><description>Summary This little pizza shop is down right at the edge of South/West Village close to a Shake Shack. The panzerottis are like super thin calzones that are frieds as oppose to baked.
The dough that they use here is really tasty. It&amp;rsquo;s chewy, has a nice bounce, and has a very nice flavor profile to it. The dough definitely has a distinct flavor to it that makes it taste super fresh.</description></item><item><title>Paulie Gee's Slice Shop</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees-slice-shop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 19:47:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees-slice-shop/</guid><description>Summary This is Paulie Gee&amp;rsquo;s sliced pizza. You can order a whole pie if you want. All in all though, I think Vinnie&amp;rsquo;s in Brooklyn is better.
The pepperoni pizza was good but not great for slice. If you come here expecting a similar crust to what the original Paulie Gee&amp;rsquo;s serves, prepare to be disappointed. The crust is not that great compared to a lot of NYC sliced pizza places.</description></item><item><title>Paulie Gee's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 22:32:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/paulie-gees/</guid><description>Summary Came here around 5:30 PM on a Saturday, and the wait was quoted 60 minutes. In reality, it was just 45 minutes, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad.
The pizza itself is similar to Roberta&amp;rsquo;s. The pizza dough is pretty fluffy, and it tastes pretty good.
The Benny Gee had much better taste than Ricotta Be Kiddin Me. The ricotta pizza was more salty, but the Benny Gee definitely had a better well rounded profile.</description></item><item><title>Massa Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/massa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 17:00:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/massa/</guid><description>Summary The place was pretty dead when I went, but the pizza was excellent. In some ways I actually liked this more than Lombardis.
Got a margarita pizza with pepperoni on it, and it was tasty.
Would love to go back and try their stromboli or calzones as well.
Overall Impression It&amp;rsquo;s a nice addition to the sparse Long Island City neighborhood. The pepperoni pizza quality and ingredients tasted really good.</description></item><item><title>Adrienne's Pizza Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/adriennes-pizza-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 17:36:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/adriennes-pizza-bar/</guid><description>Was ok. Nothing too memorable. Got the pizza with proscuitto on top. I think they should&amp;rsquo;ve cut it into smaller pieces.</description></item><item><title>Macchina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/macchina/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:26:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/macchina/</guid><description>They are known on Instagram for their Burrata pizza which was about $25. It was ok. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go out of my way to get it because it literally is just a margarita style pizza with a big piece of burrata cheese in the middle. The burrata wasn&amp;rsquo;t that soft when cut for some reason.</description></item><item><title>Lucky Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lucky-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:25:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lucky-pizza/</guid><description>One word: cheap.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Rollio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizza-rollio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:24:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizza-rollio/</guid><description>This place is just OK. Super gimmicky with the rolling pizza thing. Would rather have a slice than that. It&amp;rsquo;s like eating a super thin pizza that is malleable.</description></item><item><title>Marta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/marta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:23:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/marta/</guid><description>Pretty good. The meat one with all the salami was good.</description></item><item><title>Detroit Pizza</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/detroit-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:22:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/detroit-pizza/</guid><description>The full name of this restaurant is &amp;ldquo;Lions and Tigers and Squares Detroit Pizza&amp;rdquo;. Obviously did not want that in the title of the post. Got the pepperoni and yellow peppers, and it was pretty good. Not too expensive&amp;hellip; ~$12-14</description></item><item><title>Martina Pizzeria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/martina-pizzeria/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:20:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/martina-pizzeria/</guid><description>Fast food version of Marta&amp;rsquo;s. It&amp;rsquo;s good. I like the salami and hot peppers, and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly inexpensive.</description></item><item><title>Champion</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/champion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:18:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/champion/</guid><description>There are actually a lot of locations for this. I think Vinnie&amp;rsquo;s way better in the north Williamsburg area.</description></item><item><title>Roberta's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/robertas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:17:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/robertas/</guid><description>Pizza is pretty good and cheap. Their beer list is pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Vinnie's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/vinnies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/vinnies/</guid><description>My cousin Vinnie&amp;rsquo;s place is the best. Love the cali burger.</description></item><item><title>Emmy Squared</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/emmy-squared/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:15:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/emmy-squared/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;ve been here numerous times to both the East Village and Manhattan locations, and they have consistently delivered pretty well within expectations.
The fried chicken sandwich is delectable. It was really good and pretty spicy with the right kick.
The Le Big Matt is like pretty big too. The cheese is super melty which makes it a little messy but pretty delicious.
The Roni Supreme is by far my favorite.</description></item><item><title>Lombardi's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lombardis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 16:35:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lombardis/</guid><description>Whew, I only have 2 more New York City food posts including this one. Previously, you may have noticed the sliced pizza style. Here we have the gourmet pizza. This one is courtesy of Lombardi&amp;rsquo;s Pizza. On one side, we have italian sausage and pepperoni, and the on the other side we have margherita. As with all pizza, it&amp;rsquo;s all about the toppings, crust, and flavor. The crust is pretty good for what it is.</description></item></channel></rss>