<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nolita on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/nolita/</link><description>Recent content in Nolita on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:35:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/nolita/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Musket Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-musket-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Musket Room has been around for a while, and it is located close to the Broadway/Lafayette train in Manhattan. Chef Mary Attea is the head chef of this restaurant, and according to the Michelin Guide, the kitchen is predominantly women. We picked this restaurant to try for tonight primarily because the menu looked like a slightly different take on New American than what we were used to. I was easily able to book a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wayan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indonesian/wayan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 14:36:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/indonesian/wayan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were in the typical SOHO shopping area, walking around, and lounging. We noticed that the traffic in this area is starting to recover and getting a little more traffic than usual. It was around 5 PM, and we started getting a little hungry. I had remembered Wayan receiving a lot of accolades. I often get it confused with &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/wayla/"&gt;Wayla&lt;/a&gt;, so I never quite remembered why it was so popular. Fortunately, we were able to do a walk-in on a cloudy Saturday night at 5:15 PM. The host sat us right in front of the kitchen which was pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Balzem</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/balzem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 11:46:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/balzem/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is right around the corner of Lombardi&amp;rsquo;s in Nolita. We were hungry, and of course all the super popular restaurants had wait time. This one though for some reason had none, so why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/balzem%2F1_bread.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They served us complimentary &lt;strong&gt;bread&lt;/strong&gt; with olive oil and olives. Nothing much to say, but it was a nice gesture and good too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/balzem%2F2_octopus.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also ordered &lt;strong&gt;octopus&lt;/strong&gt; which was cooked in red wine sauce, pan seared and served on arugula salad. The octopus surprisingly had a very nice char to it. It was crunchy or tender at the right spots. I liked how some parts of it was like eating a soft sponge, and others was like biting into a nice crisp.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sosta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-sosta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:58:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/the-sosta/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place was ok. Pasta was good, but it needs protein. The meat cheese board was just ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cherche Midi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cherche-midi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:09:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cherche-midi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Same owner as the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/"&gt;Minetta Tavern&lt;/a&gt;. Great for the price. I liked teh suckling pork because it was straight up fat with crispy skin. Got the whole fish, and it was great too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only problem is it is CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Egg Shop</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/egg-shop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:35:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/egg-shop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This place sucks, is pricey, and is extremely overrated. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why this place has so many people. $18 for a egg on top of salad with fried chicken.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice to Riches</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/rice-to-riches/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 16:40:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/rice-to-riches/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my last NY food post for a while. For the last day to cap off the trip, we went to Rice To Riches in Nolita. This was actually really close to our Blue Ribbon meal a few posts ago. Rice To Riches is basically the equivalent to Baskin Robbins 31 flavors in LA. Instead of many choices of ice cream, you have many choices for tapioca. You also have the option of sampling any flavor that you want. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge tapioca person, but I was willing to give this a try&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lombardi's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lombardis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 16:35:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/lombardis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lombardis%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1905, Lombardi has been credited with developing New York style pizza and being the first pizzeria in the United States. This has been challenged by many NYC locals especially pizza aficionados. Having been here back in 2012, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of witnessing the evolution of this pizzeria. I&amp;rsquo;ve been here several times, and it&amp;rsquo;s always easier to walk in early dinner times vs prime time. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seated fast and food will come right away especially now there are so many other competing pizza places nearby.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>