<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Midtown on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown/</link><description>Recent content in Midtown on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:59:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/midtown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Palladino's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/palladinos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:59:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/palladinos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/palladinos%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palladino&amp;rsquo;s Steak and Seafood is owned by Joseph Palladino, who was a former NYPD officer and opened Nick and Sam&amp;rsquo;s Steakhouse in Dallas 20 years ago. He wanted to bring this restaurant type back to his motherland city, NYC. This restaurant recently opened in Grand Central Terminal, just opposite of the Apple store in the main concourse on the second level. I was able to make a reservation for 2 very easily for 5:45 for the dining area that has fantastic views of the main Grand Central floor and its beautiful ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lillie's Victorian Establishment</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/gastropub/lillies-victorian-establishment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 23:05:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/gastropub/lillies-victorian-establishment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lillies-victorian-establishment%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve heard of Lillie&amp;rsquo;s Victorian Establishment, and it&amp;rsquo;s been on a list for a while because it&amp;rsquo;s a very festive restaurant. It&amp;rsquo;s always difficult to get last minute reservations, but fortunately as we won theater lottery on a cold single-digit weather, there was not a lot of tourist or foot traffic at all in the Times Square area. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM very easily just a few hours in advance. As you can tell from the picture, there was a lot of snow, and the exterior was already decorated with a lot of winter ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shuya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shuya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:36:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/shuya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/shuya%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we ate at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mia/ogawa/"&gt;Ogawa&lt;/a&gt;, we were talking to the restaurant manager in Miami, and he said his old friend ran this restaurant in NYC. Apparently this restaurant originally existed in Queens, but it moved into Manhattan. At last, we had a Friday where didn&amp;rsquo;t really have any plans, so I suggested this restaurant. I was able to book a table for 2 for 6:00 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance without issues. This restaurant is known for their yuzu flavored ramen.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Four Twenty Five</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/four-twenty-five/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:04:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/four-twenty-five/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/four-twenty-five%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four Twenty Five is a contemporary, elevated restaurant from Chef Chef Jean-Georges Vongerichten. This restaurant was open on Christmas Day, and it was on our list for a while. They offered a tasting menu which mostly resembled items off their normal menu. The day prior, I was very easily able to book reservations without any issues for 2 at 4 PM. We arrived about 15 minutes early, and they had us wait in the bar area while they prepared our table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Santi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/santi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:18:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/santi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/santi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santi is a fine-dining Italian restaurant starring Chef Michael White. What was most noticeable for me was that he co-opened Marea, which ended up getting multiple accolades, including a coveted 2 Michelin Star. This restaurant is located very close to the 5th Ave and 53rd subway, and reservations were quite easy to get a few days in advance. The outside seemed different in that it felt like it was a side entrance into a place on the side a building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/moono/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:13:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/moono/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/moono%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moono is yet another Korean restaurant that has been on my list for quite a while. Its allure for me was uni rice and Pyongyang cold noodles. I finally got a chance to book this restaurant, and it was easy to book for 2 for 6 PM on a Friday evening. This restaurant is a new project by Chef Kim from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/"&gt;Jua&lt;/a&gt;. When I learned this, I had higher expectations of what I was to experience. When you arrive at the restaurant, it&amp;rsquo;s located in this interesting 3-story building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Elephant Ear</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/elephant-ear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 22:08:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/elephant-ear/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/elephant-ear%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elephant Ear, an interesting name for a Thai restaurant, has been on my list for quite a while. In this area near the theaters, there is an ongoing rotation of Thai restaurants. We happened to catch a Broadway show, so I made a reservation for two people at 6 PM. When we went to the restaurant after our show, they mentioned that there&amp;rsquo;s a 1.5 hour limit for dining.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Limusina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/limusina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:41:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/limusina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/limusina%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/"&gt;Quality Branded restaurateurs&lt;/a&gt; comes another restaurant in a similar vein to popular hits like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/"&gt;Bad Roman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zous&lt;/a&gt;. The cuisine for this restaurant is Mexican-inspired and has all the snazzy colors to indicate this could be fun. This restaurant is near the Hudson Yards area, and it was very easy to make a reservation for 2 for 6 PM on a Friday night. This restaurant is about 1 block away from the E-train exit off 34th.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brasserie Cognac</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/brasserie-cognac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 17:09:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/brasserie-cognac/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/brasserie-cognac%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brasserie Cognac recently opened a restaurant branch right next to Central Park South. At first glance of the menu, it seemed rather basic, but I figured if a restaurant opened in this area, it should be pretty decent. On a Saturday evening, we were able to walk in without reservations and were seated immediately. My first thought looking around was that there are a decent amount of tourists. This restaurant is part of the Serafina family.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Toloache</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/toloache/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 13:14:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/toloache/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/toloache%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished watching &amp;ldquo;Punch&amp;rdquo;, a Broadway play that we won through the lottery. Because we&amp;rsquo;ve tried an abundant amount of restaurants already, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to get slim. I was finally able to start trying out some Mexican restaurants, since my partner rarely picks this. Toloache was one that was nearby, and we were able to walk in without reservations at around 5:00 PM on a Saturday evening. We were seated in the second floor near the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oncheon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oncheon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:23:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oncheon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oncheon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oncheon is all about hot pot, Korean style. What I was curious about was how different was Japanese hot pot from Korean. It&amp;rsquo;s not that different. Both use high end quality meat, and their broths resemble their cultures. For example, Japanese hot pot tends to be light with miso or seaweed type flavors. The Korean hot pot seems to be similar to what you might find in Korean restaurants. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday night without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Baires Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 21:45:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/argentine/baires-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/baires-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw an early afternoon theater show, and right after, we decided to check out Argentine food. Baires Grill was appealing because it is a Miami chain, and this is their only non-Miami location. We are planning on visiting Miami in the near future, so I was curious to see how this food differs than other Argentine restaurants we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. We walked in around 4 PM on a Saturday without reservations, and they seated us immediately without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kochi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:48:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kochi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kochi has been on my list for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to several of the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other restaurants, and they&amp;rsquo;re all delightful. This is his first solo project, after working in kitchens like Le Bernardin, Per Se, and Morimoto. What&amp;rsquo;s also great about this restaurant is that it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to get a reservation if you just book a few days out. We were able to get one at 5:30 PM on a Friday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BKK New York</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/bkk-new-york/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 18:26:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/bkk-new-york/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bkk-new-york%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Thai restaurants are located around the Midtown area. This one is a modern Thai restaurant inspired by the flavors of Bangkok street food. Unlike other Thai restaurants, the menu here has some interesting options that lured us in. The name comes from the airport code for Bangkok in Thailand. Since we were around the area, I made a reservation for 2 just a few hours before very easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Dynamo Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-dynamo-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:30:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-dynamo-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-dynamo-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dynamo Room is a relatively new steakhouse located in the Penn District, right next to Madison Square Garden and in the heart of the area. The whole area feels like Times Square, considering how there are a lot of police presence with a lot of crowds. The restaurant seats 200 people, and I was easily able to make a reservation at 5:30 PM for 4 people without any issues. What initially attracted me to this restaurant was the summer restaurant week menu. For $45, it seemed like a good deal, especially given that the items seem to represent their normal menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Papa San</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/papa-san/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 23:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/papa-san/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/papa-san%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papa San was on my list for a while, especially from the folks that did &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/llama-inn/"&gt;Llama Inn&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an izakaya (think of Japanese tapas), made with a Peruano-Japanese influence. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting blend of cuisines, and it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon. In Peru, they do have a lot of Asian influences, such as lomo saltado, where they use soy sauce in the dish. We made a reservation for 2 for 5:00 PM on a Sunday evening very easily. This is located very close to Hudson Yards.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Benjamin Steakhouse Prime</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:45:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/benjamin-steakhouse-prime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/benjamin-steakhouse-prime%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restaurant Week is notorious for it&amp;rsquo;s multi-course offerings that feature items that aren&amp;rsquo;t on their respective restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menus. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun tip. Steak places are typically a really good bang for the buck as they typically offer you things on their menu. As a way to chill out and celebrate solo, I went to Benjamin Prime. I walked in on a Friday around 4:30 PM without any issues alone. They asked if I wanted a table for 1 or sit at a bar, and I asked for a table which they accommodated. This location is a very close walking distance from Bryant Park.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rosevale Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rosevale-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was another Broadway showing that we had to attend. Our theater district restaurant pool is thinning a bit, so this one was somewhat difficult to locate. It reminds me of a Midtown staple type of restaurant that is very friendly to the theater crowd, and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get in. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening around 5 PM without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Becco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:05:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/becco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/becco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becco was on our list for a while. This restaurant in the Theater District was always full around theater times, so of course, that&amp;rsquo;s naturally alluring. It was first opened in 1993 by Lidia Bastianich and her son, Joe, who you might recognize from the U.S. version of the MasterChef series. The Yelp ratings of the food seem surprisingly low compared to the Google counterpart, so that increase our curiosity. We were able to easily make a reservation the earlier in the day for 5:15 PM on a Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Locanda Verde</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:55:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/locanda-verde/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/locanda-verde%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef Andrew Carmellini has some pretty good restaurants (&lt;a href="https://www.nhgnyc.com/"&gt;NoHo Hospitality&lt;/a&gt;) that we&amp;rsquo;ve been to. Some recent ones that we really enjoyed include &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/"&gt;Cafe Carmellini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/"&gt;Carne Mare&lt;/a&gt;. Locanda Verde opened a second location in the Hudson Yards area. This is his ode to urban Italian cuisine, and we wanted to try this out because the exterior seemed very nice. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:15 on a Friday evening without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Il Divino</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 16:36:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/il-divino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/il-divino%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into the city to watch a broadway show, and I had to look for a restaurant in the area without worrying about reservations. I stumbled onto this Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Italian restaurant that seemed to have pretty decent menu items. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Friday evening pretty easily, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much foot traffic at all. We were seated next to the window and had a very casual, quick dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-view%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/"&gt;Manhatta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Modern&lt;/a&gt;. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like. Previously when this was opened, it was a buffet with &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/the-view-restaurant-and-lounge-new-york"&gt;not-so-great rated food&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sozai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 17:43:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sozai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sozai%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished watching a matinee of a Broadway show, and we&amp;rsquo;re running out of desirable early dinner options in the Midtown area. This one was on my list for quite some time as it looked like a restaurant that was a no frills izakaya type restaurant. This restaurant is about 2 doors down from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/"&gt;Valerie&lt;/a&gt;, a pretty popular Midtown restaurant. We were able to walk in around 4:30 PM on a Saturday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Don</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:45:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/don-don/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/don-don%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided Don Don because we&amp;rsquo;ve really been enjoying Chef Sungchul Shim&amp;rsquo;s restaurants, including &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/"&gt;Mari&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/"&gt;Gui&lt;/a&gt;. I made a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday just a few days ahead, and it was fairly easy. Located very close to Bryant Park, it&amp;rsquo;s along the way from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/"&gt;Valerie&lt;/a&gt;, and it can be easily missed. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty discreet until you take a look at the front window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon entering, it reminded me of when I was in the South Korea malls where they had a ton of little stools and electric BBQs. People would just congregate, drink, and eat a lot of BBQ things. The atmosphere definitely feels like that as the seats are pretty close together, and the crowd noise can get a little loud.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:31:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gui caught my attention because it offered a baked Alaska and prime rib. What I did not realize was that this restaurant had some folks with a track record of good Korean foods. Chef Sung Chul Shim comes from Kochi and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/"&gt;Mari&lt;/a&gt;. Pastry chef, Sarah Smith, comes from many fine kitchens including &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/"&gt;Le Bernardin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/"&gt;Le Rock&lt;/a&gt;. The reservation was very easy to reserve for a 5:15 PM dinner on a Friday night. The restaurant is located on the second floor, but you check in on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raon</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 17:20:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/raon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/raon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raon is a new Korean tasting restaurant from Chef Soogil Lim and his wife, Sasook Youn. Their other restaurant, Soogil, is located in the East Village, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to open a more intimate fine dining type of restaurant. One of the key features that attracted me to this was that they would a tasting menu centered around kimchi. When we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, we simply adored it. So we wanted to see how this would compare because both restaurants emphasize that kimchi is a key part of the experience. I was able to book a 5:00 PM reservation for a Saturday without much issue. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming it&amp;rsquo;s because the restaurant is still fairly new. The restaurant is very close to the N/W train off of Lexington and Bloomingdales.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kausa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/peruvian/kausa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kausa%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had won another theater tickets for this Sunday, so we looked for a place nearby. My partner desired Peruvian food again, specifically lomo saltado. The best lomo saltado place we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had was actually &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/"&gt;Mario&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a comparable place, especially in New York City. We walked in on a late Sunday afternoon without issues, and we were seated promptly. Looking over the menu, they had your typical Peruvian options.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xie Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:58:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xie-bao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show this evening, and this &amp;ldquo;crab house&amp;rdquo; just recently opened in Manhattan. This originated from a Flushing stall, and their specialty is crab roe over rice or noodle. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening without reservations. The social media circuit really raved about this dish by showing off the roe, so we decided to try it. I figured there was no need to make reservations since Manhattan Midtown Chinese restaurants are usually pretty easy to get into.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Danji</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:18:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/danji/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/danji%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danji is Chef Hooni Kim&amp;rsquo;s first restaurant that opened 15 years ago. It earned a Michelin Star back in 2012 and closed in April 2023 due to a fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/"&gt;Meju&lt;/a&gt;, which was phenomenal for what it was. We decided to check out this to see how it was, so I made a reservation pretty easily a week prior for 5:30 PM for a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mitr Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:25:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/mitr-thai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mitr-thai%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitr Thai is a Midtown Thai restaurant that is located very close to Bryant Park. It can be a great option for Thai if you prefer to stay east of the Theater District. When we walked in around 5:30 PM on a Thursday night, we actually had to wait about 30-40 minutes. The restaurant was very full both downstairs and upstairs. We were seated upstairs in a 2-seater.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Five Acres</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/five-acres%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one appeal that attracted me to try out Five Acres was that they offered a Chicago beef sandwich. For some reason, there are very few places that serve this sandwich that I know of. There used to be &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/hanks-juicy-beef/"&gt;Hank&amp;rsquo;s Juicy Beef&lt;/a&gt;, but that closed down. The other Chicago beef place that I know of is in deep Brooklyn. Since we were around this Midtown area, I figured now is the right time to give this a shot. We were able to walk into this restaurant at 4:30 PM on a Sunday without reservations. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the downstairs promenade of Rockafeller Plaza, where all the sit-down restaurants reside near the skating rink.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SaiTong Thai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 11:11:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/saitong-thai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/saitong-thai%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SaiTong Thai was a relatively new Thai restaurant that opened near the Theater District. One of its allures is that it appears to be an upscale Thai restaurant. The menu when I glanced at it seemed pretty decent although the prices were on the higher side. Since we had a theater date, we decided to check this restaurant out. We easily made a reservation for a Saturday at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SEA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:58:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/sea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEA is a casual &lt;strong&gt;South East Asian&lt;/strong&gt; restaurant from Chef Jungsik Yim of two Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/"&gt;Jungsik&lt;/a&gt;. The restaurant offers a raw bar, small plates, and shareable plates with creativity. We were able to make a reservation pretty last minute for 5:15 PM on a Friday evening fairly easy. We arrived a little early, and they were able to seat us without issue. We had some high expectations that this restaurant will have great flavors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twin Tails</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:17:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/twin-tails/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/twin-tails%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new Southeast Asian restaurant is located on the third floor of the Columbus Circle mall. The restaurant is part of the &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurant group, which also included &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; to name a few. What was exciting about the menu here was that it was leaning into higher end Vietnamese and Thai flavors. We were able to make a reservation a few days in advance for two people at 5:15 PM on a Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bourbon Steak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 21:58:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bourbon-steak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bourbon-steak%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Mina is an award winning chef and restaurateur that currently runs and operates over 40 restaurants worldwide. He opened this restaurant in the JW Marriott Essex House, right across from Central Park south and near Columbus Circle. This is his love letter to the classic American steakhouse. Bourbon Steak has multiple locations in the United States, so it&amp;rsquo;s not an entirely new restaurant. I picked this restaurant particularly because of their prix fixe menu that seems to give a pretty good spread of what this restaurant has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pure Thai Cookhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/pure-thai-cookhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pure-thai-cookhouse%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won yet another lottery for one of the theater shows, so we were hoping to walk into Wondee Thai. As expected, there was a line outside and a wait inside, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble missing the show if we had waited. We instead opted to walk a block south to this restaurant which had no patrons. We were able to walk in for 2 at 5:30 PM on a Saturday night without reservations. There seemed to be 2 sections to this restaurant, a left and a right. We were seated on the left on a small table with stools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azalea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 19:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/azalea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/azalea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won the theater lottery to watch another play in the Theater district. This was on my list for some reason, and it was conveniently very close to the theater. The menu seemed quintessential Italian American type food, and as a bonus, they also have a 3-course theater menu prix fixe for $55 per person. I was able to make a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had previously been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Bar at The Modern&lt;/a&gt;, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options. The kitchen is the same, except if you book during lunch, you have access to the dinner tasting menu as well, i.e. the full experience. We made a reservation for 12:00 PM on a Saturday without much difficulties as long as you make the reservation when it opens up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mari%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kajiken</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:14:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/kajiken/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kajiken%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kajiken is located a few streets south of Bryant Park. I originally was trying to do a walk into Tonchin, but they told me there was a 1-hour wait for a single bar seat solo. Irked, I walked towards Bryant Park, and I found that there&amp;rsquo;s this ramen place that was on my list to try. Interestingly enough, they have both soup-based ramen and dry ramen. Their dry ramen is like most other dry-noodle things where there is some oils and mixtures at the bottom of the bowl, and you simply can mix everything. I was able to walk in about 30 minutes before closing time and was seated without issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Frena</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/frena/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/frena%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israeli Chef Efi Naon opened a relatively new Moroccan-Israeli and Middle Eastern inspired restaurant in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. I saw this on Yelp a few months ago, and the menu items look reasonably interesting. I was able to book a reservation very easily on a Friday for 5:15 PM without any issues. This restaurant is close to the 50th E train station and relatively near some of the outer edges of the Theater District.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monkey-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/"&gt;Au Cheval&lt;/a&gt; and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jasmine's Caribbean Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:45:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/caribbean/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jasmines-caribbean-cuisine%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Broadway show to catch, and this restaurant is located at a convenient &amp;ldquo;restaurant row&amp;rdquo; area. This area reminds me a little of St. Marks in East Village, where there is just a street full of restaurants that are also conveniently near theaters. My partner wanted to try this, so they were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:45 PM on a Wednesday evening. When we walked through the door, it felt like we walked into a shack.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Un Deux Trois</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 16:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/cafe-un-deux-trois/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cafe-un-deux-trois%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve walked past this restaurant several times eating at various restaurants prior to watching a theater show. Tonight, we had to eat something before our 7 PM show. We made a reservation for this restaurant for 5 PM without any trouble. When you walk in, it seemed like a very bustling restaurant. Looking at the menu prior, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all that interesting, but we thought this was a good day to try it since we had to eat fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sicily Osteria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:23:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/sicily/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sicily%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had another Friday outing to watch the Mary Jane broadway show starring Rachel McAdams. Because this was very last minute, my partner was able to book this restaurant in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen. As we explore more of this area, it&amp;rsquo;s turning out that there are a good amount of restaurant options especially for Italian food. We made reservations easily for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. It was noticeable there was a large amount of theater crowds since tables cleared right before 7 and 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/smith-and-mills%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/"&gt;Naro&lt;/a&gt;. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all. I thought this was to be a restaurant, but it seems like the atmosphere is definitely more of a bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Class on 38th</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:21:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/class-on-38th/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/class-on-38th%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Class on 38th was something that seemed interesting at first glance when I was browsing the &amp;ldquo;Hot and New&amp;rdquo; sections of Yelp. The menu looked like tapas with a price point that wasn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. I went here with a business partner, who was in town and looking for something to try. I made a reservation a few weeks back without any issues for 6 PM on a Thursday. When I walked in, they allowed me to sit early to wait for my guest to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Steak Frites Bistro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:03:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/steak-frites-bistro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/steak-frites-bistro%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant has been on my radar for years, and we finally got a chance to try this. What was appealing to me was the price and options that they had. Not only was it steak frites, but you had the opportunity to try different types of steaks if you really wanted. We had an early afternoon theater showing, and this location was within minutes. We were able to walk in around 5:00 PM on a Sunday without reservations, though they told us that we had to finish our food within 2.5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria Delbianco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:19:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-delbianco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-delbianco%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were craving for an early Italian dinner before seeing a Broadway show. Osteria Delbianco actually has two locations: one on 49th and another closer to Bryant Park. Both locations are really easy to get to. We were able to walk in without reservations at around 5 PM on a Friday early evening. The one appeal to me about this restaurant was that it seemed like a local Italian restaurant, and these typically can be hit or miss. The prices seemed reasonable, so we decided to try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amarone Scarlatto</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:37:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/amarone-scarlatto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/amarone-scarlatto%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had another theater show to go to, so I was tasked for looking something near the Theater District. We were watching some random TV show, and they showed lasagna. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the context, but my partner wanted that. As we&amp;rsquo;re still exploring the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area, I ended up finding this restaurant that we were able to walk in since the reservation system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monterey%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me. We were able to make a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday night with no hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bad-roman%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/about/the-team/"&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; that created this restaurant also helped create &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/"&gt;Quality Eats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant is very bustling, with lots of noise and all types of clientele. You will find many on their date nights, and you will find big parties celebrating something as if they were celebrities. The noise level is pretty loud, and you are seated pretty close to other tables. The music is also on the louder side too, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t uncomfortably loud. At times it was hard to hear our server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St. You can&amp;rsquo;t miss it because there&amp;rsquo;s a carpet laid out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Olle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 20:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/olle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/olle%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you visit sample sales frequently, there are 2 nearby the Nomad and Koreatown area. Because the sample sales close at 7 PM sharp, it compels you to look for food during core dinner hours. Fortunately if you go shop right after work and finish around 6 PM on weekdays, foot traffic to restaurants won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Olle is a Korean restaurant about a block away from the sample sale store on 5th Ave. We were able to walk in with no reservations at around 5:30 PM, which the restaurant started coincidentally getting busy around 6 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heno Heno</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:42:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/heno-heno/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/heno-heno%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner had won some tickets to watch Appropriate on Broadway starring Sarah Paulson. The show starts at 8, but we had to pick up the will-call tickets by 7:30. I saw this Japanese small eatery was nearby the theater on 46th St, and I thought this would be a decent restaurant to try out since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of little things we can order. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening at around 5:30 PM before it got busy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Havana Central</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:05:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuban/havana-central/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/havana-central%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was raining on this gloomy Friday, and we wanted to eat somewhere close to Rockafeller. I recalled we had tried to walk into this restaurant on prior days with no success. I looked them up on OpenTable and saw that they had openings throughout the night. We figured it was worth a shot to try to walk in, and we found success. We were seated next to the door inside a glass section of the restaurant towards the front at around 6:30 PM. There was a live trio band playing Cuban style music, and some people dancing near the entrance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Okdongsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:37:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/okdongsik/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/okdongsik%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is from a renowned Korean chef (Ok Dongsik) and is a 6 time &lt;a href="https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/seoul-capital-area/kr-seoul/restaurant/okdongsik"&gt;Michelin Seoul Bib Gourmand restaurant&lt;/a&gt;. We were nearby at a popular sample sale, and this was on my list for a while to checkout. The menu is very small and is straight forward. We were able to walk in at around 6:30 PM on a Wednesday evening without reservation. They turn over seats fairly quickly even though there can easily be a line of people waiting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:56:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally during every Thanksgiving Thursday, I cook for my partner some poultry thing whether it be quail or turkey breast. This year we decided to relieve me the duties of frantically looking for materials and cooking for 6 hours for the 2 of us. Marea was closed for a few months, and we&amp;rsquo;ve always had this on our list. Because it just reopened in October, I decided to pursue the Thanksgiving tasting menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Roosters</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 13:11:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/three-roosters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/three-roosters%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been just demolishing a ton of restaurants around the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/theater-district/"&gt;Theater District&lt;/a&gt; since we&amp;rsquo;ve been going to a lot of Broadway shows. This restaurant was on our eyes to go to, but they always take a small break between 4 to 5 PM, so it can put a little time crunch if you have a show around 6:30 to 7 PM. However despite the restaurant being small with probably 5 or 6 tables, we were able to walk in on a Sunday evening around 5:30 PM without reservations. The food here is less about your normal Thai food, and more about chicken set meals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hunt &amp; Fish Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:02:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hunt-and-fish-club%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner was able to secure another show lottery near Times Square. Because I work near here and the fact that they have been able to win so many lottery shows, we&amp;rsquo;re running out of choices for restaurants. We were walking along 44th, and we stumbled onto this restaurant. After looking at the menu and the ability to walk in without reservations, we decided to try out this restaurant, Hunt &amp;amp; Fish Club. We were able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Friday without reservations easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari.ne Handroll</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:57:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/marine-handroll/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marine-handroll%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari.ne (MariNe) Hand-Roll Bar is similar to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/kazunori/"&gt;KazuNori&lt;/a&gt; where it&amp;rsquo;s simply a &amp;ldquo;hand roll&amp;rdquo; bar. The hand rolls are fairly small, but quite delightful and fresh. You can order them in different flavors, and it&amp;rsquo;s sure to satisfy anyone that enjoys sushi in hand roll format. We were able to walk in at around 5:45 PM on a Monday evening, but we were told that we had to be done by 6:30 PM due to an upcoming reservation. More on this in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avra Estiatorio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:32:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/avra-estiatorio%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avra Estiatorio was a restaurant that we wanted to check out for a while now. Because we were going to watch Gutenberg Musical at 8 PM, this fit perfectly for the opportunity. Avra has several locations spread throughout the United States: 3 in Manhattan, 1 in Miami, and 1 in Beverly Hills. It&amp;rsquo;s a rather posh Greek seafood restaurant, and it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to all the other upper end ones, such as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/"&gt;Limani&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/"&gt;Milos&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to walk in at around 6 PM without reservations, and we were seated at the upper floor. When we met the hostess, they asked if we were seeing a show, and we acknowledged that we were.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nasrin's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/persian/nasrins-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:37:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/persian/nasrins-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nasrins-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to checkout a Persian restaurant, that is somewhat close to Central Park and within walkable distance from my work. This is a new restaurant that has been opened for around 3+ months already. In Los Angeles, they have their share of Persian, so it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to see how does NYC fare for this cuisine. The restaurant entrance is a little discreet. The door leads to the second floor which is where the restaurant sits. We were able to walk-in for 2 at 5:30 PM without reservations, though the restaurant filled up somewhat afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trattoria Dell'arte</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/trattoria-dellarte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/trattoria-dellarte/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/trattoria-dellarte%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near this area because we stopped by Nordstroms for some shopping. This area is pretty close to the southern side of Central Park, and we&amp;rsquo;ve almost tapped out all the restaurants here (or so I thought). Luckily my partner has continued to show interest in Italian foods because I love it. I found this restaurant that wasn&amp;rsquo;t that far from where we were, and it was also offering a 3 course prix fixe restaurant week menu for $45. We were able to walk in around 4:30 PM on a Sunday without any reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room at the Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:04:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-bar-room-at-the-modern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modern is a well known 2 star Michelin restaurant that has an appealing tasting menu. Its sibling restaurant, the Bar Room&amp;quot;, is located in the same area as the Modern restaurant, but literally is divided by tall gigantic glass panes. The Bar Room has a more casual feel, where there&amp;rsquo;s music pumping through the speakers, and it feels more bustling like the general NYC city culture. On the other side of the pane is the extravagant tasting menu, which we also visited. Go to the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/"&gt;Kitchen Table review&lt;/a&gt; for more of how that experience was like.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tempura-matsui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/"&gt;Secchu Yokota&lt;/a&gt;. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant. It was very easy to make reservations for one person the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Four Four South Village</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/four-four-south-village/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/four-four-south-village%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese food is one of the types of cuisines that is seldomly found in Manhattan and just simply cannot compare to the San Gabriel Valley in the greater Los Angeles area in California. I asked my partner before a show if they wanted to check this out, and to my surprise they said yes! Normally they are not fond of this type of food, especially when noodles are around. This is not too far from Broadway theaters. We were able to walk in around 5:30 PM on a Monday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giardino 54</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/giardino-54/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/giardino-54%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near Broadway and 50th to watch the Back to the Future musical, which was actually surprisingly good. After, we had wanted Thai food, but the restaurant was closed briefly. My partner didn&amp;rsquo;t use the restrooms at the theater, so I scrambled for another option that had a restroom and found this restaurant off of 54th. We were able to walk in without reservations for 2 at around 5:30 PM on a Saturday night. The host said that the &amp;ldquo;garden&amp;rdquo; was saved for just reservations, which we were fine with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chalong</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 19:25:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/chalong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chalong%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show to go to around 43rd and 9th Ave, so we decided to look around the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. In this area from my research, there seems to be some pretty good Thai restaurants that have been here for a bit or are opening up. We had recently gone to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/thai/lumlum/"&gt;LumLum&lt;/a&gt;, which focused on more Northern Thai cuisine. Here in Chalong which is on 9th Ave between 51st and 52nd, they are focused on more Southern Thai. This restaurant is a few months old, and we were able to get a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM the night prior to our arrival.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cucina 8 1/2</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cucina-8.5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:25:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/cucina-8.5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cucina-8.5%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were running errands around 5th Avenue, and this restaurant was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list. I learned that my partner picked this restaurant because it was on Sex &amp;amp; The City, so I had very low expectations. We stopped by around 5:30 PM on a Friday night, and we were able to walk in without reservations. The restaurant itself is at the bottom of the staircase as you walk in. We were seated in one of the private booths, which was quite comfortable and serene.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oceana</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:13:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oceana%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice parts of living and working in Manhattan is that there is so much you can do and improvise after work. We had a show at 8 PM from winning a lottery, so it was easy to meet up after work and look for something to eat. Pre-theater prix fixe menus are a nice thing. They are basically a small tasting menu that won&amp;rsquo;t fill your belly too much, and the price is reasonable. We ended up at Oceana here since we realized we were within its small pre-theater hours of 5-6 PM on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pizzarte</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 12:06:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/pizzarte/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/pizzarte%2F0_logo.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PizzArte is one of those casual Italian pizza-esque restaurants in the Midtown area. Their goal is to deliver the spirit of Naples with affordable costs. We ended up here after looking for a cheaper Italian restaurant in the area that also had lasagna since we had more expensive plans the next day. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Friday evening around 7:30 PM and were seated upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef's Table at Brooklyn Fare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table at Brooklyn Fare is a renown &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant by Chef Cesar Ramirez. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by Japanese cuisine with French technique, and the 13 course tasting menu tonight is focused on fish &amp;amp; shellfish with 1 meat course and 4 dessert courses. I was quite excited to come here since moving to NYC. This restaurant was always very difficult to get reservations, so it was great that we were able to when we wanted. This restaurant is currently rated number 61 out of 100 on the &lt;a href="https://www.theworlds50best.com/stories/News/the-worlds-50-best-restaurants-2023-51-100-list.html"&gt;The World&amp;rsquo;s Best 50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Osteria La Baia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-la-baia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:13:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/osteria-la-baia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/osteria-la-baia%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s an Italian restaurant in Midtown that didn&amp;rsquo;t require reservations at 6 PM on a Friday evening after work? This one. It&amp;rsquo;s very close to the Rockafeller area, right across the street from a food hall. There&amp;rsquo;s a small car with a ton of flowers coming out of it. You can&amp;rsquo;t really miss it. We were able to walk in pretty easily, and we were seated towards the front. Because this restaurant is not exactly super popular, the attention and seating was quite comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ophelia</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 16:55:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/ophelia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ophelia%2F0_sign.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ophelia is a cocktail bar located in Midtown East near 1st Ave and 50th. It&amp;rsquo;s located at the top of Beekman Tower. This was built in 1928, and it was originally known as the Panhellenic Tower. The bar and hotel originally served as a womens-only club and hotel space for Greek sororities. When you walk into the lobby of the hotel, take the middle elevator to the 26th floor for entrance. We did have to make reservations ahead of time, but they are pretty easy to procure weeks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Charlie Palmer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/charlie-palmer%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had yet another show to catch, so we decided to look around the Bryant Park area. I stumbled onto Charlie Palmer, and it had been on my list of steak places to try. What was nice about this place specifically is they offered a 2-course pre-theatre menu for $49 which included a starter and entree. If you wanted dessert, you would have to pay an additional $10. Lucky for us, we weren&amp;rsquo;t that hungry, so a 2-course meal sounded fine for us. The waiter mentioned that the portion size for either course was the same as if you ordered in peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sake Bar Hagi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-bar-hagi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 16:52:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/sake-bar-hagi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sake-bar-hagi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re back from Hawaii, we went to go see Sweeney Todd, a musical that was one of my favorites. Nearby, we decided to eat something quick and light, so we opted for izakaya. Sake Bar Hagi, according to their website, says it&amp;rsquo;s New York&amp;rsquo;s first authentic izakaya since 1985. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what that really means, but we&amp;rsquo;ll find out. We arrived around 5:30 PM on a Saturday evening, and we were seated immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Rock</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 21:30:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-rock/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/le-rock%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Rock is one of those new hot and busy restaurants around the Rockafeller area because it comes from the team of Frenchette. The majority of the menu is in French, and it had been receiving pretty stellar reviews for the most part. We walked in at 5:45 PM, and we were very fortunate that they were able to seat us due to a prior cancellation. We were told that we would have to be done with dinner within 90 minutes. Despite my partner normally eating slower than most, I thought it was worth a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Duomo 51</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/duomo-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:06:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/duomo-51/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/duomo-51%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Memorial Day weekend, we&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying our free time just idling at home and doing chores. For Monday, my partner wanted to run some errands, and we were around the Rockafeller area. Because it was still a bit early around 4 PM, it was difficult to find restaurants that had already turned over to their dinner time. Eventually, my partner pointed out this restaurant, and we decided to give it a try. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the 7th floor of the Hilton DoubleTree hotel on 5th Ave and 51st.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Masseria</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 16:35:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/la-masseria/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-masseria%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had tickets to watch Phantom of the Opera before it closes in April, and my partner was scouring for some type of restaurant week menu to eat. They landed on this restaurant which is pretty close by as it had last minute vacancy. I already had very low expectations on some of these Italian restaurants that are close to theaters especially ones that are restaurant week driven. The restaurant week menu had some overlap with the normal dishes, but the ingredients to me did not really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empelln</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:54:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/empellon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/empellon%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we were again running some errands in this Midtown East area close to Central Park. We are running a bit dry on Italian options, so fortunately my partner finally said &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to a Mexican restaurant that I have wanted to go to for a long time. I vaguely recall Empelln having a Michelin Star a while back, but I cannot find any information on it at this time. I even asked ChatGPT, and they thought it had received a star in the Michelin 2019 NYC guide. Regardless, I have wanted to come here to try their infamous dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Felice</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/felice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 16:35:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/felice/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/felice%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felice appears to be an Italian premium chain restaurant with locations around New York and Florida. We were around the area shopping and walking around for errands of course, and my partner fortunately has been on an Italian binge recently. They really love lasagna, and this restaurant nearby had it on its menu. We were able to walk in on a Sunday without reservation at around 5:30 PM. When you walk in, it appears to be a coffee shop with a barista. The restaurant is actually located on the bottom floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cha Pa's Noodles and Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/vietnamese/cha-pas-noodles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cha-pas-noodles%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work around the Rockafeller area, and I had to walk towards the Midtown West for an errand during lunch. Near the area that I was in, I noticed this Vietnamese pho restaurant that didn&amp;rsquo;t have many people. Since it was cold outside and before I head back, I decided to check this out for lunch, considering it had some basic pho options. When I walked in, there were some solo diners who were scarfing their noodles fast, so I felt at ease that this was would be a quick lunch spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aquavit%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have &lt;strong&gt;2 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/"&gt;Aska&lt;/a&gt; recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:45:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/tan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner saw this restaurant on their Instagram feed, and since it&amp;rsquo;s a new Mexican restaurant, we thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to check out. I know absolutely nothing about the Chef Richard Sandoval and Chef Jonatn Gomez Luna Torres, but the menu looked pretty interesting and looks like it can bring an upscale experience and taste of Mexican cuisine. We were able to get 5 PM reservation easily on a Thursday evening, and they still have not gotten their liquor license by our visit tonight. That&amp;rsquo;s fine because they do offer mocktails, which I am a huge fan of in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gordon Ramsay Fish and Chips</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 23:09:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Times Square area, and this new fast food fish and chips restaurant just opened from Gordon Ramsay. The restaurant also has locations in Las Vegas, Orlando, DC, and now New York City. Gordon Ramsay used to have restaurants opened in NYC, but they have all been closed for quite some time. This is the only restaurant that he now has in NYC. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Piccola Cucina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 15:28:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/piccola-cucina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Piccola Cucina other than that it&amp;rsquo;s real close to Bloomingdales in Midtown. When we tried to stop in at 5:30 PM as a walk-in many months ago, they told us there was a 2 hour wait. Since we knew today we were going to be around the area, I saw they had a few openings and quickly booked a reservation for 6 PM for 2. This review is for the Midtown Uptown location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Naro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:28:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/naro%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naro is a new Korean restaurant that opened right next to the Rockafeller ice skating rink. According to the menu, the Naro name was inspired by South Korea&amp;rsquo;s first ever space vehicle to successfully achieve Earth&amp;rsquo;s orbit and also from the Korean phrase nah-ro (which means &amp;ldquo;through me&amp;rdquo;). Naro focuses on Korean cuisine, drawing inspiration from classic dishes from different moments in Korean history. Lastly, this is the third restaurant from the Atomix and Attaboy founders, so there is definitely some expectations. We actually were able to book a reservation on a Wednesday evening for 5:30 PM without much issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Reading Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:37:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-reading-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reading Room is a restaurant that caught my eye on Yelp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New and Hot&amp;rdquo; list. The menu is fairly small, simple, but seemed like it could be a good one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for restaurants around my work area that I could potentially refer others for drinks or a not too expensive dinner. This restaurant is located in the back of The Gotham Hotel on 46th between Madison and Fifth Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gatsby Landing</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:34:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gatsby-landing%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby Landing has been on my list for quite some time. The menu is reasonably priced, and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly close to my office and close to the 42nd trains. I figured today would be the day to check it out, since my options are running a little thin since I was looking for a walk-in restaurant. We arrived here around 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, and we were able to walk in easily for a party of 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Serafina</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serafina/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 15:18:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serafina/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/serafina%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near the Columbus Circle area just shopping and walking around. Generally, this area doesn&amp;rsquo;t have too many great places to eat, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide what we were in the mood for. I had proposed the thought of Serafina since I&amp;rsquo;ve never been there and my partner had a fantastic experience back in their home country. We were able to walk in without reservations during the core hours of dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ai Ki Ya</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/ai-ki-ya/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 14:42:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/ai-ki-ya/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had to run errands around Macy&amp;rsquo;s, so this was a good chance to check out some restaurant that was fairly light and also didn&amp;rsquo;t have strong smells. We were able to walk in on a Saturday at 5:30 PM with no reservations. We noticed the menus had both skewers and hot pot as options. I saw that many people ordered hot pot with cotton candy on top, and we contemplated briefly but decided not to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system &lt;a href="https://www.tock.com"&gt;Tock&lt;/a&gt;. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week. I quickly made the reservation, and then ultimately decided to keep both the bar tasting and the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting reservations. This post will be for the Atomix Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter menu. To read about the Atomix Bar tasting experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix. This one is about the bar. To read the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Refinery Rooftop Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/refinery-rooftop-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 14:43:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/refinery-rooftop-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On this very cloudy Sunday, we originally were planning to go to a &amp;ldquo;rooftop&amp;rdquo; outdoor film viewing on top of a hotel. Unfortunately, it got cloudy fast, and it rained throughout most of the day. The hosts cancelled the event, but we still desired to meet up with some friends. We ended up at Refinery Rooftop, which is just around the corner from the cancelled event. Fortunately, they were able to accept walk-ins around 4:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Silky Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:41:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/silky-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, I can grab food for myself after work, and I tend to look for noodles. My partner is not a fan at all of noodles, so I took this liberty to look for something that they would not enjoy. Despite the hot and humid weather in NYC, I rarely mind eating hot soups with noodles. Silky Kitchen has a location near where I live in Astoria, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try out its location out in Midtown near Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Black Iron Burger</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-iron-burger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 10:47:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/black-iron-burger/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/black-iron-burger%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rare occasion nowadays, I am able to sometimes grab dinner solo somewhere. I often debate about the cuisine, and I rarely want to eat something super posh right after work. I noticed a new location of a burger chain opened up. I often confuse the Black Iron Burger with the Blacktap Burger places but not this time. I walked in with no reservations at this 54th and 7th ave location and sat at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Per Se</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:37:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/per-se%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per Se is Thomas Keller&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed interpretation of the French Laundry restaurant in New York City and has &lt;strong&gt;3 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a replacement for the French Laundry, but it might be indicative of what to expect if we did ever go to Napa Valley to try it out. This restaurant is located in Columbus Circle at the top floor inside the mall. When we walked in, we were astounded by the huge ceiling and the vast feeling of space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Crab House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:14:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot recall the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve cracked open crab shells and eaten a huge chunk of crab meat. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a lot of seafood buffets, and they would always have a plethora of snow crab legs that you could eat for hours on end. We decided today to venture out to this all you can eat seafood buffet in the city. We were able to walk in with no reservations for 2 around 5:30 PM on a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Limani</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:19:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Normally we have Friday plans in the evening for a dinner restaurant after work. We didn&amp;rsquo;t plan for anything, so this restaurant was a decision at the whim. My partner always prefers either Latin based restaurants or Mediterranean because there they love hummus. This restaurant was on 51st right next to Rockafeller, so it was easy to access even on a rainy day. When we arrived at 6 PM on a Friday night, we were able to walk in without reservations as the restaurant was pretty empty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Grande Boucherie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-grande-boucherie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 18:02:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-grande-boucherie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/la-grande-boucherie%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/boucherie/"&gt;Boucherie&lt;/a&gt; before on 6th Ave near the West Village. We expected the food here to be similar but not the same as that location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first visit, I was craving for prime rib, and disappointingly, all the other places in the city were pretty expensive at $70 and up. For subsequent visits, it was decided out of convenience because the food was pretty consistent, and they have a decent pre-theater menu for the value.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Valerie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:28:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s yet another day of the year to spend more money on your partner! Valerie is a restaurant located in Midtown about 3 streets up from Bryant Park. My partner was craving crab cakes and aside from ordering from &lt;a href="https://jimmysfamousseafood.com"&gt;Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Famous Seafood&lt;/a&gt;, I was having a lot of trouble finding &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. They gave me a list, and I noticed that there was crab cake on this menu. I had no idea what to expect on an early Saturday evening when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quality Italian</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 19:31:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were around the Bloomingdales area running some errands back and forth around the Midtown East area and decided to take the risk of looking for a restaurant without making reservations since we normally eat dinner fairly early. This Quality Italian seems to be from the same owners of Quality Meats and Quality Bistro which are on my list. Quality Italian is a modern take on the Italian American steakhouse tradition, and the prices are probably on the mid to high range.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Soba Noodle Azuma</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/soba-noodle-azuma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 11:44:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/soba-noodle-azuma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been deprived of noodles in the city for a number of months now. Sure, there are sometimes where I get some Taiwanese noodles, but I also love soba noodles too. I was around the Columbus Circle area, and I was scouring for some alternative ramen places. This one peaked my interest because their specialty was not ramen but soba also known as buckwheat noodles. Buckwheat noodles are supposed to be pretty healthy for you, and on a summer NYC day like today, it seems like a win when opting for cold buckwheat noodles with a cold dip.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Palm Court</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tea-rooms/the-palm-court/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 23:46:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tea-rooms/the-palm-court/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have always heard of tea rooms, but I never thought much of it. We had heard from friends that they had gone to the Plaza Hotel, across the street from Central Park and had a pleasant experience eating sandwiches and drinking tea. I had looked at reservations before COVID, and it was usually pretty difficult to secure reservations. I did a quick glance and made reservations easily since the city is still slowly, albeit surely, opening up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Estiatorio Milos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:35:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner saw on their social media that some of their people had raved about this place for lunch. I took a look at the dinner menu here, and it seemed unjustly expensive for what it was. Usually a good indicator of prices starts with oysters. If a restaurant charges $4 for east coast oysters (average price should be around $3), you would expect the restaurant to have higher than usual menu prices. It turns out that the lunch menu prices were way more grounded, and it was a 3 course prix fixe on weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Bernardin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Le Bernardin is a &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City that primarily deals with seafood. The head chef is Eric Ripert, who is very well known in the higher end spectrum of the culinary world. We actually saw him on the floor with a mask on talking to some of the wait staff. This particular occasion was for a birthday celebration. Our reservation was at 5 PM, and it had to be reserved a month in advance. The spinning doors don&amp;rsquo;t actually open till 5 PM sharp, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a benefit to arrive before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keens Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 20:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For this memorial weekend, we wanted to go somewhere out of town, but we had to cancel plans including non refundable bus passes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching the Cooking Channel as my background noise, and they had an episode of steak. My partner hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Keen&amp;rsquo;s, and I thought this would be a great time to introduce them to it. I had been here back in 2018 for the first time, and it had a very delicious, if not the best, prime rib. Dinner reservations were difficult to make, so we opted for a lunch reservation instead which was quite easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Izakaya Toribar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:44:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/izakaya-toribar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people say Manhattan has practically endless restaurants, it&amp;rsquo;s quite true. There&amp;rsquo;s not enough time, money, and health to try all the different restaurants out there. For this visit into the city, we decided to go after yakitori since that was fairly close around the area we were at. We have had previously been to Torishin, a former Michelin 1-star, so I wanted to show my partner different yakitori places that were less upscaled. This one looked like a good candidate. This restaurant, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the outdoors setup, would&amp;rsquo;ve been a little difficult to spot because it&amp;rsquo;s in the basement of a building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spanish Diner</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/spanish-diner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:40:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/spanish-diner/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were visiting the Edge, which is a touristy spot where you can see the NYC area from 100 floors above, and in this COVID environment, it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to find some decent outdoor restaurants. We had passed by this place, which is a Jose Andres restaurant, and it seemed interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s a quasi-indoor place in that you&amp;rsquo;re eating in the building, but the area feels like you&amp;rsquo;re in a garage. The garage doors open facing outside, and there are plenty of fans to circulate air. We saw that they spaced out all the tables distantly from each other, so it seemed fine to sit down and eat. This is the Spanish Diner at Mercado Little Spain in the Hudson Yards block.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Torishin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 14:29:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torishin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this special outing, Yakitori Torishin has been on my list ever since I moved to New York City. I finally had a chance to try this for the girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/torishin%2F1_restaurant.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted the regular yakitori experience as opposed to the select counter experience. The reason is that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine the value from yakitori at literally double the cost of a regular omakase. They brought us into the back room, and we were still seated in front of the chefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Buena Vista</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 11:58:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/latin/buena-vista/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend was in town around the Hudson Yards area, and we wanted to look for something around the area. The menu here looked pretty decent, and it was on my bookmarks for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/buena-vista%2F1_bread.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;bread&lt;/strong&gt; came with some type of tomato olive oil medley. It reminded me of bruschetta toppings but more akin to diced tomatoes out of a jar. The sauce itself was alright.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wolf</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/wolf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 17:37:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/wolf/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re around the Rockafeller area and are looking for pretty decent Italian food at a not overly expensive price, this restaurant might be a good candidate. It is located on the 2nd floor of the Nordstrom NYC flagship store near the watches section. We walked in without reservations around 5:30 PM, and we were seated at the bar fairly quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/wolf%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Nordstrom doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the drinks menu online, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping my memory serves me well. The left is a &lt;strong&gt;mai thai&lt;/strong&gt;, and the right is a &lt;strong&gt;mezcal cocktail&lt;/strong&gt;. The mai thai was doused with passion fruit liqueur which is why I got it in the first place. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too strong, and everything tasted very tropically and subtle. The mezcal cocktail had a slight smokey flavor to it. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what else was in this though, but it definitely was sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Red Peony Chinese Cuisine</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-peony-chinese-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:45:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/red-peony-chinese-cuisine/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around Central Park near the southern side, and this was on my list of restaurants to try. This new-ish Chinese (Shanghainese) restaurant is located where Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai used to be in Midtown. It&amp;rsquo;s not too far from the Apple flagship store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/red-peony-chinese-cuisine%2F1_pea_sprouts.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;stir fry snow pea leaf&lt;/strong&gt; was mighty tasty. You can taste the subtleness of that wine, and the vegetable itself was tender and delicious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Elgin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 16:12:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near Rockafeller and were craving some bar like food. Not too far around the corner is this new-ish bar. Walking in, the interior is very open and seems pretty nice. There are a lot of tables that you can stand or sit on a high stool for drinks. You can tell it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty social atmosphere. But let&amp;rsquo;s get to the food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-elgin%2F1_pepperoni.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;strong&gt;Detroit pepperoni pan pizza&lt;/strong&gt;. The thickness of this was rather thin, almost New York like. Flavor wise, it was pretty salty but pretty decent. I wish they were more liberal with the pepperoni, and I am not sure I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the thinness of this. I think my mark for great Detroit pan style pizza is Emmy Squared, and this one kind of misses its mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Parker and Quinn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/parker-and-quinn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 22:45:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/parker-and-quinn/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were just around the block looking to meet a friend for a drink and some bar food at a nearby restaurant. Turns out that restaurant was booked due to a football game, so we had to hunt for another one. This restaurant for whatever reason was dead quiet but opened at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/parker-and-quinn%2F1_cured_long_island_duck_breast.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;cured Long Island duck breast&lt;/strong&gt; came with pomegranate molasses, collard greens, and kabocha squash pure. The duck breast was super tender and crispy. My only gripe was that it was very salty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nonono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/nonono/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nonono%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonono is a restaurant from the people behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/her-name-is-han/"&gt;Her Name is Han&lt;/a&gt;. This is located just a few blocks from Korea town. They are part of the &lt;a href="https://www.handhospitality.com/"&gt;Hand Hospitality&lt;/a&gt; network, which also includes &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atoboy/"&gt;Atoboy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cho-dang-gol/"&gt;Cho Dang Gol&lt;/a&gt;, and many more. The restaurant offers Japanese grill cuisine with a twist. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the restaurant several times, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a decent value and choice for any small gatherings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambiance feels like a normal Japanese restaurant where there was a lot of activity. The tables are relatively close to each other, so it can get a little tight. However, it was fine talking to your party, so the sound acoustics were good. They have both a floor table area and a second floor area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Wayfarer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-wayfarer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 15:15:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-wayfarer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stumbled onto this while trying to go to Bobby Vans steak. That place was closed unfortunately. The service here was pretty subpar by New York City standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-wayfarer%2F2_filet_mignon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;filet mignon&lt;/strong&gt; was ordered medium rare, but in my opinion it came out medium. The temperature on the steak as a whole came out cold as if it was sitting there for a tad bit too long. The blue cheese sauce was really salty, but perhaps it was there to hide the lack of taste on the steak.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yoon Haeundae Galbi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/yoon-haeundae-galbi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 22:08:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/yoon-haeundae-galbi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yoon-haeundae-galbi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember visiting Yoon Haeundae Galbi a while back when they first opened. Galbi is basically beef short ribs, and normally in the U.S., these short ribs are rather small. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any place in NYC that uses a large rib similar to the ones I had in Suwon, South Korea. When they take the meat off the rib, they also cook the tendons very thoroughly on the grill and it becomes crispy and edible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to this restaurant enough times such that I always end up recommending it as a positive alternative to other KBBQ spots.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Berimbau Do Brasil</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 17:28:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/brazilian/berimbau-do-brasil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/berimbau-do-brasil%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berimbau do Brasil is a fairly well known West Village Brazilian restaurant. According to my first and last notes, I had tried the feijoada and the picanha, and both were excellent. My partner was craving a lot of this food recently, so we decided to try the new Midtown location of this restaurant. The menu has changed decently, but we were interested to see if the flavors were still consistent to their West Village location.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ippudo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ippudo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ippudo%2F0_napkin.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had visited Ippudo twice before this time throughout my whole life, once in London and once in the East Village. This original post just had a comment of &amp;ldquo;Overrated and pricey. I&amp;rsquo;d skip here any day of the week. Daikokuya in LA is way better&amp;rdquo;. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pics of my dinner nearly 4 years ago, I thought about revisiting this Midtown location to try to remember why I was underwhelmed. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I now remember why, and it makes perfect sense why I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for it before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiran</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:18:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiran/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an updated review for the Midtown / Times Square (Theater District) location for Ichiran. I had been to the original Bushwick location years ago, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take pictures nor remembered much about it. The only thing I wrote down was &lt;code&gt;it was a much better version of Shinsengumi&lt;/code&gt;. Shinsengumi was a popular Torrance (California) restaurant that served hakata style ramen. They also allowed you to select your flavor profiles, and it was far less busy than Ichiran.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fine and Rare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been here a few times already, so this is now a proper post for it. This is a Jazzy restaurant that you can dine-in without paying a cover which is nice. The jazz itself is pretty fun, although predictable if you don&amp;rsquo;t listen to a special guest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fine-and-rare%2F1_blackberry_gimlet.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;strong&gt;blackberry gimlet&lt;/strong&gt; which has reyka vodka, fresh blackberries, and fresh lime. It was pretty good, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tsurutontan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:29:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsurutontan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Tsurutontan a few times already in various locations including Union Square and Midtown next to Rockafeller Center. When this Japan udon chain first opened in Manhattan a few years ago, there was a massive line because it was the first international location in the USA. The food was outstanding back then, and now it&amp;rsquo;s gone down a little in quality but still pretty good. This restaurant is known for having mammoth sized udon bowls which will most definitely satiate your appetite. They also have a variety of other Japanese sushi-esque dishes as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Relais De Venise L'entrecote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:08:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-relais-de-venise-lentrecote/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This review is for the Midtown East location of Le Relais De Venise L&amp;rsquo;entrecote. The previous review I had was for the &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/le-relais-de-venise-l-entrecote-new-york-3"&gt;closed SOHO location&lt;/a&gt;, which I was complaining that they charged $5.50 for tap water back in 2018. Fast forward about 3 years later post pandemic, how does this location fare compared to the previous one? I will say much better. Note that this location did not appear to charge for tap water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:29:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/nan-xiang-xiao-long-bao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nan Xiang Xiao Long Bao is one of those XLB restaurants that is not often brought up in the XLB fights because it&amp;rsquo;s not that accessible. The original location is in Flushing, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit far from Manhattan. Many people do end up going to Joe&amp;rsquo;s Shanghai to get their fix, but fortunately now a Manhattan location of this restaurant has opened in Koreatown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had originally gone to the Flushing location and said the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>