<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Disney on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/disney/</link><description>Recent content in Disney on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/disney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lamplight Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/lamplight-lounge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:36:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/lamplight-lounge/</guid><description>Lamplight Lounge was one of the few in-park Disney restaurants that we wanted to try because we heard some decent things about. I was able to nab a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 7:00 PM on a Friday night. The food is similar to a gastropub, and in the winter if you get a late enough reservation, you can actually watch the water show from your counter without cramming onto the bridge or other busy viewpoints.</description></item><item><title>Carthay Circle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:04:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</guid><description>Carthay Circle is located fairly close to the front of California Adventure. You do need an admission to the park in order to access this restaurant which is basically in the square at the end of the main road from the entrance. This was actually our second time visiting. I remember the first time being fairly underwhelming, so I felt it was wasteful to even spend the time to document it.</description></item><item><title>Napa Rose</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:43:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</guid><description>Napa Rose is located in Disney&amp;rsquo;s Grand California Adventure hotel and is known for its award-winning wine list and exemplary service. The food has a lot of inspirations from California&amp;rsquo;s fresh, farm-to-table qualities. This is arguably Disneyland&amp;rsquo;s premier restaurant that many, including some of my local family and friends, visit just for the food. I wanted to try this out to see how it compared to New York City.</description></item></channel></rss>