<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lax on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/lax/</link><description>Recent content in lax on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:38:49 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/locale/lax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kogane</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:38:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/kogane/</guid><description>We were definitely in for a treat in our visit to Los Angeles. My cousin raved about this place, and we were finally able to join for a lunch meal. They made a reservation for 4 around lunch time on Christmas eve, and it was fairly busy. For $125, you get a curated selection of omakase sushi that had a lot of interesting fishes that you would not typically have in New York City.</description></item><item><title>Lamplight Lounge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/lamplight-lounge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:36:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/lamplight-lounge/</guid><description>Lamplight Lounge was one of the few in-park Disney restaurants that we wanted to try because we heard some decent things about. I was able to nab a reservation pretty easily for 2 for 7:00 PM on a Friday night. The food is similar to a gastropub, and in the winter if you get a late enough reservation, you can actually watch the water show from your counter without cramming onto the bridge or other busy viewpoints.</description></item><item><title>Carthay Circle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:04:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/carthay-circle/</guid><description>Carthay Circle is located fairly close to the front of California Adventure. You do need an admission to the park in order to access this restaurant which is basically in the square at the end of the main road from the entrance. This was actually our second time visiting. I remember the first time being fairly underwhelming, so I felt it was wasteful to even spend the time to document it.</description></item><item><title>Xécora</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/xecora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 23:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/xecora/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt Los Angeles has better Mexican food, and I was offered a choice of eating hot pot or going for Mexican food. The hot pot choice would&amp;rsquo;ve been a place that we have a chain of here in NYC, and since we don&amp;rsquo;t know when we&amp;rsquo;ll be back in LA, I thought the answer was pretty easy. We decided on the Mexican joint because this is a local favorite for my cousin.</description></item><item><title>Yang's Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yangs-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 11:50:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yangs-kitchen/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve finally arrived in Los Angeles to kick it with family before heading up to Mammoth for a wedding. This restaurant was suggested because it has modern Taiwanese American tastes to it that is seemingly becoming a trend in the Alhambra areas. Unlike NYC, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt LA had better Asian food in the low/mid price ranges, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how it tastes. We were able to wait list on Yelp for about 5 minutes around 10:15 AM.</description></item><item><title>Shiro</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/shiro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:43:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/shiro/</guid><description>Summary This restaurant is out in the Pasadena area and is suppose to be pretty decent. After going here, I am convinced that many people just have bad taste in food.
The clams were decent. Not great, but not bad. I can&amp;rsquo;t really describe this because it tastes exactly how it looks. If you think good, then it&amp;rsquo;s good. And if you think bad, then yeah it probably tasted bad.</description></item><item><title>Mario's Peruvian &amp; Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:43:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/marios-peruvian-and-seafood/</guid><description>Summary If you are ever looking quality Peruvian anywhere, this is the place to be.
The ceviche was by far one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had. The fish was very fresh, and it was plentiful.
The lomo saltado here has always been my favorite so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve always used this place as a benchmark for other Peruvian places that serve lomo saltado. The meat is really tender, and for the price/serving ratio, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best out there.</description></item><item><title>Napa Rose</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:43:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/napa-rose/</guid><description>Napa Rose is located in Disney&amp;rsquo;s Grand California Adventure hotel and is known for its award-winning wine list and exemplary service. The food has a lot of inspirations from California&amp;rsquo;s fresh, farm-to-table qualities. This is arguably Disneyland&amp;rsquo;s premier restaurant that many, including some of my local family and friends, visit just for the food. I wanted to try this out to see how it compared to New York City.</description></item><item><title>Bistro Na's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bistro-nas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 23:26:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/bistro-nas/</guid><description>Summary Without getting too much into the history of the origins of this restaurant, the food here generally was just OK for me.
The crispy shrimp is what everyone wants to get. The shell is super crispy, crunchy, and delightfully edible. It&amp;rsquo;s comparable to the Cantonese style salted pepper shrimp with shell. However, this also has a tangy sauce on the outside of it. For me, it was a little TOO tangy, but some people at my table love it.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Truffles)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 21:30:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-6/</guid><description>For this month, it was TRUFFLES. I&amp;rsquo;ve never eaten a full blown truffle set meal. At $250 a pop and 600 consecutive phone calls over a span of 2 hours, I was able to get this reservation. Coupled with wine pairing, the meal was superbly awesome.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. This has 1 Michelin Star. I remember that after this dinner, I was getting tired of blogging all my Maude meals.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Pear)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 21:14:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-5/</guid><description>This is my 5th visit to Maude in 6 months. I guess I have the pleasure of doing this because I don&amp;rsquo;t have many financial responsibilities. This month&amp;rsquo;s tasting features pears, and again it did not disappoint me. I love pears, and I was curious in seeing how the chef uses it in his dishes.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. This has 1 Michelin Star.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Tomatoes)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 16:29:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-4/</guid><description>This is the month for tomatoes. I generally love tomatoes. They can come in so many different sizes and textures, such that it makes it very tasty. I will say that the meal for me did not disappoint.
We ended up getting the wine pairing which was about $70 extra. According to my buddy, the wine pairing was excellent throughout the meal and complemented the foods very well. I&amp;rsquo;ll just take their word for it.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Corn)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:00:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-3/</guid><description>The feature for Maude this month is corn, and it was way more awesome compared to last month. I like corn a lot, so I went in with some expectations, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed.
It really sucks to get reservations here. To get this particular reservation I called about 100 times in a given hour. If you look on my cell phone bill, you will see at least 60 5-second calls to them coupled with 40 some calls from a desk phone.</description></item><item><title>Yamakase #2</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:06:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-2/</guid><description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning to go to this. I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t. However due to some ridiculous circumstances, I was asked to go, and I had to go. It&amp;rsquo;s been barely 2 months, and I went back to my favorite LA restaurant. One would expect and hope for the same experience considering how recent their first trip here was. So really, how was it?
It was awesome. For comparison, you can also read my 2 month old review.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Berries)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 20:45:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-2/</guid><description>This could very well be my last post for food for a few weeks. Doing a special restaurant each week is getting rather grueling right now. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to soften the blow, so I&amp;rsquo;ll go to Maude each month for the remainder of the year.
This is #26 of 52 (or 26?) of my 2014 LA food expedition.
For this month, the special ingredient is berries. Like my rhubarb meal that I went to 2 months ago, I was expecting this to be similar in that every dish would have strong presence and usage of some berry.</description></item><item><title>Republique</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/republique/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 15:41:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/republique/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting very full. We&amp;rsquo;re now on #25, and my ridiculous challenge is starting to take its toll. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get a little fatter and a little less motivated. It&amp;rsquo;s getting harder to find restaurants, get people to go, and to make the trip. Alas, at least I made it to this point.
This is #25 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.
Did I mention I really don&amp;rsquo;t think I can make it to 52?</description></item><item><title>Yamakase</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 15:11:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/yamakase-1/</guid><description>This is a hole-in-the-wall place that is a real hidden gem in the Palms neighborhood of LA. It&amp;rsquo;s Japanese cuisine served kaiseki style. There are only 10 seats per night as the meal lasts just about 5 hours. There is no sign on the front. There is simply the address. We got there at 6:50 PM, but the door was locked. It actually does not open till 7 PM on the dot.</description></item><item><title>Smoke.Oil.Salt</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/smoke-oil-salt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 14:58:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/smoke-oil-salt/</guid><description>Smoke.Oil.Salt is another one of those many tapas shareable places that has been popping up all over Los Angeles. Unlike the other restaurants I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in the past few months, this is Spanish style featuring some traditional spanish dishes. It was surprisingly good.
This is #23 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. This restaurant unfortunately is now closed.</description></item><item><title>Phorage</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/phorage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:50:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/phorage/</guid><description>I have a few &amp;ldquo;safety&amp;rdquo; cards for those days I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like making a reservation or finding a place to get fat at. I decided to use one of those safety cards tonight at a place called Phorage. This restaurant replaced Roy Choi&amp;rsquo;s Chego location in Palms and features Vietnamese food sourced with high-quality locally grown produce.
This is #22 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.</description></item><item><title>Tsujita Artisan Noodle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-artisan-noodle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 20:22:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-artisan-noodle/</guid><description>So a few weeks ago, I went to Tsujita for dinner. I wanted to come back for lunch to try the tsukemen style ramen, which is what it&amp;rsquo;s most known for. Across the street nearby is its sister store, Tsujita Annex which serves ramen the entire day. This one for the time being only serves ramen for lunch, and it does have a slightly different menu. For a Sunday morning at 11 AM, there were no lines or wait.</description></item><item><title>Pine and Crane</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/pine-and-crane/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 14:37:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/pine-and-crane/</guid><description>Pine &amp;amp; Crane hasn&amp;rsquo;t been around for very long and is located in the Silver Lake area on Sunset where a plethora of restaurants sits. It&amp;rsquo;s generally difficult to find decent Chinese restaurants, let alone Taiwanese, outside of the San Gabriel Valley. So I thought I would trek here to see what the hype is about.
This is #21 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition. I&amp;rsquo;m almost half way there.</description></item><item><title>Tsujita Sushi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 20:37:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/tsujita-sushi/</guid><description>Tsujita is known for their ramen, particularly at the location where the dinner menu is different than their lunch menu. I was curious to try it for dinner to see how it compares to other Japanese restaurants. Note that this is not the Annex location. The Annex location at the time of this writing is the only Tsujita location that serves ramen for dinner.
This is #20 of 52 of my 2014 LA food expedition.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and Rice</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/chicken-and-rice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 23:18:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/chicken-and-rice/</guid><description>This was going to be one of those weeks where it&amp;rsquo;s time to go street food. If you have ever been to New York, they have halal carts that people love to eat at after a night at the bars. This is LA&amp;rsquo;s tribute to that.
This is #19 of 52 of my LA food expedition.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.</description></item><item><title>Maude (Rhubarb)</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 20:45:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/maude-1/</guid><description>What was so interesting about Maude was how each month has a different ingredient theme. I like this approach. Not only can you choose what you want to eat, but it also is cool to not have to think about what to order since the entire menu is a tasting menu. This so far is probably my favorite upscale LA restaurant (possibly attributed to the star of this month &amp;hellip; rhubarb).</description></item><item><title>EMC Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/emc-seafood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 23:10:58 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/emc-seafood/</guid><description>The full name of this restaurant is actually EMC Seafood and Raw Bar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in Koreatown close to 6th St. and Normandie. It&amp;rsquo;s on many new LA food lists, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what the hype is all about (other than the $1 happy hour oysters 4-7 PM).
This is #17 of 52 on my 2014 LA food expedition.
Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.</description></item></channel></rss>