<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New American on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/new-american/</link><description>Recent content in New American on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/new-american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, Marta, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food.</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as Saga, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to Naro. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all.</description></item><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends.</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me.</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The team that created this restaurant also helped create Don Angie, Quality Eats, Quality Italian, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item><item><title>Hunt &amp; Fish Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:02:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</guid><description>My partner was able to secure another show lottery near Times Square. Because I work near here and the fact that they have been able to win so many lottery shows, we&amp;rsquo;re running out of choices for restaurants. We were walking along 44th, and we stumbled onto this restaurant. After looking at the menu and the ability to walk in without reservations, we decided to try out this restaurant, Hunt &amp;amp; Fish Club.</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.
The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room at the Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:04:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</guid><description>The Modern is a well known 2 star Michelin restaurant that has an appealing tasting menu. Its sibling restaurant, the Bar Room&amp;quot;, is located in the same area as the Modern restaurant, but literally is divided by tall gigantic glass panes. The Bar Room has a more casual feel, where there&amp;rsquo;s music pumping through the speakers, and it feels more bustling like the general NYC city culture. This half of the restaurant has been participating with the NYC restaurant &amp;ldquo;week&amp;rdquo; program for quite some time, and we decided to check it out.</description></item><item><title>Murray's Cheese Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:54:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been frequent shoppers at Murray&amp;rsquo;s Cheese for our normal night in eating cheese and charcuterie. This location in Long Island City also has a restaurant part of it. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few glances at the menu, and there were some individual things that caught my eye. Fortunately, it was a lazy Saturday, and it was raining. This would be the ideal night to try this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations at 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Zou Zou's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:02:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</guid><description>Located near the Vessel and Hudson Yards, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for quite some time. They simply love Mediterranean small plates and dips. We actually had to make a reservation a few weeks out to nab our reservation at 5 PM on a Sunday night. The restaurant lies in this little courtyard where it leads into one of the Peloton offices. When we arrived, we were able to check in a few minutes early.</description></item><item><title>The Mercer Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 13:31:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/</guid><description>We were in the SOHO area doing a quick errand run. Because it was so cold, we decided to eat near the Prince Street subway station. We ended up at The Mercer Kitchen because they had walk-in seating, and it seemed interesting. We were seated in an intimate table right next to the bottom floor&amp;rsquo;s receptionist. We learned later that this is one of Jean George&amp;rsquo;s restaurants, and it&amp;rsquo;s scheduled to close at end of month permanently.</description></item><item><title>The Reading Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:37:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</guid><description>The Reading Room is a restaurant that caught my eye on Yelp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New and Hot&amp;rdquo; list. The menu is fairly small, simple, but seemed like it could be a good one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for restaurants around my work area that I could potentially refer others for drinks or a not too expensive dinner. This restaurant is located in the back of The Gotham Hotel on 46th between Madison and Fifth Avenue.</description></item><item><title>Gatsby Landing</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:34:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</guid><description>Gatsby Landing has been on my list for quite some time. The menu is reasonably priced, and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly close to my office and close to the 42nd trains. I figured today would be the day to check it out, since my options are running a little thin since I was looking for a walk-in restaurant. We arrived here around 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, and we were able to walk in easily for a party of 2.</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 16:12:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</guid><description>We were in the Midtown area shopping yet again. The previous night we went to Serafina, which was pretty awful. Luckily we had more choices, and this restaurant was nearby. It caught my eye because it had a nice indoor patio area that was lit by natural light similarly to The Milling Room. The menu seemed reasonable as well as the price, so maybe there can be some value found here.</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes.</description></item><item><title>Contra</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:24:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</guid><description>It was my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and they had asked for my partner to make a reservation to a Michelin Star restaurant that was not overwhelmingly expensive (&amp;lt; $120 per person before wine). My partner started looking for more contemporary cuisines, and stumbled onto this which was a bit below the radar of restaurants. I remembered looking at the menu a while back, and nothing really struck me as a must-have &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to trying to prove myself wrong.</description></item><item><title>Au Cheval</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:44:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/</guid><description>Au Cheval is well known restaurant based out of Chicago. They specialize in elevated burgers and American dishes. When they opened a New York City location, there were crazy lines out the door. The bigger brother to this restaurant is &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo; which specializes in prime rib. Both the burger and prime rib sandwich at Au Cheval are also found at &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the patience to book a &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo; reservation and pay the crazy insane prices for steak, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try some of their offerings here.</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.</description></item><item><title>Valerie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:28:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</guid><description>Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s yet another day of the year to spend more money on your partner! Valerie is a restaurant located in Midtown about 3 streets up from Bryant Park. My partner was craving crab cakes and aside from ordering from Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Famous Seafood, I was having a lot of trouble finding something. They gave me a list, and I noticed that there was crab cake on this menu. I had no idea what to expect on an early Saturday evening when we arrived.</description></item><item><title>Penny Bridge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</guid><description>Near where we live, they semi-opened this restaurant on Jackson Blvd at the start of the pandemic only to shut it down pretty quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here several dozen times, and it was never really opened until the last 6 months. Reading online, it seemed they had to change their menu several times for adjustments for some reason, and the menu itself initially seemed basic and not overly attractive. It felt they were trying really hard to attract a brunch crowd, so we have not been enthusiastic about trying.</description></item><item><title>Jojo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 17:00:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</guid><description>This restaurant is very close to the Bloomingdales along Lexington in the Upper East side. Surprisingly it has been here for a while, but we seldom come to this neighborhood to grab food. It just so happens we were on an errand run, so my partner was able to grab an early reservation. This is one of the more price friendly restaurants of Jean Georges although it arguably is still on the pricy side.</description></item><item><title>The Harrow</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 21:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</guid><description>Nearby, we had gotten free tickets to the Intrepid museum which sat on the water along 46th. The museum closed at 5 PM sharp, and we picked this restaurant since it was not too far of a walk. This had been on my list for a few years already, but we&amp;rsquo;re rarely in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen restaurants is that the restaurant prices are not usually that expensive and the food is pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Atera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:09:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</guid><description>Atera is a two Michelin Star restaurant in New York City. We&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go to this restaurant pre-pandemic, and each time we make a reservation, it was always cancelled due to shifts in NYC rules around the pandemic. Fortunately, the city is coming alive, and the reservation stuck this time around. We celebrated our very special anniversary at 5 PM. The cool thing about this restaurant that attracted me was that it had a temperament pairing of non-alcoholic juices.</description></item></channel></rss>