<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New American on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/new-american/</link><description>Recent content in New American on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:02:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/new-american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One White Street</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/one-white-street/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:02:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/one-white-street/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/one-white-street%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One White Street is located in a 19th century townhouse, that was a downtown hangout for John Lennon and Yoko Ono. Much of their produce is source from Rigor Hill Farm, located in the Hudson Valley. They practice sustainability, and much of their menu revolves around showcasing these ingredients. Originally opened in 2021 by chef Austin Johnson, this restaurant has 1 Michelin Star, and reservations are very easy to come by. We booked a pair for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening just a few days in advanced.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blue Hill Cafeteria at Stone Barns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-cafeteria-at-stone-barns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 21:11:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-cafeteria-at-stone-barns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/blue-hill-cafeteria-at-stone-barns%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;re out in the Tarrytown area, just outside of NYC, we decided to also try out their lunch tray to see how it goes. A few nights ago, we went to a very fantastic, memorable tasting dinner at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/"&gt;Blue Hill&lt;/a&gt;. For this lunch, we were expecting the ingredients to be very crispy, fresh, and delicious to commemorate everything we learned about the Blue Hill farm experience. I made a reservation for 2 for 1:00 PM on a Sunday without issues a few weeks back. We arrived early, and they accommodated us without issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blue Hill at Stone Barns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 20:07:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/blue-hill-at-stone-barns%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Hill at Stone Barns has been on our hit list for over 4 years now. Every year, my partner attempted to book the reservation online, but they would always be unsuccessful. This year, I decided to take a shot at it, and I scored a June 19th, Thursday, reservation for 5 PM. This restaurant has 2 Michelin Stars, and it is located near Tarrytown in Westchester County. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to do a train ride up from the city and take an uber, but we opted to make a weekend trip out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bridges</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bridges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:41:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bridges/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bridges%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridges opened in the late fall last year, and is headed by chef Sam Lawrence who came from Estela, which is on our list to hit. Lately, this restaurant has been getting some notoriety for having good food and a good ambiance. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit difficult to get to since you have to walk a bit from the subway entrance. I was able to book a reservation for 2 for the bar about a few days in advance for 5:45 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rosevale Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/rosevale-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rosevale-kitchen%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was another Broadway showing that we had to attend. Our theater district restaurant pool is thinning a bit, so this one was somewhat difficult to locate. It reminds me of a Midtown staple type of restaurant that is very friendly to the theater crowd, and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get in. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening around 5 PM without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The View</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 18:39:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-view/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-view%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The View was New York City&amp;rsquo;s iconic revolving restaurant, bar, and lounge, and recently reopened after a 5-year hiatus. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the New York Marriott Marquis hotel, and it was recently taken over by the Union Square Hospitality Group (known for places like Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/"&gt;Manhatta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Modern&lt;/a&gt;. Reservations were fairly easy to get, and since I was craving for prime rib, I snagged one just to see how it was like. Previously when this was opened, it was a buffet with &lt;a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/the-view-restaurant-and-lounge-new-york"&gt;not-so-great rated food&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SAGA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 20:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/saga%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAGA is a Michelin 2-star restaurant run by the &lt;a href="https://www.kenthospitalitygroup.com/"&gt;Kent Hospitality Group&lt;/a&gt;. The late Chef James Kent received a lot of good reviews for his restaurants, and this one was on my list to try, especially after trying &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/"&gt;Crown Shy&lt;/a&gt;. This restaurant is located in the same landmark Art Deco tower as Crown Shy. Crown Shy is located at the first floor, whereas this one is located on the 63rd floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Five Acres</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/five-acres/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/five-acres%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one appeal that attracted me to try out Five Acres was that they offered a Chicago beef sandwich. For some reason, there are very few places that serve this sandwich that I know of. There used to be &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/sandwiches/hanks-juicy-beef/"&gt;Hank&amp;rsquo;s Juicy Beef&lt;/a&gt;, but that closed down. The other Chicago beef place that I know of is in deep Brooklyn. Since we were around this Midtown area, I figured now is the right time to give this a shot. We were able to walk into this restaurant at 4:30 PM on a Sunday without reservations. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the downstairs promenade of Rockafeller Plaza, where all the sit-down restaurants reside near the skating rink.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafe Carmellini</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:26:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/cafe-carmellini/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cafe-carmellini%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Thanksgiving, we decided to try Cafe Carmellini out because their menu seemed pretty decent and had offerings that were present on their normal menu. My partner is a fan of turkey, so I already know what they were going to get. We made a reservation for 12 PM on Thanksgiving with no issues at all. When we walked in, they had us sit at the bar as they were preparing for Thanksgiving service. This restaurant is located inside the &lt;a href="https://www.thefifthavenuehotel.com/"&gt;5th Avenue Hotel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Musket Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-musket-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Musket Room has been around for a while, and it is located close to the Broadway/Lafayette train in Manhattan. Chef Mary Attea is the head chef of this restaurant, and according to the Michelin Guide, the kitchen is predominantly women. We picked this restaurant to try for tonight primarily because the menu looked like a slightly different take on New American than what we were used to. I was easily able to book a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had previously been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Bar at The Modern&lt;/a&gt;, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options. The kitchen is the same, except if you book during lunch, you have access to the dinner tasting menu as well, i.e. the full experience. We made a reservation for 12:00 PM on a Saturday without much difficulties as long as you make the reservation when it opens up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Foxface Natural</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:01:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/foxface-natural/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/foxface-natural%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foxface Natural was on my list ever since it opened, and I was always curious about how eclectic their food was going to be because of the various game meats they offer. They are one of the few, if not only, restaurants to serve kangaroo tartare. I saw that they had a tasting menu, and that seemed like a good thing to pursue for a Friday evening. I was able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening about a week prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sixty-three-clinton%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it. I was honestly nervous about the experience, but usually I will just go with the chefs&amp;rsquo; visions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monkey Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:27:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monkey-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monkey-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monkey Bar is a restaurant from the same people that are behind &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/"&gt;Au Cheval&lt;/a&gt; and 4 Charles in NYC. The Monkey Bar has a rich history dating back to the 1930s, where it formerly served New York City&amp;rsquo;s upper social class. In 2022, it reopened under the ownership of the 4 Charles team, and they created a menu that was very similar to the aforementioned restaurants. I was craving for prime rib, so I wanted to give this a try since I am reluctant to snipe 4 Charles reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Manhatta</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:21:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/manhatta/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/manhatta%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a splurge due to this incurable money sucking disease of gourmand syndrome, we splurged for Manhatta. Manhatta is known for its gorgeous views at the 60th floor facing up-town. It is part of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Union Square Hospitality Group, which includes The Modern, Gramercy Tavern, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/pizza/marta/"&gt;Marta&lt;/a&gt;, etc. to name a few. Aside from the view that the restaurant offers, the last few years they have made an effort to improve the food. We were able to make a reservation for 2 for the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter without much issue for 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/crown-shy%2F0_outside_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as SAGA, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smith &amp; Mills</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:09:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/smith-and-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/smith-and-mills%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Smith &amp;amp; Mills location is in the small inner plaza where the Rockafeller rink is. It caught my attention because the Tribeca location apparently had received some high regard, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a shot to check out this location. Although the food options are small, some of it looked pretty tasty. This restaurant is fairly close to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/naro/"&gt;Naro&lt;/a&gt;. We had a reservation for 3 for 5 PM, and the place was not full at all. I thought this was to be a restaurant, but it seems like the atmosphere is definitely more of a bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clinton St Baking Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:45:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/breakfast/clinton-st-baking-co/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/clinton-st-baking-co%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinton Street Baking Company is a very popular and well known destination for breakfast for decades. Word of mouth has mentioned that their pancakes and breakfast items have been delightful to eat. My party woke up early to park in line before the restaurant opening at 9 AM on a Saturday morning. It was definitely a struggle for me and my partner to arrive here from where we live, considering how annoying the subway schedules are on weekends. Right when they open, we were about the 6th small party in line, so we were able to be seated pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/monterey%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me. We were able to make a reservation for 5 PM on a Friday night with no hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bad Roman</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 14:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/bad-roman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bad-roman%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad Roman is located in the Columbus Circle mall on the third floor. The &lt;a href="https://www.qualitybranded.com/about/the-team/"&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; that created this restaurant also helped create &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/"&gt;Quality Eats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/"&gt;Quality Italian&lt;/a&gt;, other &amp;ldquo;Quality Branded&amp;rdquo; restaurants, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/"&gt;Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and more. There was a lot of social media firepower with this restaurant because of how retro it looked in vibe and style. We were able to book a seating pretty easily for 2 at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ambiance--service"&gt;Ambiance &amp;amp; Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant is very bustling, with lots of noise and all types of clientele. You will find many on their date nights, and you will find big parties celebrating something as if they were celebrities. The noise level is pretty loud, and you are seated pretty close to other tables. The music is also on the louder side too, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t uncomfortably loud. At times it was hard to hear our server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-grill%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St. You can&amp;rsquo;t miss it because there&amp;rsquo;s a carpet laid out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hunt &amp; Fish Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:02:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hunt-and-fish-club%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner was able to secure another show lottery near Times Square. Because I work near here and the fact that they have been able to win so many lottery shows, we&amp;rsquo;re running out of choices for restaurants. We were walking along 44th, and we stumbled onto this restaurant. After looking at the menu and the ability to walk in without reservations, we decided to try out this restaurant, Hunt &amp;amp; Fish Club. We were able to walk in at around 5:30 PM on a Friday without reservations easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-river-cafe%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room at the Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:04:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-bar-room-at-the-modern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modern is a well known 2 star Michelin restaurant that has an appealing tasting menu. Its sibling restaurant, the Bar Room&amp;quot;, is located in the same area as the Modern restaurant, but literally is divided by tall gigantic glass panes. The Bar Room has a more casual feel, where there&amp;rsquo;s music pumping through the speakers, and it feels more bustling like the general NYC city culture. On the other side of the pane is the extravagant tasting menu, which we also visited. Go to the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/"&gt;Kitchen Table review&lt;/a&gt; for more of how that experience was like.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Murray's Cheese Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:54:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/murrays-cheese-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/murrays-cheese-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been frequent shoppers at Murray&amp;rsquo;s Cheese for our normal night in eating cheese and charcuterie. This location in Long Island City also has a restaurant part of it. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few glances at the menu, and there were some individual things that caught my eye. Fortunately, it was a lazy Saturday, and it was raining. This would be the ideal night to try this place out. We were able to walk in without reservations at 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zou Zou's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:02:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/zou-zous/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/zou-zous%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located near the Vessel and Hudson Yards, Zou Zou&amp;rsquo;s was on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for quite some time. They simply love Mediterranean small plates and dips. We actually had to make a reservation a few weeks out to nab our reservation at 5 PM on a Sunday night. The restaurant lies in this little courtyard where it leads into one of the Peloton offices. When we arrived, we were able to check in a few minutes early. The hosts asked us to wait at the bar, and when they were ready for dinner service, they will come get you and bring you to your table.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Mercer Kitchen</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 13:31:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-mercer-kitchen%2F0_store.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in the SOHO area doing a quick errand run. Because it was so cold, we decided to eat near the Prince Street subway station. We ended up at The Mercer Kitchen because they had walk-in seating, and it seemed interesting. We were seated in an intimate table right next to the bottom floor&amp;rsquo;s receptionist. We learned later that this is one of Jean George&amp;rsquo;s restaurants, and it&amp;rsquo;s scheduled to close at end of month permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Reading Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:37:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-reading-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-reading-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reading Room is a restaurant that caught my eye on Yelp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New and Hot&amp;rdquo; list. The menu is fairly small, simple, but seemed like it could be a good one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for restaurants around my work area that I could potentially refer others for drinks or a not too expensive dinner. This restaurant is located in the back of The Gotham Hotel on 46th between Madison and Fifth Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gatsby Landing</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:34:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gatsby-landing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gatsby-landing%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby Landing has been on my list for quite some time. The menu is reasonably priced, and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly close to my office and close to the 42nd trains. I figured today would be the day to check it out, since my options are running a little thin since I was looking for a walk-in restaurant. We arrived here around 5:30 PM on a Friday evening, and we were able to walk in easily for a party of 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Bar Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 16:12:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-bar-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in the Midtown area shopping yet again. The previous night we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/serafina/"&gt;Serafina&lt;/a&gt;, which was pretty awful. Luckily we had more choices, and this restaurant was nearby. It caught my eye because it had a nice indoor patio area that was lit by natural light similarly to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-milling-room/"&gt;The Milling Room&lt;/a&gt;. The menu seemed reasonable as well as the price, so maybe there can be some value found here. We were able to walk in without reservations on a Sunday at 5:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carla</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:49:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/carla/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla is a local neighborhood restaurant close to Long Island City and Queensboro Plaza. At first glance, the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu seems very basic, but sometimes I think this could be misleading. I had been periodically glancing at the menu, and I noticed it changing every so slightly on a monthly basis. Since we had a lazy Saturday, we decided to try this place out. The restaurant&amp;rsquo;s motto is all about good vibes. We walked in as a party of 2 around 4:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contra</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:24:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It was my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and they had asked for my partner to make a reservation to a Michelin Star restaurant that was not overwhelmingly expensive (&amp;lt; $120 per person before wine). My partner started looking for more contemporary cuisines, and stumbled onto this which was a bit below the radar of restaurants. I remembered looking at the menu a while back, and nothing really struck me as a must-have &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to trying to prove myself wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Au Cheval</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:44:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/burgers/au-cheval/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Au Cheval is well known restaurant based out of Chicago. They specialize in elevated burgers and American dishes. When they opened a New York City location, there were crazy lines out the door. The bigger brother to this restaurant is &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo; which specializes in prime rib. Both the burger and prime rib sandwich at Au Cheval are also found at &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the patience to book a &amp;ldquo;4 Charles&amp;rdquo; reservation and pay the crazy insane prices for steak, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try some of their offerings here. Because they charge $2.49 plus tax, per person, for a reservation on Resy. It&amp;rsquo;s pretentious, but that did allow us to secure a reservation easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Valerie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:28:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/valerie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s yet another day of the year to spend more money on your partner! Valerie is a restaurant located in Midtown about 3 streets up from Bryant Park. My partner was craving crab cakes and aside from ordering from &lt;a href="https://jimmysfamousseafood.com"&gt;Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Famous Seafood&lt;/a&gt;, I was having a lot of trouble finding &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. They gave me a list, and I noticed that there was crab cake on this menu. I had no idea what to expect on an early Saturday evening when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Penny Bridge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/penny-bridge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Near where we live, they semi-opened this restaurant on Jackson Blvd at the start of the pandemic only to shut it down pretty quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ve walked by here several dozen times, and it was never really opened until the last 6 months. Reading online, it seemed they had to change their menu several times for adjustments for some reason, and the menu itself initially seemed basic and not overly attractive. It felt they were trying really hard to attract a brunch crowd, so we have not been enthusiastic about trying. They sent coupons to neighboring apartment buildings to lure in. Finally, we decided today would be the day that we would give this a shot, and we were able to walk in without reservations at 6 PM on a Friday easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jojo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 17:00:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jojo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This restaurant is very close to the Bloomingdales along Lexington in the Upper East side. Surprisingly it has been here for a while, but we seldom come to this neighborhood to grab food. It just so happens we were on an errand run, so my partner was able to grab an early reservation. This is one of the more price friendly restaurants of Jean Georges although it arguably is still on the pricy side.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Harrow</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 21:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-harrow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearby, we had gotten free tickets to the Intrepid museum which sat on the water along 46th. The museum closed at 5 PM sharp, and we picked this restaurant since it was not too far of a walk. This had been on my list for a few years already, but we&amp;rsquo;re rarely in the Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen area. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen restaurants is that the restaurant prices are not usually that expensive and the food is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:09:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Atera is a &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City. We&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go to this restaurant pre-pandemic, and each time we make a reservation, it was always cancelled due to shifts in NYC rules around the pandemic. Fortunately, the city is coming alive, and the reservation stuck this time around. We celebrated our very special anniversary at 5 PM. The cool thing about this restaurant that attracted me was that it had a temperament pairing of non-alcoholic juices. Although I would have liked to order the wine pairing, I always get full and drunk too fast with alcohol such that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the experience enjoyable. The restaurant is located on Worth Street, and it&amp;rsquo;s inside a building that looked very discreet on the outside. When you enter the building, the restaurant doors are directly on the left next to the elevators.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Milling Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-milling-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 10:33:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-milling-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We somehow won tickets to Shakespear in the Park, and we were debating whether we would scour for a restaurant in the west or east side. I was browsing on Yelp, and I saw this was very close to the Delacorte Theater. The interior pictures looked pretty amazing, and the food seemed pretty good although somewhat typical American. We ended up showing up promptly at opening and were seated right away without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Westlight</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 16:29:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/westlight/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westlight sits on the 22nd floor of the William Vale hotel in North Williamsburg. When you enter the lobby of the hotel, there is a line to the right that directs you to board the elevator. Upon arrival, the host will seat you on 1 of 2 floors. The 1st floor might be for reservations and has a waiter, whereas the 2nd floor might be for walk-ins. The 2nd floor has a fake grassy area with some patio tables/chairs, and you don&amp;rsquo;t get waiter service. You order your drinks and food at the bartender, and they will bring out the food to your table when it&amp;rsquo;s ready. Keep in mind that we&amp;rsquo;re still under COVID restrictions, so no indoor dining. The host brought us outside on the 1st floor and seat us in a 2-seater that overlooks west towards the Manhattan skylines. It&amp;rsquo;s simply breathtaking especially on this cooler day of the summer in the core afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M.Wells</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is across the street from Food Cellar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in a garage and used to serve a lot of steak dishes. The menu has changed into a more casual patio like experience (I am guessing just for the summer). When we arrived, there was no table service. Instead you have to go to the counter and place your order there. The menus are shown via QRCode. After you place your order, you carry the utensils, dishes, and drinks back to your table. The waiter will serve the dishes, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go pick up that. When you order, you (can) leave with them your credit card to open a tab. When you check out, they will tell you that gratuity is already included.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>American Brass</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 18:50:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/american-brass/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a restaurant from the same people that brought &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/maiella/"&gt;Maiella&lt;/a&gt;. Even though that restaurant was modern Italian, this one was more New American. It sits across the Gantry park near the Hunters Point library. Our first visit was on a Sunday, prior to the day that New York City had to shutdown dining in restaurants due to the coronavirus. Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t really out and about, the restaurant had many empty tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>While We Were Young</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/while-we-were-young/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 21:36:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/while-we-were-young/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally we don&amp;rsquo;t care about brunches, but this restaurant was surprisingly good and not too expensive. Located in West Village near the &amp;ldquo;Friends&amp;rdquo; place and some touristy spots, this is a very quaint and small shop. If I recall, it only has like at most 5 tables with counters spread throughout the place. This place is small, so set your expectations accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/while-we-were-young%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered a glass of &lt;strong&gt;orange juice&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;One Night Stand&lt;/strong&gt;. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything particular about the orange juice other than they put ice cubes in it which I thought was weird. However, the One Night Stand was actually pretty refreshing. It&amp;rsquo;s tequila, watermelon, chili agave, and lime. It has that little spicy kick to it, but not too much. The watermelon rounds it out very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Elgin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 16:12:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-elgin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were near Rockafeller and were craving some bar like food. Not too far around the corner is this new-ish bar. Walking in, the interior is very open and seems pretty nice. There are a lot of tables that you can stand or sit on a high stool for drinks. You can tell it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty social atmosphere. But let&amp;rsquo;s get to the food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-elgin%2F1_pepperoni.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;strong&gt;Detroit pepperoni pan pizza&lt;/strong&gt;. The thickness of this was rather thin, almost New York like. Flavor wise, it was pretty salty but pretty decent. I wish they were more liberal with the pepperoni, and I am not sure I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the thinness of this. I think my mark for great Detroit pan style pizza is Emmy Squared, and this one kind of misses its mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Parker and Quinn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/parker-and-quinn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 22:45:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/parker-and-quinn/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were just around the block looking to meet a friend for a drink and some bar food at a nearby restaurant. Turns out that restaurant was booked due to a football game, so we had to hunt for another one. This restaurant for whatever reason was dead quiet but opened at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/parker-and-quinn%2F1_cured_long_island_duck_breast.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;cured Long Island duck breast&lt;/strong&gt; came with pomegranate molasses, collard greens, and kabocha squash purée. The duck breast was super tender and crispy. My only gripe was that it was very salty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smoke Jazz and Supper Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/smoke-jazz-and-supper-club/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 18:25:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/smoke-jazz-and-supper-club/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came here on a date night to do the dinner and jazz thing. We purchased our tickets online, then head over. With the tickets, there&amp;rsquo;s a required minimum of 1 drink per person if you&amp;rsquo;re not having dinner, or if you are having dinner, there is a required 1 entree per person sans appetizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this night, it was the Harold Mabern Trio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/smoke-jazz-and-supper-club%2F1_cocktails.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;cocktails&lt;/strong&gt; were ok. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, so I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember exactly what these were. The red was definitely a spritz of some sort.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Death Ave</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:45:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a restaurant located close to the end of the Highline. It&amp;rsquo;s down on 10th ave at the corner. It&amp;rsquo;s actually next door to its bar. So if you want to visit this place, don&amp;rsquo;t open the first door on your left. Open the second door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/death-ave%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sour beer&lt;/strong&gt; on the top was quite good. It had some flavors of a Guinness but obviously with the sour in it. The &lt;strong&gt;sangria&lt;/strong&gt; cocktail at the bottom was alright. Not my choice, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Fulton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is one of Jean Georges&amp;rsquo; new seafood-centric restaurant situated right at the corner of the Pier near South Street Seaport. This area has a tiny Boston like mall where people can shop and eat at some decent restaurants. The iPic theater is also here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is largely going through some sort of construction. The restaurant is located at the edge of the pier and overlooks the water facing towards the Brooklyn Bridge. In fact, just about everywhere in the restaurant you can see the Brooklyn Bridge without much obstruction. If you do try to make a reservation, I definitely think the second floor seating is more beautiful than the first.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Narcissa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/narcissa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 13:30:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/narcissa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m introducing a new category for restaurants that have gardens. This one has an interesting one. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly that great, but it seems to be an attraction for others. This is tucked near or in the Standard Hotel, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember. In the summer, the indoor seats are mostly vacant, so definitely ask for a seat near the window if you decide to sit inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Huntress Whiskey N Wings</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 21:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vibe in this place was pretty cool. It reminded me of being in one of those Lord of the Rings tavern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings%2F1_poutine.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;poutine&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty salty, but it was a good match with the beers. I wish the cheese curds were a little warmer and more abundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-huntress-whiskey-n-wings%2F2_savage.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;savage&lt;/strong&gt; is actually regular hot wings. The hot wings tasted like they were fried first then doused in sauce after. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice texture combination, and it&amp;rsquo;s how I prefer my hot wings. The wings themselves didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a lot of flavor outside of the sauce though. There are some french fries that the wings sit on that soak up the sauce and oil.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Wayfarer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-wayfarer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 15:15:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-wayfarer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stumbled onto this while trying to go to Bobby Vans steak. That place was closed unfortunately. The service here was pretty subpar by New York City standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-wayfarer%2F2_filet_mignon.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;filet mignon&lt;/strong&gt; was ordered medium rare, but in my opinion it came out medium. The temperature on the steak as a whole came out cold as if it was sitting there for a tad bit too long. The blue cheese sauce was really salty, but perhaps it was there to hide the lack of taste on the steak.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jacobs Pickles</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jacobs-pickles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 21:08:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/jacobs-pickles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main site to the sister site Maison Pickle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food here is really good, filling, and not too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jacobs-pickles%2F1_pickles.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you have to get the pickles. For appetizers, we got &lt;strong&gt;4 pickles (spicy, green beans, green tomatoes, and regular)&lt;/strong&gt;. We also got a side of fried pickles. I liked them all to be honest, and would love to get the carrots next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ferris</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/ferris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 17:52:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/ferris/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered a slew of appetizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F1_drink_fir_trade.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drink fir trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_blood_sausage.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_bread_butter.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_chicken_liver_mousse.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_iberico_katsu_sando.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_octopus.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F2_uni_proscuitto.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blood sausage, bread, and chicken liver mousse was just OK. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much memorable about it. The iberico katsu sandwich was surprisingly very good, and I could probably eat a handful of these easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ferris%2F3_cote_de_boeuf.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main course, cote de boeuf, was pretty good. I actually did not care too much about the sauces, but the quality of the meat was pretty good and tender.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blanca</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:12:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blanca/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/blanca%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my first visit to Blanca back in September 2018, I was a solo diner and had just moved to New York City pretty recently. I wrote down, &amp;ldquo;Really good. Definitely get the drink pairing. Michelin 2 star. $300 per person including drinks.&amp;rdquo; The vibe and space was absolutely fantastic. I then met my partner, and the pandemic arrived. Blanca shutdown and just simply never reopened until a few weeks ago. Knowing how high in demand this restaurant was in the past, I decided to take my partner to this restaurant to re-live the experience again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Flatiron Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-flatiron-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:06:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-flatiron-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jazzy bluegrassy restaurant. Same people as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare"&gt;Fine &amp;amp; Rare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fine and Rare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:05:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/fine-and-rare/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been here a few times already, so this is now a proper post for it. This is a Jazzy restaurant that you can dine-in without paying a cover which is nice. The jazz itself is pretty fun, although predictable if you don&amp;rsquo;t listen to a special guest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fine-and-rare%2F1_blackberry_gimlet.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;strong&gt;blackberry gimlet&lt;/strong&gt; which has reyka vodka, fresh blackberries, and fresh lime. It was pretty good, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Marshal</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-marshal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:04:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-marshal/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Was surprisingly good. Good date place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gentleman Farmer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gentleman-farmer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:03:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gentleman-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good date spot, small intimate venue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hearth</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hearth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:01:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hearth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Was good but nothing particularly struck a note to me. Marc Forgione tasting menu is way better than here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Olmsted</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/olmsted/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 18:00:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/olmsted/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Was pretty good surprisingly, though the portion sizes were way too small. Ended up eating some rhubarb pie afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Maison Pickle</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/maison-pickle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:59:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/maison-pickle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;French Dip is really good here, espeically the au jus drippings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leuca</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/leuca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:56:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/leuca/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;New American centric. Cheap but not too expensive. In the Vale hotel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Minetta Tavern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:07:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/minetta-tavern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/minetta-tavern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the infamous Minetta Tavern. I had been here back in mid 2010s, and it was pretty good. Before I met my partner, I used to come here once every few months to just scarf their Black Label burger. The price for this was just barely over $20. Now in recent times post-pandemic, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit more difficult to walk in without reservations. We were able to sit at the bar on a Friday late-afternoon around 4:55 PM without reservations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 18:16:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marc-forgione%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;Marc Forgione&amp;rdquo;, this restaurant has moved from its prior Tribeca location to a different Tribeca location. Since then, they have lost their Michelin Star, but it is still a staple restaurant for those familiar with the history of this restaurant. It was quite easy to make reservations a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came here in 2012, I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Forgione is one of the Iron Chefs on Iron Chef America. This is his first restaurant, and at the time of this writing it has 1 Michelin Star. Like Michael Voltaggio, this restaurant is one of his babies, so he periodically is cooking in the kitchen to make sure everything comes out as he desires. Unfortunately he didn&amp;rsquo;t cook today, but I just want to preface this by saying this is definitely one of my favorite restaurants ever that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WD~50</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 17:59:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/wd-50%2F0_wylie.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first found out about WD~50 from my friend who wanted to try it out for the longest time. On research, I found out one of the Bravo&amp;rsquo;s Top Chef previous contestant owns this restaurant. His name is Wylie Dufresne. He is well known for pushing a movement towards molecular gastronomy, which is basically a different way to cook things. This 1 Michelin Star restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu is pretty sparse in choices in that you basically choose from 2 different types of tasting menus, the cheaper or the more expensive. Optionally, you could order 2 items off any of the tasting menus at the bar for $25. We of course opted for the expensive one considering we have no plans on coming back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Momofuku Ssam</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/momofuku-ssam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 17:47:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/momofuku-ssam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/momofuku-ssam%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my goals was to knock out some popular Momofuku establishments. SSAM was one of them. The SSAM Bar is on the San Pellegrino world&amp;rsquo;s 50 best restaurants list at the time of this writing. The service style is basically family style, so there are a lot of sharing plates. Portions are small for large groups probably, but decent sized for small groups 2-4. The decor has a very modern feel to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>