<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/seafood/</link><description>Recent content in Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 23:10:58 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/cuisine/seafood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EMC Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/emc-seafood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 23:10:58 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/emc-seafood/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/emc-seafood%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full name of this restaurant is actually EMC Seafood and Raw Bar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in Koreatown close to 6th St. and Normandie. It&amp;rsquo;s on many new LA food lists, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what the hype is all about (other than the $1 happy hour oysters 4-7 PM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is #17 of 52 on my 2014 LA food expedition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>L &amp; E Oyster Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/l-and-e-oyster-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 21:28:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/l-and-e-oyster-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/l-and-e-oyster-bar%2F0_logo.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been craving for seafood the last few weeks or months, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like driving to Whittier to go to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/portsmouth/"&gt;Portsmouth&lt;/a&gt;. I looked up Eater LA, and I found L&amp;amp;E Oyster Bar on their list of 2014 essential LA restaurants at #26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is restaurant #1 for my 2014 LA food expedition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for 2022 migration: this is an old post from my other defunct blog. I recall back then this being a super hot spot in greater Los Angeles area. Silver Lake is a bit of a drive going cross-town and has always had that hipster notoriety.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Portsmouth</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/portsmouth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 20:18:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/portsmouth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/portsmouth%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this place technically is not in LA, it&amp;rsquo;s within reasonable driving distance. Portsmouth is an oyster bar (with beer eventually) located close to downtown Whittier. The actual site is in a quiet location in suburbia, so it was odd to see the building. But with word of mouth, the internet, and Yelp/Eater-LA, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portsmouth had just been opened for roughly a week. There was a soft opening a few weeks back. I accidentally stumbled onto this site when I was craving for seafood and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to travel to Santa Monica. As some may know, the westside is just a pain to get around. The parking is annoying, and the prices are less than friendly. Eater LA posted an article about this little place, and I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be a nice small road trip for myself. I met up with Fox W, who is a well-known Foodspotter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Son of a Gun</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:39:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/lax/son-of-a-gun/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/son-of-a-gun%2F0_menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a special night where Top Chef Marcus Samuelsson creates a culinary experience with the dynamic duo of Son Of A Gun. The menu was nothing like their normal menu. Marcus Samuelsson greeted most, if not all, of the guests during my visit. You can tell he was very appreciative for us patrons to experience this. Not only did he prepare food for us, but he also presented a signed copy of his memoir book &amp;ldquo;Yes Chef&amp;rdquo;. I read the first chapter before I decided to write this. The book seems to document his journey through life and show how passionate he is with the culinary arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>