<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Epcot on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/epcot/</link><description>Recent content in Epcot on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/neighborhood/epcot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Space 220</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/space-220/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:28:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/space-220/</guid><description>Space 220 was such a difficult reservation to get. I was able to get reservations for it on the very last day that we were flying out for lunch. When we arrived, there already was a line for walk-ins. Fortunately, we had the 11:30 AM reservation with out flight being at 5:00 PM, so we were looking forward to this new experience. When you arrive at the bottom, you have to stand in line (under the sun) until they check you in.</description></item><item><title>La Hacienda De San Angel</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-hacienda-de-san-angel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 23:59:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-hacienda-de-san-angel/</guid><description>The finale for our Epcot night was this very last minute reservation for 5 at La Hacienda De San Angel. At this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve just barely recovered from being full, so I am ready to give this a try. Unlike the Mexican restaurant next to the Caballeros ride, this one was more like your typical restaurant without the smell of chlorine water or being overly dark. Per a recommendation and not normally eating Mexican food in NYC, this was something on my list to try.</description></item><item><title>Epcot Flower and Garden Festival 2022</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/flower-and-garden-festival-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:14:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/flower-and-garden-festival-2022/</guid><description>Just like 2021 at Epcot, they had this lovely Flower and Garden Festival. Unfortunately this time around, I was simply too full to eat around. I had enough room to maybe try a snack or two but that&amp;rsquo;s about it. I noticed that the indoor area between the British and Canadian pavilion was not open, so it felt like there were just a few less options.
Unlike 2021, it felt like there were significant more crowds as a whole everywhere.</description></item><item><title>La Creperie De Paris</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-creperie-de-paris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:20:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-creperie-de-paris/</guid><description>We entered Epcot around 10 AM on this Friday from the north end of the park, and we had to walk all the way down to the France pavilion to try and ride Remy. The unfortunate part when we got there was that the wait time had already exceeded 90 minutes. I checked my Disney World app, and low and behold, we could do lighting passes for $11 per person. That felt worthwhile to do and not bake under the sun.</description></item><item><title>Epcot Flower and Garden Festival 2021</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/flower-and-garden-festival-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 23:24:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/flower-and-garden-festival-2021/</guid><description>In 2021, it was by pure coincidence that the week we were going to Disney World happened to also have this International Flower and Garden festival. There are a myriad of flower and grass decorations of some of your favorite Disney characters displayed. It was our first time ever going to a destination with a lot of variety of little tastings scattered throughout. In different sections of the park, Disney has set up little booths that have different themed items, each ranging from $5 to $10.</description></item><item><title>Regal Eagle Smokehouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/regal-eagle-smokehouse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 23:04:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/regal-eagle-smokehouse/</guid><description>Summary For dinner, we stopped by the American pavilion. This BBQ restaurant only took orders via mobile. After you placed your mobile order, they will text you when it&amp;rsquo;s time to pick up your food. Outside there are a bunch of tables, but you can also sit indoors too. Like other COVID menus, the choices were not as abundant. People have shared menus that you can order 3 meats, but the mobile menu only had single meat combos.</description></item><item><title>Sommerfest</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/sommerfest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:33:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/sommerfest/</guid><description>Summary Located in the German pavilion at Epcot, this has a bunch of beer on draft and some German snacks. After looking at the original menu on Yelp, it looks like in the COVID temperament the menu is much smaller. When we went, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many options, but there was no line. Just mainly a bratwurst with paprika chips or a pretzel. Right outside, there was a fountain with social distanced tables and chairs, and I needed something to pair with my Würzburger Hofbräu pilsner from the Weinkeller shop.</description></item><item><title>La Cava Del Tequila</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-cava-del-tequila/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:18:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/la-cava-del-tequila/</guid><description>Summary This is located in the Mexican pavilion at Epcot. When you enter the pyramid, there&amp;rsquo;s a little store to the right next to the fountain. In this COVID environment, there are social distancing lines as you enter here. Unfortunately you can&amp;rsquo;t sit inside the bar, so you have to buy the drink and sit outside. I do not know if (or how much of) the drinks are pre-mixed, but it was served super fast.</description></item><item><title>Yorkshire County Fish Shop</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/yorkshire-county-fish-shop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:01:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/mco/yorkshire-county-fish-shop/</guid><description>Summary This shop is located in the British area of Epcot. After you enter the park, steer left, and it&amp;rsquo;s your very first shop on the right. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about this area is there are some tables and seats that overlook the center fountain of Epcot. On a nice cool day, it&amp;rsquo;s quite pleasant to snack on this and enjoy the scenery. Keep in mind, we went when the park had 35% attendance, so it was way more spacious and enjoyable.</description></item></channel></rss>