<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greek on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/greek/</link><description>Recent content in Greek on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 16:32:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/greek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avra Estiatorio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:32:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/avra-estiatorio%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avra Estiatorio was a restaurant that we wanted to check out for a while now. Because we were going to watch Gutenberg Musical at 8 PM, this fit perfectly for the opportunity. Avra has several locations spread throughout the United States: 3 in Manhattan, 1 in Miami, and 1 in Beverly Hills. It&amp;rsquo;s a rather posh Greek seafood restaurant, and it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to all the other upper end ones, such as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/"&gt;Limani&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/"&gt;Milos&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to walk in at around 6 PM without reservations, and we were seated at the upper floor. When we met the hostess, they asked if we were seeing a show, and we acknowledged that we were.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Estiatorio Milos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:35:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner saw on their social media that some of their people had raved about this place for lunch. I took a look at the dinner menu here, and it seemed unjustly expensive for what it was. Usually a good indicator of prices starts with oysters. If a restaurant charges $4 for east coast oysters (average price should be around $3), you would expect the restaurant to have higher than usual menu prices. It turns out that the lunch menu prices were way more grounded, and it was a 3 course prix fixe on weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nerai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:32:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, we were fortunate to book this restaurant in Midtown East at the very last minute. This was always on our list since outdoor dining was a thing as the pictures of its settings looked quite appealing. Most tables have their own electric heater that sat directly above the table, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too cold compared to other places. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, it was in the high 30s with some wind chills. We did dress warmer just in case though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Psari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:38:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what&amp;rsquo;s one of the great things about Astoria? It&amp;rsquo;s the excellent Greek seafood restaurants that are within walking distances of each other. We had been to Taverna Kyclades before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we&amp;rsquo;ve dined at their competitors. This was a restaurant that was within walking distance from our Food Bazaar trek on the way back home, so we thought to stop by and give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Souvlaki GR</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/souvlaki-gr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 22:48:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/souvlaki-gr/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re just shy of Central Park to the south and it&amp;rsquo;s in the middle of the day, this might be a good option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/souvlaki-gr%2F1_mixed_meat_salad.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bottom is the &lt;strong&gt;mixed grilled meat platter for two people&lt;/strong&gt; (psita tis oras poikilia). It&amp;rsquo;s a combination of lambchops, traditional Greek sauce, pork/beef skewers, and pita and tzatziki. All of this was pretty good. The lambchops were ordered medium rare, and it was tender and delicious. I like the char on this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Death Ave</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:45:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/death-ave/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a restaurant located close to the end of the Highline. It&amp;rsquo;s down on 10th ave at the corner. It&amp;rsquo;s actually next door to its bar. So if you want to visit this place, don&amp;rsquo;t open the first door on your left. Open the second door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/death-ave%2F1_drinks.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sour beer&lt;/strong&gt; on the top was quite good. It had some flavors of a Guinness but obviously with the sour in it. The &lt;strong&gt;sangria&lt;/strong&gt; cocktail at the bottom was alright. Not my choice, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taverna Kyclades</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:08:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We came here around 8:30 PM on a rather cold Saturday evening. Typically there is a long line outside, but today people were crowded and bundled up inside. I put my name down for 2. The wait was approximately 40-50 minutes. We had contemplated leaving when we heard the wait time, but we decided to power through and wait. It was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;em&gt;July 1, 2023&lt;/em&gt;, we visited this restaurant again, and it has moved from it&amp;rsquo;s previous location. For a table of 4, we just had to wait approximately 30 minutes on a Saturday around 7:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>