<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Steak on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/steak/</link><description>Recent content in Steak on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/steak/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monterey</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:43:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/monterey/</guid><description>This restaurant is a fairly close walk east of Rockafeller Center. I stumbled onto this restaurant as I was looking for something new and solo-friendly for a Saturday. It turns out that this restaurant has a Friday/Saturday prime rib prix-fixe menu, which has my attention. For $65 per person, you get 3 courses: a caesar salad, prime rib with french fries, and a choice of dessert. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a bad deal to me.</description></item><item><title>Vinyl Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 12:51:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/vinyl-steakhouse/</guid><description>Vinyl Steakhouse has been a steak place that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go for quite some time. The Flatiron area has been experiencing many new restaurant openings post pandemic, and this was one of them that was appealing. Similar to Turntable Chicken Jazz, this restaurant has a load of vinyls on display, and it plays music as requested. We were able to walk in on a Friday around 6:30 PM without reservations for 2.</description></item><item><title>The Grill</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:48:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/the-grill/</guid><description>The Grill was always something on my bucket list not only for a prime rib trolley, but also for Baked Alaska, my favorite dessert. Every place makes this different, so it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see different interpretations. In addition, this restaurant has always been difficult to get reservations timely, so we were able to book this a few weeks out for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening. The restaurant is located in the Seagram building, and the entrance is located off of 52nd St.</description></item><item><title>Hunt &amp; Fish Club</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:02:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/hunt-and-fish-club/</guid><description>My partner was able to secure another show lottery near Times Square. Because I work near here and the fact that they have been able to win so many lottery shows, we&amp;rsquo;re running out of choices for restaurants. We were walking along 44th, and we stumbled onto this restaurant. After looking at the menu and the ability to walk in without reservations, we decided to try out this restaurant, Hunt &amp;amp; Fish Club.</description></item><item><title>Charlie Palmer</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/charlie-palmer/</guid><description>We had yet another show to catch, so we decided to look around the Bryant Park area. I stumbled onto Charlie Palmer, and it had been on my list of steak places to try. What was nice about this place specifically is they offered a 2-course pre-theatre menu for $49 which included a starter and entree. If you wanted dessert, you would have to pay an additional $10. Lucky for us, we weren&amp;rsquo;t that hungry, so a 2-course meal sounded fine for us.</description></item><item><title>Gage and Tollner</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:28:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gage-and-tollner/</guid><description>Gage and Tollner has been on my list for quite a while now. I was casually browsing for restaurants with baked alaska, and this had shown up high on people&amp;rsquo;s list. Whenever I had tried to look at reservations, it was pretty booked. I was very lucky to have found an open reservation for 2 at 5 PM on a Sunday the night before. So how did it go?</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.</description></item><item><title>Skirt Steak</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/skirt-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/skirt-steak/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed simple menus of steak frites. We visited L&amp;rsquo;entrecote, and it was a pretty good restaurant for a similar value as this one. When I arrived at 5:20 PM and because this restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t take reservations for small parties, there was already a line out of the door. Fortunately the total wait time for us was about 15 minutes in line because we volunteered for bar seats if they were available.</description></item><item><title>Bacall's Family Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:28:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/bacalls-family-steakhouse/</guid><description>One of our traditions that will be coming back soon is eating out on Fridays after work. We&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the heart of midtown area and trying to walk into restaurants without reservations. We tried to go to one of the Cuban restaurants, but unfortunately they required a 40 minute wait. This restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far away, but they did have prime rib on the menu. When we arrived, it seems there was some show going on, but we were able to sit at a small table in the bar area.</description></item><item><title>Quality Italian</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 19:31:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/quality-italian/</guid><description>We were around the Bloomingdales area running some errands back and forth around the Midtown East area and decided to take the risk of looking for a restaurant without making reservations since we normally eat dinner fairly early. This Quality Italian seems to be from the same owners of Quality Meats and Quality Bistro which are on my list. Quality Italian is a modern take on the Italian American steakhouse tradition, and the prices are probably on the mid to high range.</description></item><item><title>Keens Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 20:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/keens/</guid><description>For this memorial weekend, we wanted to go somewhere out of town, but we had to cancel plans including non refundable bus passes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching the Cooking Channel as my background noise, and they had an episode of steak. My partner hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Keen&amp;rsquo;s, and I thought this would be a great time to introduce them to it. I had been here back in 2018 for the first time, and it had a very delicious, if not the best, prime rib.</description></item><item><title>M.Wells</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/mwells/</guid><description>Summary This place is across the street from Food Cellar. It&amp;rsquo;s nestled in a garage and used to serve a lot of steak dishes. The menu has changed into a more casual patio like experience (I am guessing just for the summer). When we arrived, there was no table service. Instead you have to go to the counter and place your order there. The menus are shown via QRCode. After you place your order, you carry the utensils, dishes, and drinks back to your table.</description></item><item><title>Empire Steak House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 14:10:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/empire-steak-house/</guid><description>Summary We were looking for a decent steak place that was walkable from where we were. The best steak house in my opinion in the city is Keen&amp;rsquo;s Steakhouse, so expectations were set pretty low. This venue is fairly nice. It&amp;rsquo;s close to Smith and Wollensky and located inside some hotel. This was one of the few steakhouses at this time that had hardly any people, so one can only think that this place wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that good.</description></item><item><title>Gallagher's Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gallaghers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:05:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/gallaghers/</guid><description>The cream of spinach tastes like Lawry&amp;rsquo;s. The horseradish cream was good. The prime rib not as good as Keen&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Delmonico</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/delmonico/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:04:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/delmonico/</guid><description>Got the Delmonico steak. I like the char on this, but the steak kindi of sucked because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t flavorful nor fatty. Cream of spinach was just OK.</description></item><item><title>Ikinari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/ikinari/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:02:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/ikinari/</guid><description>Got the rare strip. It was pretty good for $30 for 14 oz. Not a lot of fat on it. I think the price keeps getting cheaper because not a lot of people go to this.</description></item><item><title>Chuck and Blade</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/chuck-and-blade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:00:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/chuck-and-blade/</guid><description>New York strip was so so. Cream of spinach was not good. There were lots of tendons in the meat. The lava cake dessert was good though.</description></item><item><title>Quality Eats</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:59:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/quality-eats/</guid><description>Skirt steak was pretty good. Very affordable. Good date spot I think.</description></item><item><title>Strip House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/strip-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:57:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/strip-house/</guid><description>Steak was just OK. Service was slow as hell. Truffle cream of spinach was good.</description></item><item><title>American Cut</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/american-cut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:56:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/american-cut/</guid><description>Decent for the price. This is Marc Forgione&amp;rsquo;s steak house.</description></item><item><title>212 Steakhouse</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/212-steakhouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:54:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/212-steakhouse/</guid><description>Ok, this place is the only legit place in NYC that has real kobe certified beef from Japan. It was delicious and cheap&amp;hellip; with the groupon.</description></item><item><title>Old Homestead</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:50:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/old-homestead/</guid><description>Summary For the first visit and not pictured, we got the aged rib eye for 2. It was surprisingly good and flavorful.
The applewood smoked slab of bacon was thick and tasty. For 2 people, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to just get 1.
The prime rib on the bone was super thick and good. Like Keen&amp;rsquo;s, this is a monster and can probably be shared by 2 people. I would say the thickness of this was probably close to 1.</description></item><item><title>Peter Luger</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/peter-luger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 21:52:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/peter-luger/</guid><description>Peter Luger&amp;rsquo;s steak house has been around for a very long time. At one point, it even had a Michelin Star. Many tourists always recommend eating here and rave about it. The locals though on the other hand are rather indifferent. People have told me that their steaks suck and that their best dishes are their appetizers. Others have told me it&amp;rsquo;s the best steak they ever had. Does it really live up to the hype?</description></item></channel></rss>