<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michelin Star on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-star/</link><description>Recent content in Michelin Star on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:14:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/michelin-star/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yingtao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/yingtao/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:14:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/yingtao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/yingtao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a pre-Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day dinner, this was one of the few restaurants where it was incredibly easy to make a reservation just a few days in advance. Ying Tao was on my list for a while, and the menu always looked mildly interesting to me. I remember when it first opened, it was one of the few individual Chinese &amp;ldquo;tasting&amp;rdquo; in Manhattan that was prepared in a gourmand style way. I was easily able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on the Friday before Valentine&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gramercy Tavern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gramercy-tavern/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:37:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/gramercy-tavern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gramercy-tavern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gramercy Tavern has been on my list for many years already, and it&amp;rsquo;s a classic New York City restaurant with Michelin popularity. This is one of Danny Meyer&amp;rsquo;s well known restaurant, so you can expect the flavors to be very similar to his other restaurants. Getting reservations is normally very easy, but when it comes to restaurant week, it&amp;rsquo;s quite difficult because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few Michelin Star restaurants in the city that serves options from its normal menus.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Eleven Madison Park</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/eleven-madison-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 20:11:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/eleven-madison-park/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/eleven-madison-park%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef Daniel Humm is a Swiss chef who is most well known for the restaurant Eleven Madison Park. I had visited this restaurant in the mid 2010s, when it served proteins such as duck, clams, and fish on their tasting menus. In 2021, the restaurant converted from an omnivore tasting into a plant-based restaurant, a first of its kind to also receive 3 Michelin Stars for it as well. This was extremely controversial because they were charging high prices for a sole plant-based meal. In October 2025, the restaurant pivoted from a plant-based only menu and offered seafood and animal protein choices for a few of its courses. This shift encouraged me to try this restaurant again to see how it&amp;rsquo;s evolved. We were able to make a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Monday evening without any issues in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One White Street</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/one-white-street/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:02:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/one-white-street/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/one-white-street%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One White Street is located in a 19th century townhouse, that was a downtown hangout for John Lennon and Yoko Ono. Much of their produce is source from Rigor Hill Farm, located in the Hudson Valley. They practice sustainability, and much of their menu revolves around showcasing these ingredients. Originally opened in 2021 by chef Austin Johnson, this restaurant has 1 Michelin Star, and reservations are very easy to come by. We booked a pair for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening just a few days in advanced.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jungsik</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:22:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jungsik/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jungsik%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our yearly celebration, we decided to come to Jungsik, especially since it was the first NYC Korean restaurant to earn 3 Michelin Stars. I visited this restaurant on a special occasion around June 17, 2017, but I barely remember much about it and did not take pictures. Today is redemption day. I was able to make reservations for 2 fairly easily a few weeks out for a Sunday at 5 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kochi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:48:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/kochi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/kochi%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kochi has been on my list for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to several of the Chef&amp;rsquo;s other restaurants, and they&amp;rsquo;re all delightful. This is his first solo project, after working in kitchens like Le Bernardin, Per Se, and Morimoto. What&amp;rsquo;s also great about this restaurant is that it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to get a reservation if you just book a few days out. We were able to get one at 5:30 PM on a Friday without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blue Hill at Stone Barns</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 20:07:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/blue-hill-at-stone-barns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/blue-hill-at-stone-barns%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Hill at Stone Barns has been on our hit list for over 4 years now. Every year, my partner attempted to book the reservation online, but they would always be unsuccessful. This year, I decided to take a shot at it, and I scored a June 19th, Thursday, reservation for 5 PM. This restaurant has 2 Michelin Stars, and it is located near Tarrytown in Westchester County. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to do a train ride up from the city and take an uber, but we opted to make a weekend trip out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SAGA</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 20:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/saga%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAGA is a Michelin 2-star restaurant run by the &lt;a href="https://www.kenthospitalitygroup.com/"&gt;Kent Hospitality Group&lt;/a&gt;. The late Chef James Kent received a lot of good reviews for his restaurants, and this one was on my list to try, especially after trying &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/"&gt;Crown Shy&lt;/a&gt;. This restaurant is located in the same landmark Art Deco tower as Crown Shy. Crown Shy is located at the first floor, whereas this one is located on the 63rd floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Musket Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-musket-room%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Musket Room has been around for a while, and it is located close to the Broadway/Lafayette train in Manhattan. Chef Mary Attea is the head chef of this restaurant, and according to the Michelin Guide, the kitchen is predominantly women. We picked this restaurant to try for tonight primarily because the menu looked like a slightly different take on New American than what we were used to. I was easily able to book a reservation for 2 for 5:30 PM on a Friday evening a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Kitchen Table at The Modern</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:57:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-kitchen-table-at-the-modern%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had previously been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-bar-room-at-the-modern/"&gt;The Bar at The Modern&lt;/a&gt;, where the value to taste ratio was quite good. In an effort to knock another off our list, we booked The Kitchen experience. On the other side of the bar, there was a dining room with a lot of natural light of the garden of the Museum of Modern Arts. This area served a more extensive tasting menu with wine pairing options. The kitchen is the same, except if you book during lunch, you have access to the dinner tasting menu as well, i.e. the full experience. We made a reservation for 12:00 PM on a Saturday without much difficulties as long as you make the reservation when it opens up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:47:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/mari/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/mari%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari is yet another seaweed hand-roll type restaurant in a very crowded space in New York City. The difference from many others though is that this is Korean-centric, and it has earned 1 Michelin Star in both 2022 and 2023. This restaurant is the same team as Kochi, which is also near the area in the Theater District. Since my partner was attending another event, I was looking at this restaurant because perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be very solo friendly, and it was quite easy to make a 1-seat reservation the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>63 Clinton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 11:58:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/sixty-three-clinton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/sixty-three-clinton%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty Three (63) Clinton was a restaurant that I had my eyes on for a few months now. They change the menu monthly, so it was previously difficult to time the menu preferences to our food preferences. I finally found a menu (July) worth going for, however, little did I know the day of my reservation was the day the menu changed. We had 2 items on the menu with &amp;ldquo;mushroom&amp;rdquo;-like ingredients in it. I was honestly nervous about the experience, but usually I will just go with the chefs&amp;rsquo; visions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meju</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/meju/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/meju%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Island City is basically turning into an upscale, modern day Flushing-type environment. There has been a recent surge in the last few years of Asian restaurants popping up all over the place. Close to the popular Vernon Blvd area is a fermentation studio called &amp;ldquo;Little Banchan Shop&amp;rdquo;. They sell little Korean side dishes. The owner decided to open a restaurant in the back, Meju. We were able to get reservations a month in advance on Tock for 7 PM on a Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Crown Shy</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:04:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/crown-shy%2F0_outside_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many things about Crown Shy, both positive and negative. It&amp;rsquo;s located in the same building as SAGA, a Michelin 2 Star restaurant, and also a supposed good bar called Overstory. This year, Crown Shy received a Michelin Star, and various public forums raved about their dishes being inventive and good. Since reservations were easy to get, we decided to spend our Friday at this restaurant. It was very easy to book a 5:45 PM dinner reservation for 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Frevo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:46:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/frevo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/frevo%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frevo was a restaurant that has been on my partner&amp;rsquo;s list for some time. When we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;Atomix Bar&lt;/a&gt;, the chef had also highly recommended the restaurant. The head chef Franco Sampogna is Brazilian and comes from the region that my partner is from. The entrance to the restaurant has a very tiny art gallery, and it&amp;rsquo;s been recognized on the Michelin Guide with 1 star. We were able to reserve this a few weeks back without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Torien</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 15:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/torien/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/torien%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Christmas celebration before we embark on a trip, I wanted to knock this final yakitori tasting off the list. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to a slew of yakitori tasting places, and this is the last one that is on the higher end. Torien still has 1 Michelin Star in 2023, and it also has a sister 1 Michelin Star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/tokyo-region/tokyo/restaurant/torishiki"&gt;Torishiki&lt;/a&gt;, in Tokyo Japan. We were able to make a reservation for this for a Saturday a few weeks back without issues. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this compares to the other yakitori tastings, considering they use a special oak for the taste.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River Cafe</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:04:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-river-cafe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/the-river-cafe%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally made it to The River Cafe, which was a restaurant we wanted to go for a while. This restaurant sits right next to the East River, right under the Brooklyn Bridge. We made a reservation for a table of 7 at 5 PM on a Friday night. The dinner consists of primarily 3 courses, which has a fixed price of $195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The River Cafe has 1 Michelin Star and first received it in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bōm</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:29:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/bom/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/bom%2F0_napkin.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bom is a restaurant located in the back room of its sibling restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/"&gt;Oiji Mi&lt;/a&gt;. We had been to that before, and I thought it was pretty decent. Bom was always on my list of things to try, but at $295 per person, I was pretty hesitant and skeptical. This restaurant doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a Michelin Star yet. Since reservations are fairly easy and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/"&gt;Oiji Mi&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this a try since we were celebrating two major milestones in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tempura Matsui</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 15:48:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tempura-matsui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tempura-matsui%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempura Matsui is a Michelin 1-star restaurant in Manhattan that specializes in tempura omakase. I had previously gone to another tempura omakase at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/secchu-yokota/"&gt;Secchu Yokota&lt;/a&gt;. As I said previously, I really enjoy tempura as a whole, so I am very curious how a Michelin Star tempura tasting compares to a hidden gem tasting. Fortunately, my partner went to see a Broadway show, so it gave me the ability to solo dine at this restaurant. It was very easy to make reservations for one person the night prior.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef's Table at Brooklyn Fare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table at Brooklyn Fare is a renown &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant by Chef Cesar Ramirez. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by Japanese cuisine with French technique, and the 13 course tasting menu tonight is focused on fish &amp;amp; shellfish with 1 meat course and 4 dessert courses. I was quite excited to come here since moving to NYC. This restaurant was always very difficult to get reservations, so it was great that we were able to when we wanted. This restaurant is currently rated number 61 out of 100 on the &lt;a href="https://www.theworlds50best.com/stories/News/the-worlds-50-best-restaurants-2023-51-100-list.html"&gt;The World&amp;rsquo;s Best 50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jua</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 18:54:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/jua/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/jua%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jua is one of those new-ish Korean restaurants that has received a number of praises from all sorts of diners. I was able to get a 2-seater a few days before Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day on a Saturday evening. It did require me to sit and snipe on Resy, which fortunately was not as difficult as trying to get reservations at &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/"&gt;Don Angie&lt;/a&gt;. Jua is a restaurant by chef Hoyoung Kim, who was the former executive chef of Jungsik. It is a 7-course tasting menu ($135 per person) and utilizes a variety of wood-fire techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aquavit</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 16:46:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aquavit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/aquavit%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I had my eye on Aquavit for quite some time. Not only does it have &lt;strong&gt;2 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Scandinavian and Nordic inspired. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit fatigued from the high end French restaurants since their techniques and flavors are nearly the same as each other. We had been to another Scandinavian Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/"&gt;Aska&lt;/a&gt; recently, so it would be interesting to compare these two.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 11:56:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is either a blessing or a curse of the reservation system &lt;a href="https://www.tock.com"&gt;Tock&lt;/a&gt;. When the time comes to make reservations for super hot restaurants, you literally have less than 2 seconds to grab a reservation spot when they become available. I mistakenly grabbed a bar reservation thinking it was the Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter, and I was mildly disappointed. However, I refreshed the reservation system about 10 minutes later, and I noticed there were an opening for counter seating the following week. I quickly made the reservation, and then ultimately decided to keep both the bar tasting and the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting reservations. This post will be for the Atomix Chef&amp;rsquo;s Counter menu. To read about the Atomix Bar tasting experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atomix Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:56:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/atomix-bar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our anniversary, I camped on Tock to make reservations for Atomix. Here, they actually have 2 different menus: a bar tasting menu and a Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter tasting menu. I actually made reservations for both, with some thought that I was going to sell the bar one because I thought they would be similar. However after some research, I realized they are actually 2 distinct experiences. I ended up keeping both reservations, and so there will be two distinct reviews for Atomix. This one is about the bar. To read the Chef&amp;rsquo;s counter experience, please click &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/atomix/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Per Se</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:37:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/per-se/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/per-se%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per Se is Thomas Keller&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed interpretation of the French Laundry restaurant in New York City and has &lt;strong&gt;3 Michelin Stars&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a replacement for the French Laundry, but it might be indicative of what to expect if we did ever go to Napa Valley to try it out. This restaurant is located in Columbus Circle at the top floor inside the mall. When we walked in, we were astounded by the huge ceiling and the vast feeling of space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oiji Mi</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:04:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/oiji-mi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I read about Oiji Mi somewhere, and my gourmand syndrome was kicking in since I felt like I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a prix fixe upper end restaurant in a while. Oiji Mi is relatively new, and it comes from the owners of the original East Village&amp;rsquo;s Oiji. It offers creative contemporary Korean dining composed uniquely for NYC. I saw that they offer a 5 course tasting menu for $125 per person, and the menu looked quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contra</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:24:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/contra/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It was my partner&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and they had asked for my partner to make a reservation to a Michelin Star restaurant that was not overwhelmingly expensive (&amp;lt; $120 per person before wine). My partner started looking for more contemporary cuisines, and stumbled onto this which was a bit below the radar of restaurants. I remembered looking at the menu a while back, and nothing really struck me as a must-have &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to trying to prove myself wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aska</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/scandinavian/aska/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For my partner&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I decided on this 2 Michelin Star restaurant located in the Williamsburg area. What appealed to me originally about this was that it was not just another French restaurant. French cuisine is great, but there are so many high end French restaurants around the city. Perhaps I am getting a little burnt out of having the same French tastes over and over, so I wanted something that was less normal. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had high end Scandinavian, so I thought today could be a good day. And to add, I had heard that they have non-alcoholic (juice) pairings, so I was excited to check this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Atera</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:09:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/atera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Atera is a &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City. We&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to go to this restaurant pre-pandemic, and each time we make a reservation, it was always cancelled due to shifts in NYC rules around the pandemic. Fortunately, the city is coming alive, and the reservation stuck this time around. We celebrated our very special anniversary at 5 PM. The cool thing about this restaurant that attracted me was that it had a temperament pairing of non-alcoholic juices. Although I would have liked to order the wine pairing, I always get full and drunk too fast with alcohol such that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the experience enjoyable. The restaurant is located on Worth Street, and it&amp;rsquo;s inside a building that looked very discreet on the outside. When you enter the building, the restaurant doors are directly on the left next to the elevators.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Bernardin</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/le-bernardin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Le Bernardin is a &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant in New York City that primarily deals with seafood. The head chef is Eric Ripert, who is very well known in the higher end spectrum of the culinary world. We actually saw him on the floor with a mask on talking to some of the wait staff. This particular occasion was for a birthday celebration. Our reservation was at 5 PM, and it had to be reserved a month in advance. The spinning doors don&amp;rsquo;t actually open till 5 PM sharp, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a benefit to arrive before.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don Angie</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:23:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/don-angie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restaurant had been on my peripheral for a while because of the lasagna dish. I didn&amp;rsquo;t decide to try to book a reservation until I learned it was awarded its first ever Michelin Star. I had tried a few times on Resy, but always missed it. Fortunately, I was able to land a reservation on a weekend at 5 PM EST. The restaurant itself is in West Village and felt like a typical trendy cafe in the area. The tables were social distanced, and had a nice romantic setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cote</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:00:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/cote/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indoor dining finally opened again in NYC on September 30, 2020. There are those that feel it&amp;rsquo;s reckless in this COVID temperament, but we still decided to celebrate by booking an indoor reservation at Cote, a 1 Michelin Star Korean BBQ restaurant. Normally, this is difficult to get a reasonable time, so we were happy it was not too bad. Like all upscale restaurants, they take your temperature via the forehead, and each table is partitioned by a plastic partition. Aside from air conditioning, there&amp;rsquo;s no way for your aerosols to hit another table unless you tried to spit a few feet up. There&amp;rsquo;s more than enough space between booths, so it was very enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gabriel Kreuther</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 18:03:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/gabriel-kreuther/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be a big one. For our first anniversary, we treated ourselves to a nice French place that I think is generally underrated and under the radar. Gabriel Kreuthers has been something that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try, and it&amp;rsquo;s rated 2 Michelin Stars in 2019. We went bold with the &lt;strong&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Carte Blanche Tasting Menu&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a total of at least 28 dishes spread through of what they say is 9 courses.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aldea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:31:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/portuguese/aldea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had Portuguese food other than the pastels, so this is the first for me. This special occasion was for a birthday and to try out a different type of cuisine that is largely not as popular as the mainstream French or Asian themed Michelin Star restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got the tasting menu with wine pairing. The hosts were very nice in that we mentioned we&amp;rsquo;d like to just have wine pairing for 1 person and not the other, so that we can share since we&amp;rsquo;re not big drinkers. The hosts still gave us 2 glasses and poured smaller samples. I am pretty sure if I had the wine pairing to myself, I would be drunk before I reached the end due to my inability to have the enzymes to process alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oxomoco</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 23:50:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This apparently received a coveted 1 Michelin Star at this time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went here for brunch, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to go back to try the dinner. Just like &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/"&gt;Casa Enrique&lt;/a&gt;, I find it pretty good but pricey for what you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oxomoco%2F1_horchata.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horchata was tasty, but does not beat those horchata machines back in LA. Also, it was loaded with ice, so the amount of liquid you get is pretty small for $6.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hirohisa</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 17:05:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/hirohisa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hirohisa apparently has been around for a while, but they just received a Michelin star again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I felt the price point $160 pp for the 9-course tasting + $70 sake pairing was a decent price for splurging for a special someone&amp;rsquo;s birthday dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a note: they do respect some allergy restrictions. My guest had lobster specific allergies, and they were able to accomodate easy. She did not have any rashes or swelling at the end of the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Delaware and Hudson</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 22:08:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/tastings/delaware-and-hudson/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;2016 and 2017 Michelin 1 star. Tasting only for dinner. Atlantic food. Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casa Enrique</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 17:49:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/casa-enrique/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been to this Michelin 1 star restaurant with a friend for brunch. We were underwhelmed as we&amp;rsquo;ve been to several Mexican restaurants in Southern California. My partner hasn&amp;rsquo;t tried this before, so I thought to give it another shot for dinner. Note that the restaurant does not take reservations. We were able to walk in at 5 PM on a Saturday evening and be seated indoors right away. Take note that there is usually a line outside because people want to wait for outdoor tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casa Mono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:06:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/casa-mono%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had stumbled drunk here back in 2018 not realizing it was a Michelin restaurant. Fortunately, it was on our list to come back to have a more proper dinner where our memory would still function. Our friends wanted a taste of a Michelin type of experience, and in lieu of a tasting menu, we opted for a more shareable format. Reservations are fairly easy to come by, so on a Sunday night, the restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t super full at 5 PM. Casa Mono still today maintains 1 Michelin Star.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 18:16:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/marc-forgione/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marc-forgione%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formerly known as &amp;ldquo;Marc Forgione&amp;rdquo;, this restaurant has moved from its prior Tribeca location to a different Tribeca location. Since then, they have lost their Michelin Star, but it is still a staple restaurant for those familiar with the history of this restaurant. It was quite easy to make reservations a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came here in 2012, I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Forgione is one of the Iron Chefs on Iron Chef America. This is his first restaurant, and at the time of this writing it has 1 Michelin Star. Like Michael Voltaggio, this restaurant is one of his babies, so he periodically is cooking in the kitchen to make sure everything comes out as he desires. Unfortunately he didn&amp;rsquo;t cook today, but I just want to preface this by saying this is definitely one of my favorite restaurants ever that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WD~50</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 17:59:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/wd-50/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/wd-50%2F0_wylie.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first found out about WD~50 from my friend who wanted to try it out for the longest time. On research, I found out one of the Bravo&amp;rsquo;s Top Chef previous contestant owns this restaurant. His name is Wylie Dufresne. He is well known for pushing a movement towards molecular gastronomy, which is basically a different way to cook things. This 1 Michelin Star restaurant&amp;rsquo;s menu is pretty sparse in choices in that you basically choose from 2 different types of tasting menus, the cheaper or the more expensive. Optionally, you could order 2 items off any of the tasting menus at the bar for $25. We of course opted for the expensive one considering we have no plans on coming back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>