<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/seafood/</link><description>Recent content in Seafood on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:59:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/cuisine/seafood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Palladino's</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/palladinos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:59:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/palladinos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/palladinos%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palladino&amp;rsquo;s Steak and Seafood is owned by Joseph Palladino, who was a former NYPD officer and opened Nick and Sam&amp;rsquo;s Steakhouse in Dallas 20 years ago. He wanted to bring this restaurant type back to his motherland city, NYC. This restaurant recently opened in Grand Central Terminal, just opposite of the Apple store in the main concourse on the second level. I was able to make a reservation for 2 very easily for 5:45 for the dining area that has fantastic views of the main Grand Central floor and its beautiful ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abuqir</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/abuqir/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 19:49:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/abuqir/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/abuqir%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we went to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/le-petit-pecheur/"&gt;Le Petit Pecheur&lt;/a&gt; because we were on a mission to try all the various seafood places in Astoria. Abuqir was on my list because it was highly rated for its &amp;ldquo;Egyptian&amp;rdquo; flavors, freshness, and value. All the NYC food blogs and Queens food crew for some reason feel this is a hidden find and offers good value. We went to this place around 4:00 PM on a Saturday, and there was a late afternoon crowd already.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le Petit Pecheur</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/le-petit-pecheur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 22:43:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/le-petit-pecheur/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/le-petit-pecheur%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Petit Pêcheur is one of the highly rated Astoria seafood places where you can pick your seafood and they will cook it for you. We&amp;rsquo;ve been to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/"&gt;Hamido Seafood&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/"&gt;Taverna Kyclades&lt;/a&gt; several times, so we&amp;rsquo;re wondering how this place stacks up. This restaurant opened nearly 1 year ago, and it has been low key on the radar. We were able to walk in without reservations around 4:30 PM on a Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Time and Tide</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/time-and-tide/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/time-and-tide%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time and Tide comes from the &lt;a href="https://www.kenthospitalitygroup.com/"&gt;Kent Hospitality Group&lt;/a&gt;, which owns restaurants such as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/saga/"&gt;Saga&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/crown-shy/"&gt;Crown Shy&lt;/a&gt;. The head chef, &lt;em&gt;Top Chef winner&lt;/em&gt; Danny Garcia, overhauled the menu recently, and we got a chance to experience it. The restaurant was inspired to be a steakhouse modeled fish restaurant. I was easily able to make a reservation for 5:30 PM on a Friday night because the restaurant snipers have moved onto newer restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smithereens</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:46:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/smithereens/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/smithereens%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smithereens opened pretty recently in last November, and is from chef Nick Tamburo (&lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/claud/"&gt;Claud&lt;/a&gt;) and beverage director Nikita Malhotra (Momofuku Ko). This is a New England-style restaurant focused on fresh seafood and some different types of cocktails. Their wine list is pretty extensive, and they also have some pretty interesting glasses of white wines as well. I was able to book a reservation for 5:30 PM for 2 on a Friday evening about a week in advance. The restaurant is located in the East Village off 9th Ave, and it&amp;rsquo;s located in half floor basement of a building.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xie Bao</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:58:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xie-bao/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xie-bao%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a show this evening, and this &amp;ldquo;crab house&amp;rdquo; just recently opened in Manhattan. This originated from a Flushing stall, and their specialty is crab roe over rice or noodle. We were able to walk in on a Saturday evening without reservations. The social media circuit really raved about this dish by showing off the roe, so we decided to try it. I figured there was no need to make reservations since Manhattan Midtown Chinese restaurants are usually pretty easy to get into.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hamido Seafood</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:38:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/hamido-seafood/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/hamido-seafood%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen this restaurant Hamido Seafood on social media all over the place. Like many Astoria restaurants, they pride themselves in having the freshest seafood, and they are somewhat close to &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/"&gt;Taverna Kyclades&lt;/a&gt; down the street. We went to the original Hamido Seafood restaurant at 4 PM on a Saturday late afternoon, and we were lucky to be seated right away before the crowds came. They are located very close to the N/W train off the Ditmars train stop.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rice Thief</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:02:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/rice-thief/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rice-thief%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rice Thief is one of the few Korean raw marinated crab restaurants in New York City. The focus of this restaurant is to provide deeply marinated raw crabs with lots of seasoning in it. To the surprise of many, the raw crab meat is actually a little gooey but quite flavorful. My partner saw this restaurant on Instagram and expressed interest in trying this out, despite me wanting to avoid bringing them here. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure how they would do with raw crabs and the mess that is to ensue. Nonetheless, this was the catalyst for us to try out this restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fulton Fish Co.</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:07:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/fulton-fish-co/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/fulton-fish-co%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to check out the Tin Building down in South Street Seaport, which is a building by Chef Jean-Georges. It was basically similar to Eataly, where it has a market for different cuisines and restaurants. There are only 2 floors, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much to see in my opinion. However when it comes to food, we decided to try the seafood joint, Fulton Fish Co. We were able to walk in with no reservations at 5:30 PM on a Saturday early evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marea</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:56:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/marea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/marea%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally during every Thanksgiving Thursday, I cook for my partner some poultry thing whether it be quail or turkey breast. This year we decided to relieve me the duties of frantically looking for materials and cooking for 6 hours for the 2 of us. Marea was closed for a few months, and we&amp;rsquo;ve always had this on our list. Because it just reopened in October, I decided to pursue the Thanksgiving tasting menu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lure Fishbar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lure-fishbar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:57:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lure-fishbar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lure-fishbar%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lure Fishbar is run by the same hospitality network thath also owns &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/bar-tulix/"&gt;Bar Tulix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-mercer-kitchen/"&gt;Mercer Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, which is closed unfortunately. Whenever we were in the SOHO area, we always thought about checking this place out especially since we couldn&amp;rsquo;t walk into Balthazar. The restaurant is very seafood straight forward, and it always seems like it has a very steady crowd. The restaurant entrance is actually located down some stairs. We were able to walk in on a Friday evening around 6:30 PM without reservations, but they were only able to seat us at the sushi bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avra Estiatorio</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:32:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/avra-estiatorio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/avra-estiatorio%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avra Estiatorio was a restaurant that we wanted to check out for a while now. Because we were going to watch Gutenberg Musical at 8 PM, this fit perfectly for the opportunity. Avra has several locations spread throughout the United States: 3 in Manhattan, 1 in Miami, and 1 in Beverly Hills. It&amp;rsquo;s a rather posh Greek seafood restaurant, and it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to all the other upper end ones, such as &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/"&gt;Limani&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/"&gt;Milos&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to walk in at around 6 PM without reservations, and we were seated at the upper floor. When we met the hostess, they asked if we were seeing a show, and we acknowledged that we were.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Oceana</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:13:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/oceana/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/oceana%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice parts of living and working in Manhattan is that there is so much you can do and improvise after work. We had a show at 8 PM from winning a lottery, so it was easy to meet up after work and look for something to eat. Pre-theater prix fixe menus are a nice thing. They are basically a small tasting menu that won&amp;rsquo;t fill your belly too much, and the price is reasonable. We ended up at Oceana here since we realized we were within its small pre-theater hours of 5-6 PM on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chef's Table at Brooklyn Fare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:12:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/contemporary/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/chefs-table-at-brooklyn-fare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table at Brooklyn Fare is a renown &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; Michelin Star restaurant by Chef Cesar Ramirez. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by Japanese cuisine with French technique, and the 13 course tasting menu tonight is focused on fish &amp;amp; shellfish with 1 meat course and 4 dessert courses. I was quite excited to come here since moving to NYC. This restaurant was always very difficult to get reservations, so it was great that we were able to when we wanted. This restaurant is currently rated number 61 out of 100 on the &lt;a href="https://www.theworlds50best.com/stories/News/the-worlds-50-best-restaurants-2023-51-100-list.html"&gt;The World&amp;rsquo;s Best 50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gordon Ramsay Fish and Chips</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 23:09:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/gordon-ramsay-fish-and-chips%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were around the Times Square area, and this new fast food fish and chips restaurant just opened from Gordon Ramsay. The restaurant also has locations in Las Vegas, Orlando, DC, and now New York City. Gordon Ramsay used to have restaurants opened in NYC, but they have all been closed for quite some time. This is the only restaurant that he now has in NYC. So how was it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Crab House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:14:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/crab-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot recall the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve cracked open crab shells and eaten a huge chunk of crab meat. In Los Angeles, I used to go to a lot of seafood buffets, and they would always have a plethora of snow crab legs that you could eat for hours on end. We decided today to venture out to this all you can eat seafood buffet in the city. We were able to walk in with no reservations for 2 around 5:30 PM on a Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Limani</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:19:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/limani/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Normally we have Friday plans in the evening for a dinner restaurant after work. We didn&amp;rsquo;t plan for anything, so this restaurant was a decision at the whim. My partner always prefers either Latin based restaurants or Mediterranean because there they love hummus. This restaurant was on 51st right next to Rockafeller, so it was easy to access even on a rainy day. When we arrived at 6 PM on a Friday night, we were able to walk in without reservations as the restaurant was pretty empty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carne Mare</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:58:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/steak/carne-mare/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/carne-mare%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carne Mare is an Italian chophouse restaurant from Andrew Carmellini. He has opened a number of restaurants in NYC already as well as other places in the U.S. The thing that attracted mem to this restaurant was I was craving for prime rib, and then I noticed they had this gorgonzola cured strip-loin that people have been raving about. To add to this, they also offer baked alaska which is basically one of my favorite desserts of all time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Mermaid Inn</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 22:33:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/the-mermaid-inn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure of enjoying the company of one of our friends who is coming into town for work. This restaurant is conveniently close to the Highline and was also near their hotel. I vaguely recall that this is a very popular seafood restaurant down in West Village, and it had been on my list for a number of years. Surprisingly, they opened another location here, and we thought we&amp;rsquo;d go check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bar Tulix</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/bar-tulix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 19:10:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/bar-tulix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following our Disney World trip and since I started going back to the office, we are starting to do our Friday date nights again. This restaurant appeared in the local news as a brand new restaurant, so we thought we&amp;rsquo;d give it a try before the crowds started discovering this and also because we missed NYC food after being in Disney World for a week. The restaurant is a partnership between restauranteur John McDonald of Mercer Street Hospitality with partnership with Chef Justin Bazdarich (&lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mexican/oxomoco/"&gt;Oxomoco&lt;/a&gt;). We recalled we had a great time at Oxomoco for their brunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Flex Mussels</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flex-mussels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 21:46:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flex-mussels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had tickets to the Banksy exhibit later in the evening near the border of Chelsea and West Village. This mussel restaurant was something I had liked to go since I moved out to NYC, and finally all stars aligned. Surprisingly, there are not a lot of mussel restaurants in NYC. In Los Angeles in Culver City, I used to go to a place called &amp;ldquo;Meet in Paris&amp;rdquo;, and it had literally 10+ different types of mussel broths. This reminded me of those vibes, so I wanted to try this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Estiatorio Milos</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:35:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/estiatorio-milos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner saw on their social media that some of their people had raved about this place for lunch. I took a look at the dinner menu here, and it seemed unjustly expensive for what it was. Usually a good indicator of prices starts with oysters. If a restaurant charges $4 for east coast oysters (average price should be around $3), you would expect the restaurant to have higher than usual menu prices. It turns out that the lunch menu prices were way more grounded, and it was a 3 course prix fixe on weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nerai</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:32:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/nerai/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, we were fortunate to book this restaurant in Midtown East at the very last minute. This was always on our list since outdoor dining was a thing as the pictures of its settings looked quite appealing. Most tables have their own electric heater that sat directly above the table, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too cold compared to other places. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, it was in the high 30s with some wind chills. We did dress warmer just in case though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Psari</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:38:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/psari/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what&amp;rsquo;s one of the great things about Astoria? It&amp;rsquo;s the excellent Greek seafood restaurants that are within walking distances of each other. We had been to Taverna Kyclades before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we&amp;rsquo;ve dined at their competitors. This was a restaurant that was within walking distance from our Food Bazaar trek on the way back home, so we thought to stop by and give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rawbar by Domodomo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/rawbar-by-domodomo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 15:13:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/rawbar-by-domodomo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close to NYU, this is next door to its parent restaurant Domodomo. This is primarily a rawbar, meaning somewhat affordable raw seafood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rawbar-by-domodomo%2F1_iced_green_tea.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;iced green tea&lt;/strong&gt; is nice for a warm day. The green tea is quite flavorful, but of course if you want it to be sweeter, you can ask for sugar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/rawbar-by-domodomo%2F2_east_coast_oysters.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered a dozen &lt;strong&gt;oysters&lt;/strong&gt;. Essentially 2 of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half Moon (Cape Cod Bay, MA) : sweet, medium salnity, clean finish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wellfleet (Wellfleet Harbor, MA) : briny, creamy, high salinity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Savage Harbour (PEI, Canada) : crisp, sweet, medium salinity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chekbooktook (New Brunswick) : buttery, sweet, delicate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duxbury (Duxbury Bay, MA) : briny, sweet, and buttery finish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the daily oysters : can&amp;rsquo;t remember what the waiter said about these other than being the saltiest of the east coast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They serve oysters with your choice of 2 condiments: cocktail sauce, mignonette, wasabi lime sorbet, thai chili, and ponzu. Pictured is the cocktail sauce and mignonette. East coast oysters tend to be more briny and salty than west coast, but the best part of this is that it&amp;rsquo;s simply not as expensive as other places. The average Manhattan east coast oyster price is $3 per.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Fulton</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:40:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-fulton/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is one of Jean Georges&amp;rsquo; new seafood-centric restaurant situated right at the corner of the Pier near South Street Seaport. This area has a tiny Boston like mall where people can shop and eat at some decent restaurants. The iPic theater is also here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is largely going through some sort of construction. The restaurant is located at the edge of the pier and overlooks the water facing towards the Brooklyn Bridge. In fact, just about everywhere in the restaurant you can see the Brooklyn Bridge without much obstruction. If you do try to make a reservation, I definitely think the second floor seating is more beautiful than the first.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taverna Kyclades</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 15:08:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/taverna-kyclades/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We came here around 8:30 PM on a rather cold Saturday evening. Typically there is a long line outside, but today people were crowded and bundled up inside. I put my name down for 2. The wait was approximately 40-50 minutes. We had contemplated leaving when we heard the wait time, but we decided to power through and wait. It was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;em&gt;July 1, 2023&lt;/em&gt;, we visited this restaurant again, and it has moved from it&amp;rsquo;s previous location. For a table of 4, we just had to wait approximately 30 minutes on a Saturday around 7:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Grand Central Oyster Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/grand-central-oyster-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:30:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/grand-central-oyster-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Grand Central Oyster Bar is a pretty famous spot in New York City located in the Grand Central Terminal off of 42nd St. This is the central train hub that people take to go towards upstate New York and beyond such as Connecticut. I had been here a while back, but this would be the first time for my partner. What better way is there other than to grab some oysters before jumping on a train back home. This location is at the lower level right close to the dining concourse and right next to the 4 columns that has a distinct sound acoustics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simply Hooked</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/simply-hooked/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:27:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/simply-hooked/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This used to be in the Lower East Side, but I guess they set up shop in this Gansevoort Market area. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good. I prefer the &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery"&gt;A Salt &amp;amp; Battery&lt;/a&gt; place instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hot N Juicy Crawfish</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/hot-n-juicy-crawfish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:26:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/hot-n-juicy-crawfish/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Got the soft shell poboy. Was decent for lunch. $17 for fries, drink, and a poboy. The normal stuff is rather expensive. Probably a $2-3 per pound markup compared to LA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lobster Press</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lobster-press/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:24:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lobster-press/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is Marc Forgione&amp;rsquo;s fast food-ish restaurant near Penn Station. I got the chili lobster here, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as having it at the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Greenpoint Fish and Lobster</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/greenpoint-fish-and-lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:23:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/greenpoint-fish-and-lobster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly good. The oyster shuckers did a good job keeping it juicy. Happy hour is cheap!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Salt &amp; Battery</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:20:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/a-salt-and-battery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;British style fish &amp;amp; chips.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Flora Bar</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flora-bar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:19:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/flora-bar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Seafood centric. Ambience is good, but the food is eh.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zadie's Oyster Room</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/zadies-oyster-room/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:17:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/zadies-oyster-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Different cooking styles for all types of oysters. Was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cape House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/cape-house/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:16:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/cape-house/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Scallops and clam strips were good. Pickles were salty not sour.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sunken Hundred</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/sunken-hundred/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:14:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/sunken-hundred/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good restaurant. I like the spanish octopus, fish churros, and pork chop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s CLOSED.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Luke's Lobster</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lukes-lobster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 15:42:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/seafood/lukes-lobster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/lukes-lobster%2F1_lobster.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a pleasure of visiting Luke&amp;rsquo;s Lobster in East Village when I traveled to NYC from Los Angeles. What you see here is the &amp;ldquo;Taste of Main&amp;rdquo; sample platter. It consists of: half lobster sandwich, half shrimp sandwich, half crab sandwich, 2 crab claws, 1 bag of chips, and 1 bottle of pop. The only comparison I have for this is The Lobsta Truck here in Los Angeles. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, it basically is a food truck that serves lobster sandwiches that are pretty small.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>