<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Union Square on Gourmand Syndrome</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/union-square/</link><description>Recent content in Union Square on Gourmand Syndrome</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:45:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/neighborhood/union-square/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cafe Zaffri</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:45:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/mediterranean/cafe-zaffri/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/cafe-zaffri%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cafe Zaffri has been opened for just a week and are going through an early preview of their menu. The executive Chef Mary Attea heads the menu by tapping into her Lebanese roots and incorporating Levantine flavors into a modern menu. Along with the Chef, owners Jennifer and Nicole Vitagliano also came from &lt;a href="https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/new-american/the-musket-room/"&gt;The Musket Room&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to make a reservation for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day at 5:30 PM just a few days before because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet been fully discovered by the populous.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xu's Public House</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xus-public-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:57:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/chinese/xus-public-house/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a new upscaled Chinese restaurant that we accidentally stumbled into. The decor is very modern and has a slight pretentious feel to it. I learned that the restaurant likes to advertise it hand makes basically all the dough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xus-public-house%2F1_waffle.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They gave this &lt;strong&gt;waffle&lt;/strong&gt; like starter. It is similar to those red bean cakes but without the red bean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/xus-public-house%2F2_dumpling_sampler.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;dumpling sampler&lt;/strong&gt; had 4 dumplings. This was a special, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to remember (top left clockwise): some soup dumpling, some squid ink dumpling with gold flakes, another soup dumpling variant, and shu mai with (crab?) eggs. All the soup dumplings were OK. The skin was thick, but I think with this stuff I still prefer Din Tai Fung or even some places in Flushing. The squid ink dumpling had good flavors, but nothing really tastewise was miles beyond what you can get at some other Chinese restaurants. The shu mai definitely tasted a little more &amp;ldquo;upscale&amp;rdquo; but not that much more mind blowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Patisserie Fouet</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/patisserie-fouet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 14:05:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/desserts/patisserie-fouet/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patisserie Fouet is another one of those Japanese French style dessert places where they also have a prix fixe (3 desserts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/patisserie-fouet%2F1_yuzu_jelly.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yuzu jelly&lt;/strong&gt; was ok. It is not like the panna cotta pictures on Yelp. It tasted like one of those raindrops that had some yuzu flavors in it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t care too much for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/patisserie-fouet%2F2_yuzu_sugar_sugar.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yuzu sugar sugar&lt;/strong&gt; came with yuzu mousse, green tea sponge cake, Japanese yam, and black sesame ice cream. The red shell was made from a candy cane type of stickiness. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too crazy over this because it sticks to your teeth. The black sesame was definitely one of the stars for this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vapiano</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/vapiano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 14:02:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/italian/vapiano/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vapiano seems like it&amp;rsquo;s a chained Italian fast eatery. For the NYC location, the front desk gives you a card, and you walk up to a pasta station if you want pasta or a pizza station if you want pizza. You then tell the cook what you want, and they make it fresh in front of you. They ask that you take the card and tap the screen with it to get it charged with what you ordered. After you finish your meal, you pay as the cashier as you exit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ichiba</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 13:08:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/ramen/ichiba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ramen place is near NYU and Union Station, so it&amp;rsquo;s very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/ichiba%2F1_spicy_miso_ramen.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spicy miso&lt;/strong&gt; ramen comes with ox bones and marrow broth, spicy miso garlic base, bean sprouts, roasted corn, toasted nori, naruto fishcake, soy braised beef, scallions, and thick wavy noodle. THe broth is super rich, far beyond what I was expecting. It&amp;rsquo;s not spicy per se, but the soup doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down super smooth for me. At the end, the spicy pepper would always surprise for some reason. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s attributed to the oil and thickness of the broth, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. Regardless, I thought the ramen was acceptable, but there are better ones in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casa Mono</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:06:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/spanish/casa-mono/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/casa-mono%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had stumbled drunk here back in 2018 not realizing it was a Michelin restaurant. Fortunately, it was on our list to come back to have a more proper dinner where our memory would still function. Our friends wanted a taste of a Michelin type of experience, and in lieu of a tasting menu, we opted for a more shareable format. Reservations are fairly easy to come by, so on a Sunday night, the restaurant wasn&amp;rsquo;t super full at 5 PM. Casa Mono still today maintains 1 Michelin Star.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tsurutontan</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:29:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/japanese/tsurutontan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img data-pagefind-meta="image[src]" id="" src="https://pics.gourmandsyndrome.com/tsurutontan%2F0_front.webp" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Tsurutontan a few times already in various locations including Union Square and Midtown next to Rockafeller Center. When this Japan udon chain first opened in Manhattan a few years ago, there was a massive line because it was the first international location in the USA. The food was outstanding back then, and now it&amp;rsquo;s gone down a little in quality but still pretty good. This restaurant is known for having mammoth sized udon bowls which will most definitely satiate your appetite. They also have a variety of other Japanese sushi-esque dishes as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>La Maison Du Croque Monsieur</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-maison-du-croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:00:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/french/la-maison-du-croque-monsieur/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The croque monsieur was mediocre at best.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dear Irving</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dear-irving/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:40:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/bars/dear-irving/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good old boys bar. Think jazzy-ish. Nice place.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Barn Joo</title><link>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/barn-joo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 14:57:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.gourmandsyndrome.com/nyc/korean/barn-joo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had been here several years ago, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed much at all. This is a Korean bar type restaurant in Union Square with a myriad of different Korean foods including noodles, rice, buns, etc. The last time I was here, I had ordered a bunch of side dishes and had wrote down &lt;code&gt;typical Korean American bar food&lt;/code&gt;. This time around, we decided to try out Korean BBQ. The staff led us up the stairs where there were many tables with BBQ grills in them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>